<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet version="1.0" href="../../stylesheets/flow2html.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<flowDataSet xmlns:common="http://lca.jrc.it/ILCD/Common" xmlns="http://lca.jrc.it/ILCD/Flow" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" version="1.1" locations="../ILCDLocations.xml" xsi:schemaLocation="http://lca.jrc.it/ILCD/Flow ../../schemas/ILCD_FlowDataSet.xsd">
	<flowInformation>
		<dataSetInformation>
			<common:UUID>1e96e840-1ab9-433d-b95c-84e18d4aed82</common:UUID>
			<name>
				<baseName xml:lang="en">Coating residue</baseName>
				<baseName xml:lang="zh">涂层残留物</baseName>
			</name>
			<common:synonyms xml:lang="en">Efflorescence; White powder</common:synonyms>
			<common:synonyms xml:lang="zh">Efflorescence; White powder</common:synonyms>
			<classificationInformation>
				<common:classification name="ILCD 1.1" classes="../ILCDClassification.xml">
					<common:class level="0">Materials production</common:class>
					<common:class level="1">Other materials</common:class>
				</common:classification>
			</classificationInformation>
			<common:generalComment xml:lang="en">Coating residue generally refers to the waste generated during painting work, and its chemical composition is related to the type of paint used. In general, the main components of paint residue include synthetic resins, solvents, fillers, pigments, and preservatives.   1. Synthetic resin: Synthetic resin is one of the main components of most paints. They are usually obtained through synthetic chemical reactions and have good adhesion and durability.   2. Solvent: A solvent is a chemical substance that makes paint less viscous. Common solvents include aromatic hydrocarbons, ketones, esters, and mineral oils. Most of these solvents are volatile.   3. Filler: Filler is a chemical substance added to improve the strength and hardness of paint coatings. Common fillers include titanium oxide, white carbon black, aluminum silicate, etc.   4. Pigments: Pigments are chemical substances added for dyeing purposes. Common pigments include titanium dioxide, iron oxide, and chromium oxide. In addition, there are also some special pigments, such as fluorescent and metallic pigments.   5. Preservatives: Preservatives are chemical substances added to prevent paint from being corroded by bacteria and fungi during use. Common preservatives include benzoic acid, imidazole, etc.   When carrying out spraying work, it is necessary to properly handle paint residue to ensure minimal impact on the environment.</common:generalComment>
			<common:generalComment xml:lang="zh">涂料渣一般指在油漆工作中产生的废弃物，其化学成分:与使用的油漆类型有关。一般情况下，涂料渣的主要成分包括合成树脂、溶剂、填料、颜料和防腐剂等。   1.合成树脂:合成树脂是大多数油漆的主要成分之一。它们通常是通过合成化学反应获得的，具有良好的附着力和耐久。   2.溶剂:溶剂是使油漆变得黏稠度较低的化学物质。常用的溶剂包括芳香烃、酮、酯和矿物油等。这些溶剂大部分具有挥发性。   3.填料:填料是为了提高油漆涂层的强度和硬度而添加的化学物质。常见的填料包括氧化钛、白炭黑、硅酸铝等。   4.颜料:颜料是为了染色而添加的化学物质。常见的颜料包括二氧化钛、 氧化铁和氧化铬等。另外,还有些特殊的颜料,如荧光和金属颜料等。   5.防腐剂:防腐剂是为了防止油漆在使用过程中被细菌和真菌侵蚀而添加的化学物质。常见的防腐剂包括苯甲酸、异嗑唑等。   在进行喷涂工作时，必须正确地处理涂料渣，以确保对环境造成的影响最小化。</common:generalComment>
		</dataSetInformation>
		<quantitativeReference>
			<referenceToReferenceFlowProperty>0</referenceToReferenceFlowProperty>
		</quantitativeReference>
	</flowInformation>
	<modellingAndValidation>
		<LCIMethod>
			<typeOfDataSet>Product flow</typeOfDataSet>
		</LCIMethod>
	</modellingAndValidation>
	<administrativeInformation>
		<dataEntryBy>
			<common:timeStamp>2024-01-16T09:23:19.793591+08:00</common:timeStamp>
			<common:referenceToDataSetFormat type="source data set" refObjectId="a97a0155-0234-4b87-b4ce-a45da52f2a40" uri="../sources/a97a0155-0234-4b87-b4ce-a45da52f2a40.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">ILCD format</common:shortDescription>
			</common:referenceToDataSetFormat>
		</dataEntryBy>
		<publicationAndOwnership>
			<common:dataSetVersion>01.00.000</common:dataSetVersion>
		</publicationAndOwnership>
	</administrativeInformation>
	<flowProperties>
		<flowProperty dataSetInternalID="0">
			<referenceToFlowPropertyDataSet type="flow property data set" refObjectId="93a60a56-a3c8-11da-a746-0800200b9a66" version="00.00.000" uri="../flowproperties/93a60a56-a3c8-11da-a746-0800200b9a66.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">Mass</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToFlowPropertyDataSet>
			<meanValue>1.0</meanValue>
		</flowProperty>
	</flowProperties>
</flowDataSet>
