<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet version="1.0" href="../../stylesheets/process2html.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<processDataSet xmlns:common="http://lca.jrc.it/ILCD/Common" xmlns="http://lca.jrc.it/ILCD/Process" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" version="1.1" locations="../ILCDLocations.xml" xsi:schemaLocation="http://lca.jrc.it/ILCD/Process ../../schemas/ILCD_ProcessDataSet.xsd">
	<processInformation>
		<dataSetInformation>
			<common:UUID>421f85d8-34cb-4c46-a73b-82176dc99ceb</common:UUID>
			<name>
				<baseName xml:lang="en">cement production;cement, ordinary portland cement, 42.5MPa;new dry process, 4000 t-cl/d;mixed solid wastes</baseName>
				<baseName xml:lang="zh">水泥生产;水泥, 普通硅酸盐水泥, 42.5MPa;新型干法, 4000 t-cl/d;混合固废</baseName>
			</name>
			<classificationInformation>
				<common:classification>
					<common:class level="0">Materials production</common:class>
					<common:class level="1">Other mineralic materials</common:class>
				</common:classification>
			</classificationInformation>
			<common:generalComment xml:lang="en">Precalciner kiln dry process cement production is a typical representative of new dry process. The process flow of new dry process cement production line of precalciner kiln with a daily production capacity of 4000t clinker in China.Limestone from the mine is transported into the crusher feed bib by the dump truck. crushed by crusher and crusher, sent to the crushed stone storage, and then sent to the pre-homogenization yard by skirt plate feeder and belt conveyor in a quantitative manner. Clay is imported by dump truck or unloaded from the clay pile shed of the plant into the clay feed bin by bucket, fed by feeder into the double-roll crusher for crushing, and sent to the pre-batch homogenization yard by metering equipment. The limestone and clay are automatically combined in the pre-batching homogenizing yard and homogenized into a uniform mixed raw material. The mixed raw materials, limestone and iron powder are sent to the feeding bin of the grinding head of the raw mill from the yard by belt conveyor, and then sent to the drying mill for drying and grinding by quantitative unloading and feeding. The hot gas for the drying mill comes from the exhaust gas discharged from the suspension preheater, and the hot air is supplied with the help of the hot air furnace during start-up.The powdered raw meal after grinding is lifted by a pneumatic pump and sent to two continuous air homogenization silos for further air mixing and storage. The raw material in the homogenizing storage is discharged, measured, lifted and fed into the suspension preheater and decomposer at the kiln tail by the pneumatic pump, and then preheated and decomposed. After that, it enters the rotary kiln for calcination to produce clinker. The raw coal used in the rotary kiln and decomposition furnace is dried and ground to make coal powder and stored in the coal powder bin for supply. The clinker is cooled by castor cooler and then sent to the clinker storage by skirt conveyor, metering scale and bucket elevator respectively.The clinker and gypsum are fed into the cement mill for grinding by a metering device. The cement mill with powder selector constitutes a so-called ring-flow cement mill, which can also be ground with the appropriate amount of mixed materials and clinker and gypsum according to the product requirements. After grinding, the cement is sent to the cement warehouse by the silo air transfer pump for storage. Part of the cement is packaged in bags by the packaging machine and transported out of the factory by train or truck, while the other part is shipped in bulk by bulk special vehicle.</common:generalComment>
			<common:generalComment xml:lang="zh">预分解窑干法水泥生产是新型干法的典型代表。我国日产4000t熟料的预分解窑新型干法水泥生产线的工艺流程。来自矿山的石灰石由自卸卡车运入破碎机喂料仓，经破碎机和破碎机破碎，送入碎石库内存储，然后由裙板式喂料机、皮带输送机定量送往预均化堆场。粘土用自卸卡车输入或从工厂的粘土堆棚中用铲斗卸入粘土喂料仓，经喂料机喂入双辊破碎机破碎，经计量设备送入预配料的预均化堆场。石灰石和粘土在预配料均化堆场自动配合，并均化成均匀的混合原料。混合原料、石灰石及铁粉各自从堆场由皮带输送机送往生料磨的磨头喂料仓，经定量卸料、喂料送入烘干磨进行烘干与粉磨。烘干磨的热气体来自悬浮预热器排出的废气，启动时则借助热风炉供热风。粉磨后的生料用气力提升泵送入两个连续性空气均化库进一步用空气搅拌均化生料和储存生料。均化库中的生料经卸料、计量、提升、定量喂入后由气力提升泵送至窑尾悬浮预热器和分解炉经预热和分解后的物料进入回转窑煅烧成熟料。回转窑和分解炉所用原煤经烘干兼粉磨后制成的煤粉并存储在煤粉仓中供给。熟料经蓖式冷却机冷却后由裙板输送机、计量称、斗式提升机分别送入熟料库中存储。熟料、石膏经定量喂料机喂料送入水泥磨中粉磨。水泥磨带有选粉机构成所谓的圈流水泥磨粉磨时也可根据产品要求加入适量的混合材料和熟料、石膏一同粉磨。粉磨后的水泥经仓式空气输送泵送至水泥库中存储一部分水泥经包装机包装为袋装水泥用火车或卡车运输出厂另一部分由散装专用车散装出厂。</common:generalComment>
		</dataSetInformation>
		<quantitativeReference type="Reference flow(s)">
			<referenceToReferenceFlow>10</referenceToReferenceFlow>
		</quantitativeReference>
		<time>
			<common:referenceYear>2005</common:referenceYear>
		</time>
		<geography>
			<locationOfOperationSupplyOrProduction location="CN"/>
		</geography>
		<technology>
			<technologyDescriptionAndIncludedProcesses xml:lang="en">Limestone 1 from the mine is transported to the crusher feeding bin by dump trucks, crushed by crusher 6 and crusher 7, and sent to the gravel bin for storage. Homogenization yard 9. The clay is imported with a dump truck or unloaded from the clay storage shed of the factory with a bucket into the clay feeding bin. It is fed to the double-roller crusher through the feeder for crushing and sent to the pre-batched pre-homogenization storage yard through the metering equipment9 . Limestone and clay are automatically mixed in the pre-batching and homogenization yard and homogenized into a uniform mixed raw material. The mixed raw materials, limestone and iron powder 3 are each sent from the stockyard by a belt conveyor to the grinding head feeding bin of the raw material mill 1. After quantitative unloading, the feed material is sent to the drying mill for drying and powder grinding. The hot gas of the drying mill comes from the exhaust gas discharged from the suspension preheater 14. When starting up, the hot air furnace is used to supply hot air.The ground raw meal is sent to two continuous air homogenization warehouses using a pneumatic lift pump 12, and the air is further used to stir the homogenized raw meal and store the raw meal. After unloading, measuring, lifting and quantitative feeding, the raw meal in the homogenization warehouse is pumped by pneumatic lift to the suspension preheater 14 and decomposition furnace 15 at the end of the kiln. The preheated and decomposed materials enter the rotary kiln 16 for forging Burn clinker. The raw coal used in the rotary kiln and decomposition furnace 4 is dried and ground to produce pulverized coal and is stored in the pulverized coal bin for supply. After the clinker is cooled by the grating cooler 17, it is sent to the clinker warehouse for storage by the skirt conveyor, weighing scale, and bucket elevator respectively.Clinker and gypsum 5 are fed into the cement mill for grinding through a quantitative feeding machine. The cement mill 23 is equipped with a powder selector 24 to form a so-called circle flow cement mill. When grinding, an appropriate amount of mixed materials can also be added according to product requirements to grind together with clinker and gypsum. The ground cement is sent to the cement warehouse 2 and 6 for storage through a warehouse-type air transfer pump 25. Part of the cement is packaged into bagged cement by a packaging machine 27 and transported to the factory by train or truck 28. The other part is shipped in bulk by a special bulk truck 29. .</technologyDescriptionAndIncludedProcesses>
			<technologyDescriptionAndIncludedProcesses xml:lang="zh">来 自矿 山 的石 灰 石 1 由 自卸卡 车运 入 破 碎 机 喂 料仓  经 破 碎 机 6 和 破 碎 机 7 破 碎  送 入碎 石库 内 存储  然 后由 裙 板式 喂 料 机 、 皮带 输 送 机 定 量 送 往 预均 化 堆场 9 。 粘 土 用 自卸卡车 输 入 或 从工 厂的 粘 土 堆 棚 中用 铲 斗卸 入 粘土 喂 料仓  经 喂 料 机 喂 入双辊破 碎 机 破 碎  经计 量 设备 送 入 预配 料 的预 均 化 堆场 9 。石 灰 石 和 粘 土 在 预 配料 均化堆场 自动 配 合  并均 化成 均 匀的 混合原 料 。 混 合 原 料 、 石 灰 石及 铁 粉 3 各 自从堆场 由 皮 带 输送机 送 往 生 料磨 1 的磨头喂 料 仓  经 定 量 卸 料 、 喂 料送 入烘 干 磨进 行 烘 干与 粉 磨 。 烘干磨 的 热气体 来自悬 浮 预热 器 14排 出 的 废 气  启动 时 则 借 助 热 风 炉 供 热 风 。粉 磨 后的 生 料 用 气力提 升泵 12 送 入两 个 连续 性 空 气均化 库  进 一 步 用 空 气 搅拌均 化 生 料 和 储存 生 料 。 均 化 库 中的生 料 经 卸 料 、 计 量 、 提升 、 定 量 喂 入 后 由气 力提 升 泵送 至窑尾悬 浮 预 热 器 14 和 分 解 炉 15  经 预热 和 分解 后的 物料进入 回 转 窑 16锻 烧 成熟 料 。 回转 窑 和 分 解炉 所 用 原 煤 4 经 烘干兼 粉磨 后  制 成 的 煤粉 并存储在煤粉 仓 中供给 。 熟 料经 蓖 式冷 却 机 17 冷 却后  由 裙 板 输 送 机 、 计 量称 、 斗 式 提升 机 分别 送 入 熟 料 库 中存 储 。熟料 、 石膏 5 经 定 量 喂 料 机 喂 料 送 入 水 泥磨 中粉 磨 。 水 泥 磨 23带 有 选 粉 机24 构 成所谓 的 圈 流水泥磨  粉 磨 时也 可 根据产 品 要 求 加 入 适量 的 混合 材 料 和 熟料 、 石膏 一同 粉 磨 。 粉 磨 后的水泥 经 仓 式 空 气 输 送泵 25 送 至 水 泥 库 2 6 中存 储  一部 分水 泥 经 包 装 机 27 包装为 袋 装水 泥  用 火 车或 卡 车28 运 输 出厂  另 一部 分 由 散装专 用 车 29 散 装 出厂 。</technologyDescriptionAndIncludedProcesses>
			<technologicalApplicability xml:lang="en">This dataset describes the production of ordinary Portland cement with a strength of 42.5MPa using the new dry process technology. It is typically applied in construction projects requiring high-strength concrete and is suitable for various types of large-scale civil engineering and architectural works.</technologicalApplicability>
			<technologicalApplicability xml:lang="zh">该数据集描述了使用新型干法技术生产42.5MPa强度的普通硅酸盐水泥。它通常应用于需要高强度混凝土的建筑项目，适用于各种类型的大型土木工程和建筑工程。</technologicalApplicability>
			<referenceToTechnologyFlowDiagrammOrPicture type="source data set" refObjectId="90052edb-0515-27ec-bb95-5f72115442e0" uri="../sources/90052edb-0515-27ec-bb95-5f72115442e0.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">XA6XbLTghoC6BSxp2JecqQpxnfb.png</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToTechnologyFlowDiagrammOrPicture>
		</technology>
		<mathematicalRelations>
			<modelDescription xml:lang="en">The functional unit is the service performance of 1 kilogram of cement with a 28-day compressive strength of 42.5MPa, that is, IFu=42.5kgMPa.The research scope is defined as: raw material pretreatment, raw material grinding, raw material calcination, clinker grinding, cement homogenization, and cement storage.</modelDescription>
			<modelDescription xml:lang="zh">以1千克28天抗压强度为42.5MPa的水泥所具有的使用性能为功能单位，即IFu=42.5kgMPa。研究范围界定为：原料预处理一生料粉磨一生料煅烧一熟料粉磨一水泥均化一水泥储存。</modelDescription>
		</mathematicalRelations>
	</processInformation>
	<modellingAndValidation>
		<LCIMethodAndAllocation>
			<typeOfDataSet>Unit process, black box</typeOfDataSet>
			<LCIMethodPrinciple>Not applicable</LCIMethodPrinciple>
			<deviationsFromLCIMethodPrinciple xml:lang="en">None</deviationsFromLCIMethodPrinciple>
			<deviationsFromLCIMethodPrinciple xml:lang="zh">无</deviationsFromLCIMethodPrinciple>
			<deviationsFromModellingConstants xml:lang="en">None</deviationsFromModellingConstants>
			<deviationsFromModellingConstants xml:lang="zh">无</deviationsFromModellingConstants>
		</LCIMethodAndAllocation>
		<dataSourcesTreatmentAndRepresentativeness>
			<deviationsFromCutOffAndCompletenessPrinciples xml:lang="en">None</deviationsFromCutOffAndCompletenessPrinciples>
			<deviationsFromCutOffAndCompletenessPrinciples xml:lang="zh">无</deviationsFromCutOffAndCompletenessPrinciples>
			<deviationsFromSelectionAndCombinationPrinciples xml:lang="en">None</deviationsFromSelectionAndCombinationPrinciples>
			<deviationsFromSelectionAndCombinationPrinciples xml:lang="zh">无</deviationsFromSelectionAndCombinationPrinciples>
			<deviationsFromTreatmentAndExtrapolationPrinciples xml:lang="en">None</deviationsFromTreatmentAndExtrapolationPrinciples>
			<deviationsFromTreatmentAndExtrapolationPrinciples xml:lang="zh">无</deviationsFromTreatmentAndExtrapolationPrinciples>
			<referenceToDataSource type="source data set" refObjectId="0835e8c8-ee9f-4d76-a513-9d8a610aeca1" uri="../sources/0835e8c8-ee9f-4d76-a513-9d8a610aeca1.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">曹晓润. (2005). 低环境负荷型水泥的生态环境评价 [硕士, 武汉理工大学]. </common:shortDescription>
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="zh">曹晓润. (2005). 低环境负荷型水泥的生态环境评价 [硕士, 武汉理工大学]. </common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToDataSource>
			<useAdviceForDataSet xml:lang="en">The dataset outlines the life cycle assessment of cement production and should be used considering the prescribed boundary which includes raw material pretreatment, raw material grinding, raw material calcination, clinker grinding, cement homogenization, and cement storage. Users must account for other emissions and energy use beyond this scope separately. Ensure that the application of this data is consistent with the 42.5MPa strength grade and matches the technology described; discrepancies between the processes may lead to inaccuracies in assessment results.</useAdviceForDataSet>
			<useAdviceForDataSet xml:lang="zh">该数据集概述了水泥生产的生命周期评估，使用时应考虑规定的边界，包括原料预处理、生料磨、生料煅烧、熟料磨、水泥均质化和水泥储存。用户必须单独核算超出此范围的其他排放和能源使用。确保此数据的应用与42.5MPa强度等级一致，并与描述的技术相匹配；过程之间的差异可能导致评估结果不准确。</useAdviceForDataSet>
		</dataSourcesTreatmentAndRepresentativeness>
		<completeness/>
		<validation>
			<review type="Dependent internal review">
				<common:reviewDetails xml:lang="en">Inventory: The internal review was done by several iteration steps concerning raw data validation, raw data documentation, representativity, completeness and consistency of modelling with regard to ISO 14040 and 14044.</common:reviewDetails>
				<common:reviewDetails xml:lang="zh">清单： 内部审查通过几个迭代步骤完成，涉及原始数据验证、原始数据记录、代表性、完整性、与 ISO 14040 和 14044 有关的建模的一致性。</common:reviewDetails>
				<common:referenceToNameOfReviewerAndInstitution refObjectId="f4b4c314-8c4c-4c83-968f-5b3c7724f6a8" type="contact data set" uri="../contacts/f4b4c314-8c4c-4c83-968f-5b3c7724f6a8.xml">
					<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">Tiangong LCI Data Working Group</common:shortDescription>
					<common:shortDescription xml:lang="zh">天工LCI数据工作小组</common:shortDescription>
				</common:referenceToNameOfReviewerAndInstitution>
			</review>
		</validation>
	</modellingAndValidation>
	<administrativeInformation>
		<dataGenerator>
			<common:referenceToPersonOrEntityGeneratingTheDataSet type="contact data set" refObjectId="8ef5498f-0005-47f9-91da-1ded9b451ba1" uri="../contacts/8ef5498f-0005-47f9-91da-1ded9b451ba1.xml" version="01.00.000">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">Siqi Yang, ysqsophia@gmail.com</common:shortDescription>
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="zh">杨思琪, ysqsophia@gmail.com</common:shortDescription>
			</common:referenceToPersonOrEntityGeneratingTheDataSet>
			<common:other xml:lang="en">ysqsophia@gmail.com</common:other>
			<common:other xml:lang="zh">ysqsophia@gmail.com</common:other>
		</dataGenerator>
		<dataEntryBy>
			<common:timeStamp>2023-12-21T10:49:48+08:00</common:timeStamp>
		</dataEntryBy>
		<publicationAndOwnership>
			<common:dateOfLastRevision>2024-01-27T10:33:36.549103+08:00</common:dateOfLastRevision>
			<common:dataSetVersion>00.01.004</common:dataSetVersion>
			<common:permanentDataSetURI>https://lcadata.tiangong.world/showProcess.xhtml?uuid=421f85d8-34cb-4c46-a73b-82176dc99ceb&amp;amp;version=01.00.000&amp;amp;stock=TianGong</common:permanentDataSetURI>
			<common:referenceToOwnershipOfDataSet refObjectId="f4b4c314-8c4c-4c83-968f-5b3c7724f6a8" type="contact data set" uri="../contacts/f4b4c314-8c4c-4c83-968f-5b3c7724f6a8.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">Tiangong LCI Data Working Group</common:shortDescription>
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="zh">天工LCI数据工作小组</common:shortDescription>
			</common:referenceToOwnershipOfDataSet>
			<common:copyright>false</common:copyright>
			<common:licenseType>Free of charge for all users and uses</common:licenseType>
		</publicationAndOwnership>
	</administrativeInformation>
	<exchanges>
		<exchange dataSetInternalID="0">
			<referenceToFlowDataSet type="flow data set" refObjectId="c431c0c3-3f5e-4b7b-af99-2ebbdcaf5f98" uri="../flows/c431c0c3-3f5e-4b7b-af99-2ebbdcaf5f98.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">limestone, crushed, for mill</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToFlowDataSet>
			<exchangeDirection>Input</exchangeDirection>
			<meanAmount>1073.7</meanAmount>
			<resultingAmount>1073.7</resultingAmount>
			<dataDerivationTypeStatus></dataDerivationTypeStatus>
			<generalComment xml:lang="en">Limestone</generalComment>
			<generalComment xml:lang="zh">石灰石</generalComment>
		</exchange>
		<exchange dataSetInternalID="1">
			<referenceToFlowDataSet type="flow data set" refObjectId="4f19a2fe-7b3b-11dd-ad8b-0800200c9a66" uri="../flows/4f19a2fe-7b3b-11dd-ad8b-0800200c9a66.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">gypsum stone (CaSO4-dihydrate)</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToFlowDataSet>
			<exchangeDirection>Input</exchangeDirection>
			<meanAmount>51.1</meanAmount>
			<resultingAmount>51.1</resultingAmount>
			<dataDerivationTypeStatus></dataDerivationTypeStatus>
			<generalComment xml:lang="en">Gupsum</generalComment>
			<generalComment xml:lang="zh">石膏</generalComment>
		</exchange>
		<exchange dataSetInternalID="2">
			<referenceToFlowDataSet type="flow data set" refObjectId="000194b6-3952-98e9-d1ad-0000493d769a" uri="../flows/000194b6-3952-98e9-d1ad-0000493d769a.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">ash</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToFlowDataSet>
			<exchangeDirection>Input</exchangeDirection>
			<meanAmount>98.0</meanAmount>
			<resultingAmount>98.0</resultingAmount>
			<dataDerivationTypeStatus></dataDerivationTypeStatus>
			<generalComment xml:lang="en">Fly ash</generalComment>
			<generalComment xml:lang="zh">粉煤灰</generalComment>
		</exchange>
		<exchange dataSetInternalID="3">
			<referenceToFlowDataSet type="flow data set" refObjectId="98d3683b-565f-492d-b2df-de9de017bb28" uri="../flows/98d3683b-565f-492d-b2df-de9de017bb28.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">blast furnace slag</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToFlowDataSet>
			<exchangeDirection>Input</exchangeDirection>
			<meanAmount>137.6</meanAmount>
			<resultingAmount>137.6</resultingAmount>
			<dataDerivationTypeStatus></dataDerivationTypeStatus>
			<generalComment xml:lang="en">The original document is labeled as &quot;slag&quot; (i.e. blast furnace slag).</generalComment>
			<generalComment xml:lang="zh">原文献是矿渣（即高炉矿渣）</generalComment>
		</exchange>
		<exchange dataSetInternalID="4">
			<referenceToFlowDataSet type="flow data set" refObjectId="4f19a2ff-7b3b-11dd-ad8b-0800200c9a66" uri="../flows/4f19a2ff-7b3b-11dd-ad8b-0800200c9a66.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">hard coal</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToFlowDataSet>
			<exchangeDirection>Input</exchangeDirection>
			<meanAmount>100.957</meanAmount>
			<resultingAmount>100.957</resultingAmount>
			<dataDerivationTypeStatus></dataDerivationTypeStatus>
			<generalComment xml:lang="en">The original data is 0.0938kg standard coal, here converted to hard coal, the conversion formula is 1kg hard coal = 0.929kg standard coal.</generalComment>
			<generalComment xml:lang="zh">原始数据为0.0938kg标准煤，这里换算为硬煤，换算公式为1kg硬煤=0.929kg标准煤。</generalComment>
		</exchange>
		<exchange dataSetInternalID="5">
			<referenceToFlowDataSet type="flow data set" refObjectId="890a70b7-b677-4e2a-8a1b-7d017e0a10ae" uri="../flows/890a70b7-b677-4e2a-8a1b-7d017e0a10ae.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">Electricity</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToFlowDataSet>
			<exchangeDirection>Input</exchangeDirection>
			<meanAmount>347.76</meanAmount>
			<resultingAmount>347.76</resultingAmount>
			<dataDerivationTypeStatus></dataDerivationTypeStatus>
			<generalComment xml:lang="en">Electricity</generalComment>
			<generalComment xml:lang="zh">电力</generalComment>
		</exchange>
		<exchange dataSetInternalID="6">
			<referenceToFlowDataSet type="flow data set" refObjectId="fe0acd60-3ddc-11dd-a70a-0050c2490048" uri="../flows/fe0acd60-3ddc-11dd-a70a-0050c2490048.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">particles (&gt; PM10)</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToFlowDataSet>
			<exchangeDirection>Output</exchangeDirection>
			<meanAmount>0.15</meanAmount>
			<resultingAmount>0.15</resultingAmount>
			<dataDerivationTypeStatus></dataDerivationTypeStatus>
			<generalComment xml:lang="en">Dust, with an unspecified particle size, is treated as PM &gt; 10 micrometers in diameter.</generalComment>
			<generalComment xml:lang="zh">粉尘，未标明粒径，按PM&gt;10处理。</generalComment>
		</exchange>
		<exchange dataSetInternalID="7">
			<referenceToFlowDataSet type="flow data set" refObjectId="fe0acd60-3ddc-11dd-ac48-0050c2490048" uri="../flows/fe0acd60-3ddc-11dd-ac48-0050c2490048.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">sulfur dioxide</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToFlowDataSet>
			<exchangeDirection>Output</exchangeDirection>
			<meanAmount>0.3501</meanAmount>
			<resultingAmount>0.3501</resultingAmount>
			<dataDerivationTypeStatus></dataDerivationTypeStatus>
			<generalComment xml:lang="en">Sulfur dioxide. Considering the actual operating conditions of domestic cement plants and the development trend for the foreseeable future, the statistical average of measured data is adopted for this evaluation.</generalComment>
			<generalComment xml:lang="zh">二氧化硫。考虑到国内水泥厂运行的实际情况和未来很长时间的发展趋势，本次评价采用实测数据的统计平均值。</generalComment>
		</exchange>
		<exchange dataSetInternalID="8">
			<referenceToFlowDataSet type="flow data set" refObjectId="f79d0f8f-2b0e-49cb-bed0-b1ea0fbd8625" uri="../flows/f79d0f8f-2b0e-49cb-bed0-b1ea0fbd8625.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">Nitrogen oxides</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToFlowDataSet>
			<exchangeDirection>Output</exchangeDirection>
			<meanAmount>1.419</meanAmount>
			<resultingAmount>1.419</resultingAmount>
			<dataDerivationTypeStatus></dataDerivationTypeStatus>
			<generalComment xml:lang="en">Nitrogen oxides. Considering the actual operating conditions of domestic cement plants and the development trend for the foreseeable future, the statistical average of measured data is adopted for this evaluation.</generalComment>
			<generalComment xml:lang="zh">氮氧化物。考虑到国内水泥厂运行的实际情况和未来很长时间的发展趋势，本次评价采用实测数据的统计平均值。</generalComment>
		</exchange>
		<exchange dataSetInternalID="9">
			<referenceToFlowDataSet type="flow data set" refObjectId="fe0acd60-3ddc-11dd-af54-0050c2490048" uri="../flows/fe0acd60-3ddc-11dd-af54-0050c2490048.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">carbon dioxide</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToFlowDataSet>
			<exchangeDirection>Output</exchangeDirection>
			<meanAmount>807.3</meanAmount>
			<resultingAmount>807.3</resultingAmount>
			<dataDerivationTypeStatus></dataDerivationTypeStatus>
			<generalComment xml:lang="en">Carbon dioxide. Considering the actual operating conditions of domestic cement plants and the development trend for the foreseeable future, the statistical average of measured data is adopted for this evaluation.</generalComment>
			<generalComment xml:lang="zh">二氧化碳。考虑到国内水泥厂运行的实际情况和未来很长时间的发展趋势，本次评价采用实测数据的统计平均值。</generalComment>
		</exchange>
		<exchange dataSetInternalID="10">
			<referenceToFlowDataSet type="flow data set" refObjectId="89fb85db-c8dc-426c-a4cd-52de2184a31b" uri="../flows/89fb85db-c8dc-426c-a4cd-52de2184a31b.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">cement, ordinary portland cement, 42.5MPa</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToFlowDataSet>
			<exchangeDirection>Output</exchangeDirection>
			<meanAmount>1000.0</meanAmount>
			<resultingAmount>1000.0</resultingAmount>
			<dataDerivationTypeStatus></dataDerivationTypeStatus>
			<generalComment xml:lang="en">42.5 grade silicate composite cement cement</generalComment>
			<generalComment xml:lang="zh">42.5普通硅酸盐水泥</generalComment>
		</exchange>
	</exchanges>
</processDataSet>
