<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet version="1.0" href="../../stylesheets/process2html.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<processDataSet xmlns:common="http://lca.jrc.it/ILCD/Common" xmlns="http://lca.jrc.it/ILCD/Process" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" version="1.1" locations="../ILCDLocations.xml" xsi:schemaLocation="http://lca.jrc.it/ILCD/Process ../../schemas/ILCD_ProcessDataSet.xsd">
	<processInformation>
		<dataSetInformation>
			<common:UUID>4aaff338-966e-486c-9890-fe0641c48511</common:UUID>
			<name>
				<baseName xml:lang="en">Northwest Wheat Production | Shaanxi Wheat Production</baseName>
				<baseName xml:lang="zh">西北小麦| 陕西小麦生产</baseName>
			</name>
			<classificationInformation>
				<common:classification>
					<common:class level="0">Materials production</common:class>
					<common:class level="1">Other mineralic materials</common:class>
				</common:classification>
			</classificationInformation>
			<common:generalComment xml:lang="en">Reducing the carbon footprint (CF) of crop production is an efficient way to mitigate climate change. Growing legume green manure (LGM) instead of summer fallow may achieve this goal by lowering synthetic nitrogen (N) fertilizer needs and replenishing the depleted soil carbon (C) pool. The Rothamsted Carbon (RothC) model was incorporated into the Life-Cycle Assessment (LCA) to evaluate the present and projected CFs of green manure-based wheat production systems in dryland agriculture on the Loess Plateau of China. The ﬁeld study included four main treatments (Huai bean, soybean and mung bean grown as green manure in summer and fallow as control) and four synthetic N rates (0, 108, 135 and 162 kg N ha−1) applied at wheat sowing. Soybean as LGM increased averaged wheat yield over 4 synthetic N rates by 8% compared with fallow (P b 0.05), and synthetic N requirement was reduced by 33% without compromising the wheat yield for all the main treatments. Although LGM treatments had higher greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions from agricultural inputs, the greater amount ofC inputs elevated the corresponding SOC stocks (SOCS) by 14–24% after 8 years, thus signiﬁcantly reducing the CF by 25–51% compared with fallow. The modelled SOCS equilibrium indicates that the CF for cropping systems with LGMwill be 53–62% lower than fallow and 23–37% lower compared with their current level. In conclusion, introducing legume green manure instead of summer fallow is a highly efﬁcient measure for persistent CF reduction, and coupling the RothC model and LCA is an alternative method to predict the long-term impact of different cropping systems on GHG emissions.</common:generalComment>
		</dataSetInformation>
		<quantitativeReference type="Reference flow(s)">
			<functionalUnitOrOther xml:lang="en">kg CO2 eq ha−1</functionalUnitOrOther>
		</quantitativeReference>
		<time>
			<common:referenceYear>2008</common:referenceYear>
			<common:timeRepresentativenessDescription xml:lang="en">The on-going experiment was initiated in June 2008 and arranged in a split-plot design. There were four main treatments: (i) summer fallow–winter wheat (Triticum aestivum L.) (control), (ii) Huai bean (Glycine ussuriensis Regel et Maack)–winter wheat, (iii) soybean (G. max (L.) Merr.)–winter wheat and (iv) mung bean (Phaseolus radiatus L.)–winter wheat. The sub-treatments included four synthetic N rates: 0 (N0), 108 (N1), 135 (N2) and 162 (N3) kg N ha−1 applied at wheat sowing. N3 is the average synthetic N level in this area, thus summer fallow–winter wheat at N3 is the traditional practice. Each plot was 6× 5m2 and replicated three times.</common:timeRepresentativenessDescription>
		</time>
		<geography>
			<locationOfOperationSupplyOrProduction location="XY-SAX-CN">
				<descriptionOfRestrictions xml:lang="en">Changwu County</descriptionOfRestrictions>
				<descriptionOfRestrictions xml:lang="zh">长武县</descriptionOfRestrictions>
			</locationOfOperationSupplyOrProduction>
		</geography>
		<technology>
			<technologyDescriptionAndIncludedProcesses xml:lang="en">After wheat harvest in late June, thewheat strawwas removed from the plots. The field was ploughed (0–20 cm) with a rotavator to prepare the seedbed for LGM. Legumes were seeded via a planter in late June to early July after wheat harvest, depending on the weather conditions. The seeding rates of mung bean, soybean and Huai bean were 135, 150 and 165 kg ha−1, respectively. Seven to eight weeks after legume seeding (late August to early September), fresh legume samples at full-bloom stage were collected manually; the rest of the plot was terminated, and the LGM was spread evenly within corresponding plot. The plant residues were then chopped into small pieces with farmmachinery and immediately incorporated into the soil to a depth of 20 cm using a rotavator. After decomposing for 2 to 3weeks, winterwheat was planted at a seeding rate of 180 kg ha−1 and with varying N fertilizer (urea, 46% N) rates and 120 kg P2O5 ha−1 (triple superphosphate-TSP, 46% P2O5) as basal fertilizer for each treatment, both applied at sowing in late September.</technologyDescriptionAndIncludedProcesses>
			<referenceToTechnologyFlowDiagrammOrPicture type="source data set" refObjectId="6482c43c-772f-b937-d2f0-653341429169" uri="../sources/6482c43c-772f-b937-d2f0-653341429169.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">Bw1wbcXnTosVH2xbHq7clvgknlh.png</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToTechnologyFlowDiagrammOrPicture>
		</technology>
		<mathematicalRelations/>
	</processInformation>
	<modellingAndValidation>
		<LCIMethodAndAllocation>
			<typeOfDataSet></typeOfDataSet>
			<LCIMethodPrinciple>Attributional</LCIMethodPrinciple>
			<deviationsFromLCIMethodPrinciple xml:lang="en">None</deviationsFromLCIMethodPrinciple>
			<LCIMethodApproach>Consequential</LCIMethodApproach>
			<deviationsFromLCIMethodApproaches xml:lang="en">The carbon footprint ofa cropping systemcan be expressed in terms of the total global warming potential (GWP) taking into consideration e.g. soil GHG emissions, soil carbon (C) sequestration, fuel, fertilizer and lime usage (Hauggaard-Nielsen et al., 2016). To evaluate the CF of studied treatments, the LCA was applied with a system boundary of cradle-to-farm gate (Fig. 1) and the functional unit was expressed as kg CO2 eq ha−1.Specifically, the life-cycle inventory (LCI) for the estimated CF of this study considered the following emissions: 1) themanufacture, storage and transport of synthetic N and P fertilizer; 2) the diesel fuel consumption of the farm machinery used for ﬁeld operation; 3) CO2 from synthetic N application and N2O emissions caused by LGM, wheat residue and synthetic N (the soil background N2O emissions and those during the growth period of legumes are relatively low (Barton et al., 2011). Therefore, these parts ofN2O were not included in this research. The methane emissions from the ﬁeld were also neglected in this study because it contributes minimally to the CF in dryland agriculture); and 4) the change in SOCS.</deviationsFromLCIMethodApproaches>
			<deviationsFromModellingConstants xml:lang="en">None</deviationsFromModellingConstants>
		</LCIMethodAndAllocation>
		<dataSourcesTreatmentAndRepresentativeness>
			<deviationsFromCutOffAndCompletenessPrinciples xml:lang="en">None</deviationsFromCutOffAndCompletenessPrinciples>
			<deviationsFromSelectionAndCombinationPrinciples xml:lang="en">None</deviationsFromSelectionAndCombinationPrinciples>
			<dataTreatmentAndExtrapolationsPrinciples xml:lang="en">The RothC model (Ver. 26.3) was applied to simulate the annual SOCS dynamics of the different treatments and predict the corresponding SOCS at the new equilibrium. Soil organic carbon of this model is split into four active compartments and a small amount of inert organic matter (IOM). The four active compartments are Decomposable Plant Material (DPM), Resistant Plant Material (RPM), Microbial Biomass (BIO) and Humified Organic Matter (HUM). Each compartment decomposes by a ﬁrst-order process with its own characteristic rate. The IOM compartment is resistant to decomposition (Coleman and Jenkinson, 2014). To run the model, average temperature, open pan evaporation, soil clay content in the plough layer and the ratio of DPM: RPM were used. For fallow treatment, the C was from wheat residue and the default value DPM:RPM= 1.44 was applied; for treatments with LGM, a higher DPM:RPM= 3.35 was used for simulation.</dataTreatmentAndExtrapolationsPrinciples>
			<deviationsFromTreatmentAndExtrapolationPrinciples xml:lang="en">None</deviationsFromTreatmentAndExtrapolationPrinciples>
			<referenceToDataSource type="source data set" refObjectId="5986568f-0744-447c-b6fe-04b8d5f7859e" uri="../sources/5986568f-0744-447c-b6fe-04b8d5f7859e.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">Yao, Z. et al. Coupling life-cycle assessment and the RothC model to estimate the carbon footprint of green manure-based wheat production in China. Science of The Total Environment 607–608, 433–442 (2017).</common:shortDescription>
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="zh">Yao, Z. et al. Coupling life-cycle assessment and the RothC model to estimate the carbon footprint of green manure-based wheat production in China. Science of The Total Environment 607–608, 433–442 (2017).</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToDataSource>
			<samplingProcedure xml:lang="en">The 0–20 cm soil samples were collected with a 5-cm diameter soil auger each year after wheat harvest for SOC determination; the depth was chosen based on the fact that most ofthe root biomass was distributed within this layer and both wheat residue and LGM were incorporated into soil no deeper than 20 cm. To homogenize the soil sample, 3 soil cores were collected in each plot and mixed together. The airdried soil samples were ground to pass a 0.25-mm sieve for SOC determination via K2Cr2O7–H2SO4 wet oxidation. To procure accurate SOCcontent data, all the samples from2008 to 2016were measured together and each batch was calibrated using certified reference materials (China Geological Survey).</samplingProcedure>
		</dataSourcesTreatmentAndRepresentativeness>
		<completeness/>
		<validation>
			<review type="Dependent internal review">
				<common:reviewDetails xml:lang="en">Inventory: The internal review was done by several iteration steps concerning raw data validation, raw data documentation, representativity, completeness and consistency of modelling with regard to ISO 14040 and 14044.</common:reviewDetails>
				<common:reviewDetails xml:lang="zh">清单： 内部审查通过几个迭代步骤完成，涉及原始数据验证、原始数据记录、代表性、完整性、与 ISO 14040 和 14044 有关的建模的一致性。</common:reviewDetails>
				<common:referenceToNameOfReviewerAndInstitution refObjectId="f4b4c314-8c4c-4c83-968f-5b3c7724f6a8" type="contact data set" uri="../contacts/f4b4c314-8c4c-4c83-968f-5b3c7724f6a8.xml">
					<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">Tiangong LCI Data Working Group</common:shortDescription>
					<common:shortDescription xml:lang="zh">天工LCI数据工作小组</common:shortDescription>
				</common:referenceToNameOfReviewerAndInstitution>
			</review>
		</validation>
	</modellingAndValidation>
	<administrativeInformation>
		<dataGenerator>
			<common:referenceToPersonOrEntityGeneratingTheDataSet type="contact data set" refObjectId="0baacd46-c1ae-4c45-91a8-c085fba4757c" uri="../contacts/0baacd46-c1ae-4c45-91a8-c085fba4757c.xml" version="01.00.000">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">Haoran Zhang, hrzhang@whu.edu.cn</common:shortDescription>
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="zh">张浩然, hrzhang@whu.edu.cn</common:shortDescription>
			</common:referenceToPersonOrEntityGeneratingTheDataSet>
			<common:other xml:lang="en">hrzhang@whu.edu.cn</common:other>
			<common:other xml:lang="zh">hrzhang@whu.edu.cn</common:other>
		</dataGenerator>
		<dataEntryBy>
			<common:timeStamp>2023-11-03T09:57:25+08:00</common:timeStamp>
		</dataEntryBy>
		<publicationAndOwnership>
			<common:dateOfLastRevision>2023-11-03T09:57:25+08:00</common:dateOfLastRevision>
			<common:dataSetVersion>01.00.000</common:dataSetVersion>
			<common:copyright>false</common:copyright>
		</publicationAndOwnership>
	</administrativeInformation>
	<exchanges/>
</processDataSet>
