<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet version="1.0" href="../../stylesheets/process2html.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<processDataSet xmlns:common="http://lca.jrc.it/ILCD/Common" xmlns="http://lca.jrc.it/ILCD/Process" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" version="1.1" locations="../ILCDLocations.xml" xsi:schemaLocation="http://lca.jrc.it/ILCD/Process ../../schemas/ILCD_ProcessDataSet.xsd">
	<processInformation>
		<dataSetInformation>
			<common:UUID>5b66f9e9-6bcd-4bce-b33a-70cf3fe69a93</common:UUID>
			<name>
				<baseName xml:lang="en">The production of CLT | Cross-Laminated Timber (CLT) | 1 m3 of CLT is comprised of the following: Softwood lumber: 428 odkg (462 kg @ 8% M.C.); Resins: 2.7 kg; Total mass: 464.7 kg</baseName>
			</name>
			<classificationInformation>
				<common:classification>
					<common:class level="0">Materials production</common:class>
					<common:class level="1">Other mineralic materials</common:class>
				</common:classification>
			</classificationInformation>
		</dataSetInformation>
		<quantitativeReference type="Reference flow(s)">
			<functionalUnitOrOther xml:lang="en">The purpose of the functional unit is to quantify the service delivered by the product system and provide a reference to which the inputs and outputs can be related. For EPDs covering the complete life cycle (based on a “cradle-to-grave” LCA study), a functional unit is defined. For EPDs not covering the complete life cycle (e.g. “cradle-to gate” LCA study -leaving out the use and/or the end of life), a declared unit is defined. The declared unit is defined as “the production of one cubic meter (1 m3) of CLT produced in British Columbia.”</functionalUnitOrOther>
		</quantitativeReference>
		<time/>
		<geography>
			<locationOfOperationSupplyOrProduction location="CA">
				<descriptionOfRestrictions xml:lang="en">“The surveyed data is representative of the BC CLT industry as the 3 surveyed facilities represent all currently operating CLT manufacturing facilities in BC.” </descriptionOfRestrictions>
			</locationOfOperationSupplyOrProduction>
		</geography>
		<technology/>
		<mathematicalRelations/>
	</processInformation>
	<modellingAndValidation>
		<LCIMethodAndAllocation>
			<typeOfDataSet>Unit process, single operation</typeOfDataSet>
			<LCIMethodPrinciple></LCIMethodPrinciple>
			<deviationsFromLCIMethodPrinciple xml:lang="en">None</deviationsFromLCIMethodPrinciple>
			<LCIMethodApproach>Allocation - mass</LCIMethodApproach>
			<deviationsFromLCIMethodApproaches xml:lang="en">&quot;Allocation is the method used to partition the environmental load of a process when several products or functions share the same process. CLT manufacturing is a single output process, where the CLT is the only product that is produced. The CLT manufacturing process does produce wood waste that is transferred for free to downstream users, but no environmental burden has been allocated to these wastes. The lumber input to the CLT manufacturing process is, however, a product that results from a multiple output process whereby valuable coproducts are produced and sold. In accordance with UL PCRs, “mass” was deemed as the most appropriate parameter for allocation of these inputs and thus the “mass allocation” results incorporate lumber data based on mass allocation. A detailed explanation of the lumber allocation methodology is provided in the lumber LCA project report” (Athena Sustainale Materials Institute, 2021, p. 8)</deviationsFromLCIMethodApproaches>
			<deviationsFromModellingConstants xml:lang="en">None</deviationsFromModellingConstants>
		</LCIMethodAndAllocation>
		<dataSourcesTreatmentAndRepresentativeness>
			<deviationsFromCutOffAndCompletenessPrinciples xml:lang="en">None</deviationsFromCutOffAndCompletenessPrinciples>
			<deviationsFromSelectionAndCombinationPrinciples xml:lang="en">None</deviationsFromSelectionAndCombinationPrinciples>
			<deviationsFromTreatmentAndExtrapolationPrinciples xml:lang="en">None</deviationsFromTreatmentAndExtrapolationPrinciples>
			<referenceToDataSource type="source data set" refObjectId="cc2d27ef-3d11-44cf-8a21-bf6fc355e4ec" uri="../sources/cc2d27ef-3d11-44cf-8a21-bf6fc355e4ec.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">Athena Sustainale Materials Institute. A Cradle-to-Gate Life Cycle Assessment  of CLT produced in British Columbia. (2021).</common:shortDescription>
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="zh">Athena Sustainale Materials Institute. A Cradle-to-Gate Life Cycle Assessment  of CLT produced in British Columbia. (2021).</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToDataSource>
		</dataSourcesTreatmentAndRepresentativeness>
		<completeness>
			<common:other xml:lang="en">This is a “cradle-to gate” LCA study -leaving out the use and/or the end of life.Both human activity and capital equipment were excluded from the system boundary. The environmental effects of manufacturing and installing capital equipment and buildings have generally been shown to be minor relative to the throughput of materials and components over the useful lives of the buildings and equipment.The cut-off criteria for all activity stage flows considered within the system boundary conform with ISO 21930: 2017 Section 7.1.8. Specifically, the cut-off criteria were applied as follows:• All inputs and outputs for which data are available are included in the calculated effects and no collected core process data are excluded.• A one percent cut-off is considered for renewable and non-renewable primary energy consumption and the total mass of inputs within a unit process. The sum of the total neglected flows does not exceed 5% of all energy consumption and mass of inputs.• All flows known to contribute a significant impact or to uncertainty are included.• The cut-off rules are not applied to hazardous and toxic material flows – all of which are included in the life cycle inventory.No material or energy input or output was knowingly excluded from the system boundary.</common:other>
		</completeness>
		<validation>
			<review type="Dependent internal review">
				<common:reviewDetails xml:lang="en">Inventory: The internal review was done by several iteration steps concerning raw data validation, raw data documentation, representativity, completeness and consistency of modelling with regard to ISO 14040 and 14044.</common:reviewDetails>
				<common:reviewDetails xml:lang="zh">清单： 内部审查通过几个迭代步骤完成，涉及原始数据验证、原始数据记录、代表性、完整性、与 ISO 14040 和 14044 有关的建模的一致性。</common:reviewDetails>
				<common:referenceToNameOfReviewerAndInstitution refObjectId="f4b4c314-8c4c-4c83-968f-5b3c7724f6a8" type="contact data set" uri="../contacts/f4b4c314-8c4c-4c83-968f-5b3c7724f6a8.xml">
					<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">Tiangong LCI Data Working Group</common:shortDescription>
					<common:shortDescription xml:lang="zh">天工LCI数据工作小组</common:shortDescription>
				</common:referenceToNameOfReviewerAndInstitution>
			</review>
		</validation>
	</modellingAndValidation>
	<administrativeInformation>
		<dataGenerator>
			<common:referenceToPersonOrEntityGeneratingTheDataSet type="contact data set" refObjectId="df059f52-a1c7-4bff-9ef1-9335a3530e71" uri="../contacts/df059f52-a1c7-4bff-9ef1-9335a3530e71.xml" version="01.00.000">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">Wanyue Tan, wytan9@student.ubc.ca</common:shortDescription>
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="zh">谭惋月, wytan9@student.ubc.ca</common:shortDescription>
			</common:referenceToPersonOrEntityGeneratingTheDataSet>
			<common:other xml:lang="en">wytan9@student.ubc.ca</common:other>
			<common:other xml:lang="zh">wytan9@student.ubc.ca</common:other>
		</dataGenerator>
		<dataEntryBy>
			<common:timeStamp>2023-11-15T15:44:39+08:00</common:timeStamp>
		</dataEntryBy>
		<publicationAndOwnership>
			<common:dateOfLastRevision>2023-11-15T15:44:39+08:00</common:dateOfLastRevision>
			<common:dataSetVersion>01.00.000</common:dataSetVersion>
			<common:copyright>false</common:copyright>
		</publicationAndOwnership>
	</administrativeInformation>
	<exchanges/>
</processDataSet>
