<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet version="1.0" href="../../stylesheets/process2html.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<processDataSet xmlns:common="http://lca.jrc.it/ILCD/Common" xmlns="http://lca.jrc.it/ILCD/Process" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" version="1.1" locations="../ILCDLocations.xml" xsi:schemaLocation="http://lca.jrc.it/ILCD/Process ../../schemas/ILCD_ProcessDataSet.xsd">
	<processInformation>
		<dataSetInformation>
			<common:UUID>7b53effa-ba79-46b2-adfc-fc2897939f2a</common:UUID>
			<name>
				<baseName xml:lang="en">small-scale intensive pig production | Pig production</baseName>
				<baseName xml:lang="zh">小规模集约化生猪生产|生猪生产</baseName>
			</name>
			<classificationInformation>
				<common:classification>
					<common:class level="0">Materials production</common:class>
					<common:class level="1">Other mineralic materials</common:class>
				</common:classification>
			</classificationInformation>
			<common:generalComment xml:lang="en">On-site pig operations cover a pig's whole life cycle, including piglet production, pig rearing, manure management, to the final slaughtering. A pig's life cycle (see Fig. S1) starts from adult female pigs (gilts or sows) reach maturity and mate with adult male pigs (boars). The main difference between gilts and sows lies in that whether they have given birth to their first litter before. After mating, adult female pigs have a pregnancy (gestation) period of about 114 days. They are moved to a farrowing barn when ready to give birth (farrow). Usually, a female pig will fallow 8–12 baby pigs (piglets) per litter. The goal of most farmers is to have, on average, greater than two litters per sow per year. After giving birth, female pigs remain with their piglets, nursing for 3–4 weeks until the piglets are weaned (lactation). Then, they are either returned for mating or sent away for slaughter when they fail to rebreed.Weaned piglets (about 7.5 kg) are separated from the sows and start to be fed with solid feed. In the whole pig rearing stage, quality diets based on the nutritional requirements under different growth conditions are essential in maximizing the growth performance. First, these piglets are moved to a nursery facility and are housed with piglets from other litters, where they normally grow to 9–10 weeks of age (about 15–25 kg). After nursing, pigs enter the grower-finisher stage to gain weight until they are market-ready. Around 6–7 months of age, the market weight pigs (about 115 kg) are transported at a distance of approximately 370 km via truck for slaughter. A large amount of excreta is generated at the facility, separated into solid manure and slurry in house, and then further treated through compost and digestion. We also include the upstream production of resources and energy that are used for pig production, e.g. tap water for drinking and washing the pig house, electricity for illumination, and sodium hydroxide for disinfection. However, resource use and emissions related to infrastructure construction are not taken into account due to limited information. As recommended by the ISO standards, the system expansion method is used to deal with the multi-product systems. For instance, the fermented manure that can return to croplands as nutrient sources is assumed to avoid mineral fertilizer production (Laurent et al., 2014).</common:generalComment>
			<common:generalComment xml:lang="zh">养猪操作涵盖了猪的整个生命周期，包括仔猪生产、生猪饲养、粪便管理，直到最后的屠宰。猪的生命周期(见图S1)从成年母猪(后备母猪或母猪)到成熟并与成年公猪(公猪)交配开始。小母猪和母猪的主要区别在于它们以前是否生过第一胎。交配后，成年母猪的妊娠期约为114天。当准备分娩时，它们被转移到产房。通常，一头母猪每窝休耕8-12头小猪(仔猪)。大多数农民的目标是平均每头母猪每年产仔2窝以上。分娩后，母猪与仔猪呆在一起，哺乳3-4周，直到仔猪断奶(哺乳)。然后，它们要么被送回交配，要么在繁殖失败时被送去屠宰。断奶仔猪(约7.5公斤)与母猪分离，开始饲喂固体饲料。在全猪饲养阶段，根据不同生长条件下的营养需求选择优质饲粮，是提高猪生长性能的关键。首先，这些仔猪被转移到托儿所，并与其他窝的仔猪一起饲养，在那里它们通常长到9-10周龄(约15-25公斤)。在哺乳之后，猪进入生长-育肥阶段，以增加体重，直到它们准备上市。约6-7个月大时，市场体重猪(约115公斤)通过卡车运输，距离约370公里，用于屠宰。该设施产生大量排泄物，在室内分离成固体粪便和泥浆，然后通过堆肥和消化进一步处理。我们还包括用于养猪生产的上游资源和能源的生产，例如用于饮用和清洗猪舍的自来水，用于照明的电力和用于消毒的氢氧化钠。然而，由于信息有限，与基础设施建设相关的资源使用和排放并未考虑在内。根据ISO标准的推荐，系统扩展方法用于处理多产品系统。例如，假设发酵后的粪便可以作为营养来源返回农田，从而避免了矿物肥料的生产(Laurent et al.， 2014)。</common:generalComment>
		</dataSetInformation>
		<quantitativeReference type="Reference flow(s)">
			<functionalUnitOrOther xml:lang="en">The functional unit (FU) is defined to be 1000 kg of pig carcass weight (CW) after the process in slaughterhouse.</functionalUnitOrOther>
		</quantitativeReference>
		<time>
			<common:referenceYear>2010</common:referenceYear>
			<common:timeRepresentativenessDescription xml:lang="en">On-field investigation (Guo and Wang, 2010)</common:timeRepresentativenessDescription>
			<common:timeRepresentativenessDescription xml:lang="zh">实地调查(Guo and Wang, 2010)</common:timeRepresentativenessDescription>
		</time>
		<geography>
			<locationOfOperationSupplyOrProduction location="JS-CN">
				<descriptionOfRestrictions xml:lang="en">In this study, primary data about material and energy consumption, the composition of feed and the mixture with other ingredients at different pig production stages are derived from interviews with several pig production facilities in Jiangsu Province, China.</descriptionOfRestrictions>
				<descriptionOfRestrictions xml:lang="zh">在本研究中，关于猪生产不同阶段的材料和能源消耗、饲料组成以及与其他成分混合的主要数据来自对中国江苏省几家养猪场的采访。</descriptionOfRestrictions>
			</locationOfOperationSupplyOrProduction>
		</geography>
		<technology>
			<technologyDescriptionAndIncludedProcesses xml:lang="zh">因此，按照ISO标准14040和14044 (ISO 14040, 2006;ISO 14044, 2006)，使用开源软件openLCA(版本1.9.0)进行了从摇篮到屠宰场的生命周期分析，以评估中国小规模集约化养猪生产系统的环境影响，包括全球变暖、陆地酸化、淡水富营养化潜力和毒性指标。分析了不同生长阶段饲料配方的贡献。本研究为中国小规模生猪生产系统的环境热点问题提供了启示，并为后续的环境改善提供了基准，从而向可持续农业产业迈进。</technologyDescriptionAndIncludedProcesses>
			<technologyDescriptionAndIncludedProcesses xml:lang="en">Therefore, in accordance with the ISO standards 14040 and 14044 (ISO 14040, 2006; ISO 14044, 2006), a cradle-to-slaughterhouse gate life cycle analysis is performed using the open-source software openLCA (version 1.9.0) to evaluate the environmental impacts, including global warming, terrestrial acidification, freshwater eutrophication potential and toxicity indicators, of small-scale intensive pig production systems in China. The contribution of feed formulas from different growth stages is also analyzed. This study enlightens the environmental hotspots of small-scale pig production systems in China and provides a benchmark for subsequent environmental improvements to move towards a sustainable agriculture industry.</technologyDescriptionAndIncludedProcesses>
			<referenceToTechnologyFlowDiagrammOrPicture type="source data set" refObjectId="c6c3c8c0-e8e8-c1f8-395b-89ade9c807af" uri="../sources/c6c3c8c0-e8e8-c1f8-395b-89ade9c807af.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">QvBUbrN1woIT15xZ7LgcOyLTn2d.png</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToTechnologyFlowDiagrammOrPicture>
		</technology>
		<mathematicalRelations/>
	</processInformation>
	<modellingAndValidation>
		<LCIMethodAndAllocation>
			<typeOfDataSet>Unit process, single operation</typeOfDataSet>
			<LCIMethodPrinciple></LCIMethodPrinciple>
			<deviationsFromLCIMethodPrinciple xml:lang="en">None</deviationsFromLCIMethodPrinciple>
			<deviationsFromLCIMethodApproaches xml:lang="en">Based on the LCI results, life cycle impact assessment (LCIA) is carried out by using the ReCiPe midpoint (H) 2016 method (Huijbregts et al., 2016), which is an updated version of ReCiPe 2008 and now provides characterization factors that are representative with a global scope. Six impact categories are mostly used to evaluate the main life cycle environmental impact potentials, namely global warming (GWP), freshwater eutrophication (FEP), terrestrial acidification (TAP), freshwater ecotoxicity (FETP), human carcinogenic toxicity (HTP) and terrestrial ecotoxicity (TETP) (Cherubini et al., 2015; Noyaet al., 2017). Among them, GWP, FEP and TAP are the most concerned impact categories in previous studies (de Vries and de Boer, 2010; Reckmann et al., 2013).</deviationsFromLCIMethodApproaches>
			<deviationsFromLCIMethodApproaches xml:lang="zh">基于LCI结果，使用ReCiPe midpoint (H) 2016方法(Huijbregts et al.， 2016)进行生命周期影响评估(LCIA)，该方法是ReCiPe 2008的更新版本，现在提供具有全球范围代表性的表征因子。六个影响类别主要用于评估主要生命周期环境影响潜力，即全球变暖(GWP)、淡水富营养化(FEP)、陆地酸化(TAP)、淡水生态毒性(FETP)、人类致癌毒性(HTP)和陆地生态毒性(TETP) (Cherubini et al.， 2015;Noyaet al.， 2017)。其中，GWP、FEP和TAP是以往研究中最受关注的影响类别(de Vries和de Boer, 2010;Reckmann et al.， 2013)。</deviationsFromLCIMethodApproaches>
			<deviationsFromModellingConstants xml:lang="en">None</deviationsFromModellingConstants>
		</LCIMethodAndAllocation>
		<dataSourcesTreatmentAndRepresentativeness>
			<deviationsFromCutOffAndCompletenessPrinciples xml:lang="en">None</deviationsFromCutOffAndCompletenessPrinciples>
			<deviationsFromSelectionAndCombinationPrinciples xml:lang="en">None</deviationsFromSelectionAndCombinationPrinciples>
			<deviationsFromTreatmentAndExtrapolationPrinciples xml:lang="en">None</deviationsFromTreatmentAndExtrapolationPrinciples>
			<referenceToDataSource type="source data set" refObjectId="1e2326c8-3391-4eeb-bc12-0688b3d0db62" uri="../sources/1e2326c8-3391-4eeb-bc12-0688b3d0db62.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">Liu, X., Cai, Z. &amp; Yuan, Z. Environmental burdens of small-scale intensive pig production in China. Science of The Total Environment 770, 144720 (2021).</common:shortDescription>
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="zh">Liu, X., Cai, Z. &amp; Yuan, Z. Environmental burdens of small-scale intensive pig production in China. Science of The Total Environment 770, 144720 (2021).</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToDataSource>
		</dataSourcesTreatmentAndRepresentativeness>
		<completeness/>
		<validation>
			<review type="Dependent internal review">
				<common:reviewDetails xml:lang="en">Inventory: The internal review was done by several iteration steps concerning raw data validation, raw data documentation, representativity, completeness and consistency of modelling with regard to ISO 14040 and 14044.; Documentation: The review of the documentation was performed by Ecobilan and is in compliance with ISO 14040 and 14044. The data set documentation is correct in view of the appropriateness of the information provided. It includes all relevant information in view of data quality and scope of application of the respective LCI result.</common:reviewDetails>
				<common:referenceToNameOfReviewerAndInstitution refObjectId="f4b4c314-8c4c-4c83-968f-5b3c7724f6a8" type="contact data set" uri="../contacts/f4b4c314-8c4c-4c83-968f-5b3c7724f6a8.xml">
					<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">Tiangong LCI Data Working Group</common:shortDescription>
				</common:referenceToNameOfReviewerAndInstitution>
			</review>
		</validation>
	</modellingAndValidation>
	<administrativeInformation>
		<dataGenerator>
			<common:referenceToPersonOrEntityGeneratingTheDataSet type="contact data set" refObjectId="f3bc507b-0b5e-46f7-a7a3-44799e722d1c" uri="../contacts/f3bc507b-0b5e-46f7-a7a3-44799e722d1c.xml" version="01.00.000">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">Rui Yang, 1632707028@qq.com</common:shortDescription>
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="zh">杨瑞, 1632707028@qq.com</common:shortDescription>
			</common:referenceToPersonOrEntityGeneratingTheDataSet>
			<other xml:lang="en">1632707028@qq.com</other>
			<other xml:lang="zh">1632707028@qq.com</other>
		</dataGenerator>
		<dataEntryBy>
			<common:timeStamp>2023-10-26T11:39:07+08:00</common:timeStamp>
		</dataEntryBy>
		<publicationAndOwnership>
			<common:dateOfLastRevision>2023-10-26T11:39:07+08:00</common:dateOfLastRevision>
			<common:dataSetVersion>01.00.000</common:dataSetVersion>
			<common:copyright>false</common:copyright>
		</publicationAndOwnership>
	</administrativeInformation>
	<exchanges/>
</processDataSet>
