<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet version="1.0" href="../../stylesheets/process2html.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<processDataSet xmlns:common="http://lca.jrc.it/ILCD/Common" xmlns="http://lca.jrc.it/ILCD/Process" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" version="1.1" locations="../ILCDLocations.xml" xsi:schemaLocation="http://lca.jrc.it/ILCD/Process ../../schemas/ILCD_ProcessDataSet.xsd">
	<processInformation>
		<dataSetInformation>
			<common:UUID>987bf91c-634a-4c64-92fb-f83919053d26</common:UUID>
			<name>
				<baseName xml:lang="en">Penaeus white shrimp culture ; Penaeus white shrimp adult shrimp ; Factory farming</baseName>
				<baseName xml:lang="zh">南美白对虾养殖;南美白对虾成虾;工厂化养殖</baseName>
			</name>
			<classificationInformation>
				<common:classification>
					<common:class level="0">Unit processes</common:class>
					<common:class level="1">Materials production</common:class>
					<common:class level="2">Food and renewable raw materials</common:class>
				</common:classification>
			</classificationInformation>
			<common:generalComment xml:lang="en">The research scope of this paper includes five stages: infrastructure construction of aquaculture farms, transportation of shrimp seedlings, shrimp breeding, shrimp transportation to market, and infrastructure disposal. Among them, feed production for shrimp breeding stage is a link, is the use of fish meal, soybeans, peanuts, fish oil, flour, minerals and adhesives production of compound feed</common:generalComment>
			<common:generalComment xml:lang="zh">本文研究范围包括从养殖场基础设施建设、虾苗运输、成虾养殖、成虾运往市场、基础设施废弃处置五个阶段。其中饲料生产为成虾养殖阶段是一个环节，是利用鱼粉、大豆、花生、鱼油、面粉、矿物质与粘合剂等生产的配合饲料</common:generalComment>
		</dataSetInformation>
		<quantitativeReference type="Reference flow(s)">
			<functionalUnitOrOther xml:lang="en">1 ton of white shrimp</functionalUnitOrOther>
			<referenceToReferenceFlow>23</referenceToReferenceFlow>
		</quantitativeReference>
		<time>
			<common:referenceYear>2019</common:referenceYear>
			<common:dataSetValidUntil>2021</common:dataSetValidUntil>
			<common:timeRepresentativenessDescription xml:lang="en">The sampling time was not specified in the literature. The researcher conducted a survey at the fixed observation point of Taoluo Town, Rizhao City, Shandong Province in June and November 2019. </common:timeRepresentativenessDescription>
			<common:timeRepresentativenessDescription xml:lang="zh">文献未具体说明采样时间，研究者于 2019 年 6 月份、11 月份在山东省日照市涛雒镇固定观察点调研</common:timeRepresentativenessDescription>
		</time>
		<geography>
			<locationOfOperationSupplyOrProduction location="RZ-SD-CN">
				<descriptionOfRestrictions xml:lang="en">The study is located in Tao Luo Town, Rizhao City, Shandong Province.</descriptionOfRestrictions>
				<descriptionOfRestrictions xml:lang="zh">山东省日照市涛雒镇</descriptionOfRestrictions>
			</locationOfOperationSupplyOrProduction>
		</geography>
		<technology>
			<technologyDescriptionAndIncludedProcesses xml:lang="en">Technology of factory culture of Penaeus alba. Factory farming is divided into three types: factory stillwater farming, factory running water farming and factory circulating water farming. The shrimp farmers in Rizhao City where this research institute is located mostly adopt factory running water farming. In this farming mode, farmers have a number of breeding sheds with brick-concrete structure, good light transmission and heat preservation. Each breeding shed will have a number of breeding ponds, the shape is mostly regular quadrilateral, the scale is mostly 4m(length)*4m (width), 5m(length)*5m (width), 6m(length)*6m (width), and the depth of the pool is mostly between 1m and 1.3m. The bottom of the pool is in the shape of a pot to drain water to the middle [110], and the center of the bottom of the pool is set with a Φ110 mm polyvinyl riser for drainage. Drainage is generally divided into three stages, the early displacement is small, about 8-10cm per day, the duration is mostly 25-35 days; In the middle period, the displacement is large, and the drainage is about 25-40cm per day, and the duration is mostly 50-60 days. The latter stage displaces the most, draining about 60-70cm per day for a duration of 30-45 days. The growth cycle of the South American white shrimp in this region is mostly 110-130 days, and the majority of the shrimp are raised 2 times a year, and the survival rate is about 35%-55%. Regarding the input of feed, factory farming generally only throws compound feed. In addition, every year, farmers have to clean the pond disinfection, the frequency is twice a year.</technologyDescriptionAndIncludedProcesses>
			<technologyDescriptionAndIncludedProcesses xml:lang="zh">南美白对虾工厂化养殖技术。工厂化养殖分为工厂化静水式养殖、工厂化流水式养殖、工厂化循环水式养殖三中，本研究所在日照市的对 虾养殖户多采用工厂化流水式养殖模式。该养殖模式下的养殖户建有多个养殖棚，结构为砖混结构，透光性以及保温性良好。每个养殖棚内会建有多个养殖池，形 状多为正四边形，规模多为 4m(长)*4m（宽）、5m(长)*5m（宽）、6m(长)*6m（宽）， 池深大多在 1m-1.3m 之间。池底呈锅底状向中间排水[110]，池底中央设置Φ110 mm 聚 乙烯立管进行排水。排水一般分 3 个阶段，前期排水量较小，每天约排水 8-10cm， 持续时间多为 25—35 天；中期排水量较大，每天排水约 25-40cm，持续时间多为 50-60 天；后期排水量最大，每天排水约 60-70cm,持续时间为 30-45 天。该地区 的南美白对虾生长周期多为 110-130 天，每年养殖 2 造的居多，成活率大概在 35%-55%之间。关于饲料的投入，工厂化养殖一般只投配合饲料。另外，每年养殖 户都要进行清池消毒，频率一年两次。</technologyDescriptionAndIncludedProcesses>
			<technologicalApplicability xml:lang="en">Penaeus vannamei, commonly known as white shrimp, is cultured in this process for the purpose of seafood production. The cultivated shrimp are intended for consumption and distributed to various markets after reaching maturity. This factory farming method is designed for high-volume, controlled production of shrimp to meet consumer demand in food industries. The shrimps are grown using a compound feed that includes ingredients such as fish meal, soybeans, peanuts, fish oil, flour, minerals, and adhesives.</technologicalApplicability>
			<technologicalApplicability xml:lang="zh">本工艺流程中培养的南美白对虾（Penaeus vannamei），通常被用于海产品生产，培育至成年后的虾类用于食用并分发至各个市场。这种工厂化养殖方法旨在为满足食品产业中的消费需求而设计，能进行高容量、控制性的白虾生产。所使用的配合饲料包括鱼粉、大豆、花生、鱼油、面粉、矿物质和粘合剂等成分。</technologicalApplicability>
			<referenceToTechnologyFlowDiagrammOrPicture type="source data set" refObjectId="f238fe88-5ec9-d194-b3e3-3f3073b6abb0" uri="../sources/f238fe88-5ec9-d194-b3e3-3f3073b6abb0.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">Xcnxb54RVo70abxrp1bcBbvDnVf.png</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToTechnologyFlowDiagrammOrPicture>
		</technology>
		<mathematicalRelations>
			<modelDescription xml:lang="en">In this study, the equivalent factor method is used for the characteristics. According to the impact potential degree of different substances on the same environmental impact type, one of them is used as the reference substance, and the impact potential value is 1. The equivalent factor is the ratio of the impact potential of other substances of the same quality to the impact potential value of the reference substance</modelDescription>
			<modelDescription xml:lang="zh">本研究采用当量因子法进行特征化所，根据不同物质对同一种环境影响类型的影响潜在 程度，将其中一种物质作为基准物质，影响潜值 1，当量因子为相同质量的其他物质影响潜力与该基准物质影响潜值的比值</modelDescription>
		</mathematicalRelations>
	</processInformation>
	<modellingAndValidation>
		<LCIMethodAndAllocation>
			<typeOfDataSet>Unit process, black box</typeOfDataSet>
			<LCIMethodPrinciple>Attributional</LCIMethodPrinciple>
			<deviationsFromLCIMethodPrinciple xml:lang="en">None</deviationsFromLCIMethodPrinciple>
			<deviationsFromLCIMethodPrinciple xml:lang="zh">无</deviationsFromLCIMethodPrinciple>
			<LCIMethodApproach>Allocation</LCIMethodApproach>
			<deviationsFromLCIMethodApproaches xml:lang="en">The research done in this paper is a typical case study rather than a statistical study: firstly, taking a Penaeus vannamei farm in Rizhao City as an example, using the life cycle assessment method and SimaPro9.0 software, the carbon emissions of Penaeus vannamei farming industry chain at each stage are quantified and analyzed. Then the same method was used to calculate the carbon emissions of the shrimp industry chain of 13 farms and take the mean value for analysis</deviationsFromLCIMethodApproaches>
			<deviationsFromLCIMethodApproaches xml:lang="zh">本文所做研究为典型案例研究而非统计学研究：先以日照市的一家南美白对虾养殖场为例， 运用生命周期评价方法，使用 SimaPro9.0 软件，对南美白对虾养殖产业链各阶段 的碳排放量进行量化和分析。而后运用同样的方法计算出 13 家养殖场对虾产业链 的碳排放量并取均值进行分析</deviationsFromLCIMethodApproaches>
			<deviationsFromModellingConstants xml:lang="en">None</deviationsFromModellingConstants>
			<deviationsFromModellingConstants xml:lang="zh">无</deviationsFromModellingConstants>
		</LCIMethodAndAllocation>
		<dataSourcesTreatmentAndRepresentativeness>
			<deviationsFromCutOffAndCompletenessPrinciples xml:lang="en">None</deviationsFromCutOffAndCompletenessPrinciples>
			<deviationsFromCutOffAndCompletenessPrinciples xml:lang="zh">无</deviationsFromCutOffAndCompletenessPrinciples>
			<dataSelectionAndCombinationPrinciples xml:lang="en">The data come from field investigation of 13 farms, and the data are real, effective and reliable. The calculated carbon emissions of the 13 cases were analyzed by taking the mean value. Secondly, part of the data is derived from the SimaPro database, which contains the latest science-based multiple life cycle impact assessment methods and databases</dataSelectionAndCombinationPrinciples>
			<dataSelectionAndCombinationPrinciples xml:lang="zh">数据来自实地调研13家养殖场，数据真实、有效、 可靠。分别对13个案例计算后的碳排放量取均值进行分析。其次，部分数据源自SimaPro数据库，包含了最新 的基于科学的多种生命周期影响评价方法和数据库</dataSelectionAndCombinationPrinciples>
			<deviationsFromSelectionAndCombinationPrinciples xml:lang="en">None</deviationsFromSelectionAndCombinationPrinciples>
			<deviationsFromSelectionAndCombinationPrinciples xml:lang="zh">无</deviationsFromSelectionAndCombinationPrinciples>
			<dataTreatmentAndExtrapolationsPrinciples xml:lang="en">Literature researchers used SimaPro9.0 software to quantify the carbon emissions at each stage of the shrimp breeding industry chain, and on this basis, analyzed the carbon emissions of the shrimp industry chain of 13 farms and took the mean value. Among them, the information of the infrastructure construction stage of the breeding farm mainly includes the type, quantity and service life of construction materials, etc. The information of shrimp fry transportation stage mainly includes the source and destination of shrimp fry transportation, transportation mode, transportation weight, transportation distance, energy consumption during transportation, etc. The information of adult shrimp breeding stage mainly includes the input quantity of water, electricity, feed and other energy substances, as well as the quantity of wastewater discharged in the breeding process and the quality inspection of wastewater, etc. The information from the transportation of adult shrimp to the market stage mainly includes the transportation mode, transportation weight, transportation distance, transportation destination and energy consumption during transportation. The information in the stage of infrastructure waste disposal mainly includes the transportation destination, transportation mode, transportation weight, transportation distance, and energy consumption generated by the transportation process of waste.The basic assumptions of the literature in LCA analysis are as follows: the transportation mode of shrimp fry is air transportation; Fuel consumption is calculated according to gasoline for land transport and jet fuel for air transport; The electric energy consumed in the life cycle comes from the residential power output of the state grid. Aquaculture water is groundwater by default.</dataTreatmentAndExtrapolationsPrinciples>
			<dataTreatmentAndExtrapolationsPrinciples xml:lang="zh">文献研究者使用 SimaPro9.0 软件，对南美白对虾养殖产业链各阶段的碳排放量进行量化，在此基础上对13 家养殖场对虾产业链的碳排放量并取均值进行分析。其中， 养殖场基础设施建设阶段的信息主要有建筑材料的投入种类、数量以及使用年限 等；虾苗运输阶段的信息主要有虾苗的运输源地与目的地、运输方式、运输重量、 运输距离、运输过程的能源消耗等；成虾养殖阶段的信息主要有水、电、饲料等 能源物质的投入数量以及养殖过程的废水排放数量、废水质量检测情况等；成虾 运输至市场阶段的信息主要有成虾出塘后的运输方式、运输重量、运输距离、运 输目的地以及运输过程产生的能源消耗情况等；基础设施废弃处置阶段的信息主要有废弃物的运输目的地、运输方式、运输重量、运输距离、运输过程所产生的 能源消耗等。文献在进行 LCA 分析时基本假设如下：虾苗运输方式为空运；燃油的消耗陆运按 汽油计算，空运按航空燃油计算；生命周期内所消耗的电能均来自国家电网的居 民用电输出；养殖水默认为地下水。</dataTreatmentAndExtrapolationsPrinciples>
			<deviationsFromTreatmentAndExtrapolationPrinciples xml:lang="en">None</deviationsFromTreatmentAndExtrapolationPrinciples>
			<deviationsFromTreatmentAndExtrapolationPrinciples xml:lang="zh">无</deviationsFromTreatmentAndExtrapolationPrinciples>
			<referenceToDataSource type="source data set" refObjectId="32d95ef4-873a-481a-91ae-46a59d7a1112" uri="../sources/32d95ef4-873a-481a-91ae-46a59d7a1112.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">马一鸣. 基于生命周期评价方法的南美白对虾养殖产业链碳排放研究. (上海海洋大学, 2021).</common:shortDescription>
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="zh">马一鸣. 基于生命周期评价方法的南美白对虾养殖产业链碳排放研究. (上海海洋大学, 2021).</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToDataSource>
			<samplingProcedure xml:lang="en">There are two main sources of data in this paper. There are two main sources of data in this paper. First, it comes from field research. In June and November 2019, it was conducted at the fixed observation point in Taoluo Town, Rizhao City, Shandong Province. Most of the input and output data of the breeding industry came from the questionnaire survey of the heads of breeding plants and feed processing plants, and the water quality monitoring data were taken from the fixed monitoring point of the local Institute of Marine and Fishery. The data on the transportation of adult shrimp to the market were obtained from the survey of Rizhao aquatic product wholesale market and the head of the breeding farm. The second is from the database of life cycle assessment software Simapro. The first is from field research, which was conducted at fixed observation points in Taoluo Town, Rizhao City, Shandong Province in June and November 2019. Most of the input and output data of the breeding industry come from the questionnaire survey of the heads of breeding plants and feed processing plants. The water quality monitoring data were obtained from the fixed monitoring points of the local Marine and fishery Research Institute, and the data of the transportation of adult shrimp to the market were obtained from the survey of the directors of the fishery products wholesale market and aquaculture farms in Rizhao City. The second is the database derived from the life cycle assessment software Simapro</samplingProcedure>
			<samplingProcedure xml:lang="zh"> 本文数据主要有两大来源。一是来源于实地调研，2019 年 6 月份、11 月份在山东省日照市涛雒镇固定观察点调研，养殖产业的投入产出数据绝大部分来源于对养殖厂以及饲料加工厂负责人的问卷调查，水质监测数据则取自于当地海洋与渔业研究所的固定监测点，成虾运输至市场数据取自于日照市水产品批发市场以及养殖场负责人的调研。二是来源于生命周期评价软件 Simapro 的数据库</samplingProcedure>
			<useAdviceForDataSet xml:lang="en">When using this data set for Life Cycle Assessment, it is important to include all stages mentioned: infrastructure for farm construction, shrimp seedling transport, shrimp breeding, market transportation, and infrastructure disposal. Special attention should be given to the representative nature of the inputs and outputs from the aquaculture and feed processing factories, as well as the local water quality monitoring data. Ensure that the time and location of data collection are relevant for the assessed system and account for seasonal differences by considering the data from June and November 2019. If modeling transport to the market, use the provided transportation data from Rizhao City’s seafood wholesale market and aquaculture farm surveys.</useAdviceForDataSet>
			<useAdviceForDataSet xml:lang="zh">在使用本数据集进行生命周期评估时，应包括提及的所有阶段：养殖场基础设施建设、虾苗运输、虾养殖、市场运输及基础设施废弃处置。应特别注意来自养殖厂和饲料加工厂的输入输出数据的代表性，以及当地水质监测数据。确保数据收集的时间和地点与评估的系统相关，并通过考虑2019年6月和11月的数据来考虑季节差异。如果建模到市场的运输，使用提供的来自日照市水产品批发市场和养殖场调研的运输数据。</useAdviceForDataSet>
		</dataSourcesTreatmentAndRepresentativeness>
		<completeness>
			<common:other xml:lang="en">The input data included five stages of farm infrastructure construction, shrimp fry transportation, adult shrimp cultivation, adult shrimp transportation to market, and infrastructure waste disposal in the South American white shrimp farming industry chain. Construction of shrimp hatchery, infrastructure construction of aquaculture farms, shrimp seedling cultivation process, shrimp seedling transportation, shrimp cultivation, shrimp transportation to the market, shrimp shell recovery and infrastructure waste disposal of aquaculture plants, etc. However, since the shrimp seedling cultivation process is mostly located in Hainan Province, our research group has little contact with these shrimp seedling cultivation farms, and there is no relevant real and reliable data source. Therefore, the carbon emissions generated by the construction of shrimp hatchery and shrimp seedling cultivation process are not within the scope of this study; At the same time, the recovery rate of shrimp shell in our country is not high enough, the recovery situation of shrimp shell is not the same all over the country, and it is difficult to obtain first-hand data. At present, there are no cases and data of the recovery stage of shrimp shell for reference, so the carbon emissions of the recovery process of shrimp shell are not included in the calculation of carbon emissions of the South American white shrimp industry chain. In addition, after the abandonment of the farm, its managers generally choose to sell the recyclable waste to the waste recycling center, and the non-recyclable waste is directly abandoned. We do not know how the waste recycling center chooses to deal with these wastes, and the actual situation is difficult to grasp. Therefore, in this stage, the carbon emissions generated by the transportation of wastes from the site of the factory to the waste recycling center are only considered in the quantification of carbon emissions.</common:other>
			<common:other xml:lang="zh">输入数据包括南美白对虾养殖产业链的养殖场基础设施建设、虾苗运输、成虾养殖、成虾运往市场以及基础设施废弃处置五个阶段。虾苗孵化场的建设、养殖场基础设施建设、虾苗培 育过程、虾苗运输、成虾养殖、成虾运输至市场、虾壳的回收以及养殖厂基础设 施废弃处置等，但由于虾苗培育的过程大多设在我国海南省，该课题组与这些虾苗培育场家联系较少，无相关真实可靠的数据来源，故虾苗孵化场建设以及虾苗培 育过程所产生的的碳排放不在此次研究的范围内；同时，我国的虾壳回收率并不 够高，虾壳的回收情况全国各地不尽相同，一手数据较难获取，目前尚无虾壳回收阶段的案例及数据可供参考，故虾壳回收过程的碳排放量也不在此次南美白对虾产业链碳排放的计算内；另外，养殖场废弃后，其管理者一般选择将可回收废 弃物卖给废品回收中心，不可回收物直接遗弃。至于废品回收中心选择怎么处理 这些废弃物我们不得而知，实际情况很难掌握，故该阶段在进行碳排放量化时仅 考虑了废弃物从工厂所在地到废品回收中心运输过程所产生的碳排放。</common:other>
		</completeness>
		<validation>
			<review type="Dependent internal review">
				<common:reviewDetails xml:lang="en">Inventory: The internal review was done by several iteration steps concerning raw data validation, raw data documentation, representativity, completeness and consistency of modelling with regard to ISO 14040 and 14044.</common:reviewDetails>
				<common:reviewDetails xml:lang="zh">清单： 内部审查通过几个迭代步骤完成，涉及原始数据验证、原始数据记录、代表性、完整性、与 ISO 14040 和 14044 有关的建模的一致性。</common:reviewDetails>
				<common:referenceToNameOfReviewerAndInstitution refObjectId="f4b4c314-8c4c-4c83-968f-5b3c7724f6a8" type="contact data set" uri="../contacts/f4b4c314-8c4c-4c83-968f-5b3c7724f6a8.xml">
					<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">Tiangong LCI Data Working Group</common:shortDescription>
					<common:shortDescription xml:lang="zh">天工LCI数据工作小组</common:shortDescription>
				</common:referenceToNameOfReviewerAndInstitution>
			</review>
		</validation>
	</modellingAndValidation>
	<administrativeInformation>
		<dataGenerator>
			<common:referenceToPersonOrEntityGeneratingTheDataSet type="contact data set" refObjectId="abfa6bbd-f608-4d9b-9c7c-6ee2fe42e70e" uri="../contacts/abfa6bbd-f608-4d9b-9c7c-6ee2fe42e70e.xml" version="01.00.000">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">Kangni Wu, wukangni@xmu.stu.edu.cn</common:shortDescription>
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="zh">吴康妮, wukangni@xmu.stu.edu.cn</common:shortDescription>
			</common:referenceToPersonOrEntityGeneratingTheDataSet>
			<common:other xml:lang="en">wukangni@xmu.stu.edu.cn</common:other>
			<common:other xml:lang="zh">wukangni@xmu.stu.edu.cn</common:other>
		</dataGenerator>
		<dataEntryBy>
			<common:timeStamp>2024-01-26T10:16:09+08:00</common:timeStamp>
		</dataEntryBy>
		<publicationAndOwnership>
			<common:dateOfLastRevision>2024-04-15T04:07:18.735189+08:00</common:dateOfLastRevision>
			<common:dataSetVersion>01.00.000</common:dataSetVersion>
			<common:permanentDataSetURI>https://lcadata.tiangong.world/showProcess.xhtml?uuid=987bf91c-634a-4c64-92fb-f83919053d26&amp;amp;version=01.00.000&amp;amp;stock=TianGong</common:permanentDataSetURI>
			<common:referenceToOwnershipOfDataSet refObjectId="f4b4c314-8c4c-4c83-968f-5b3c7724f6a8" type="contact data set" uri="../contacts/f4b4c314-8c4c-4c83-968f-5b3c7724f6a8.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">Tiangong LCI Data Working Group</common:shortDescription>
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="zh">天工LCI数据工作小组</common:shortDescription>
			</common:referenceToOwnershipOfDataSet>
			<common:copyright>false</common:copyright>
			<common:licenseType>Free of charge for all users and uses</common:licenseType>
		</publicationAndOwnership>
	</administrativeInformation>
	<exchanges>
		<exchange dataSetInternalID="0">
			<referenceToFlowDataSet type="flow data set" refObjectId="ec23da1b-e5fa-4f01-bd2c-3233fece2175" uri="../flows/ec23da1b-e5fa-4f01-bd2c-3233fece2175.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">cement, unspecified</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToFlowDataSet>
			<exchangeDirection>Input</exchangeDirection>
			<meanAmount>42.354</meanAmount>
			<resultingAmount>42.354</resultingAmount>
			<dataDerivationTypeStatus>Measured</dataDerivationTypeStatus>
		</exchange>
		<exchange dataSetInternalID="1">
			<referenceToFlowDataSet type="flow data set" refObjectId="08a91e70-3ddc-11dd-959a-0050c2490048" uri="../flows/08a91e70-3ddc-11dd-959a-0050c2490048.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">iron</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToFlowDataSet>
			<exchangeDirection>Input</exchangeDirection>
			<meanAmount>53.0</meanAmount>
			<resultingAmount>53.0</resultingAmount>
			<dataDerivationTypeStatus>Measured</dataDerivationTypeStatus>
			<generalComment xml:lang="en">It belongs to the infrastructure construction stage and has a service life of 20 years. This data is the input data equivalent to one breeding cycle.</generalComment>
			<generalComment xml:lang="zh">属于基础设施建设阶段,使用年限20年，该数据为折合一个养殖周期的投入数据</generalComment>
		</exchange>
		<exchange dataSetInternalID="2">
			<referenceToFlowDataSet type="flow data set" refObjectId="4f19f116-7b3b-11dd-ad8b-0800200c9a66" uri="../flows/4f19f116-7b3b-11dd-ad8b-0800200c9a66.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">polyethylene low density granulate (PE-LD)</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToFlowDataSet>
			<exchangeDirection>Input</exchangeDirection>
			<meanAmount>14.6</meanAmount>
			<resultingAmount>14.6</resultingAmount>
			<dataDerivationTypeStatus>Measured</dataDerivationTypeStatus>
			<generalComment xml:lang="en">It belongs to the infrastructure construction stage and has a service life of 15 years. This data is the input data equivalent to one breeding cycle.</generalComment>
			<generalComment xml:lang="zh">属于基础设施建设阶段,使用年限15年，该数据为折合一个养殖周期的投入数据</generalComment>
		</exchange>
		<exchange dataSetInternalID="3">
			<referenceToFlowDataSet type="flow data set" refObjectId="4f1a3f30-7b3b-11dd-ad8b-0800200c9a66" uri="../flows/4f1a3f30-7b3b-11dd-ad8b-0800200c9a66.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">transport in t*km</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToFlowDataSet>
			<exchangeDirection>Input</exchangeDirection>
			<meanAmount>207.064</meanAmount>
			<resultingAmount>207.064</resultingAmount>
			<dataDerivationTypeStatus>Measured</dataDerivationTypeStatus>
			<generalComment xml:lang="en">Transport of shrimp seedlings by air. The original data is mass * distance = (0.09412t * 2200km)</generalComment>
			<generalComment xml:lang="zh">虾苗运输，方式：空运。原文数据为质量*距离=（0.09412t*2200km）</generalComment>
		</exchange>
		<exchange dataSetInternalID="4">
			<referenceToFlowDataSet type="flow data set" refObjectId="419682fe-60fb-4b43-be89-bf2824b51104" uri="../flows/419682fe-60fb-4b43-be89-bf2824b51104.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">water</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToFlowDataSet>
			<exchangeDirection>Input</exchangeDirection>
			<meanAmount>8470590.0</meanAmount>
			<resultingAmount>8470590.0</resultingAmount>
			<dataDerivationTypeStatus>Measured</dataDerivationTypeStatus>
			<generalComment xml:lang="en">Belongs to the adult shrimp breeding stage</generalComment>
			<generalComment xml:lang="zh">属于成虾养殖阶段</generalComment>
		</exchange>
		<exchange dataSetInternalID="5">
			<referenceToFlowDataSet type="flow data set" refObjectId="890a70b7-b677-4e2a-8a1b-7d017e0a10ae" uri="../flows/890a70b7-b677-4e2a-8a1b-7d017e0a10ae.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">Electricity</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToFlowDataSet>
			<exchangeDirection>Input</exchangeDirection>
			<meanAmount>60504.228</meanAmount>
			<resultingAmount>60504.228</resultingAmount>
			<dataDerivationTypeStatus>Measured</dataDerivationTypeStatus>
			<generalComment xml:lang="en">Belongs to the adult shrimp breeding stage</generalComment>
			<generalComment xml:lang="zh">属于成虾养殖阶段</generalComment>
		</exchange>
		<exchange dataSetInternalID="6">
			<referenceToFlowDataSet type="flow data set" refObjectId="55a4c166-2eb6-43a3-9a13-2e4f2c4fee60" uri="../flows/55a4c166-2eb6-43a3-9a13-2e4f2c4fee60.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">Diesel</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToFlowDataSet>
			<exchangeDirection>Input</exchangeDirection>
			<meanAmount>9.76</meanAmount>
			<resultingAmount>9.76</resultingAmount>
			<dataDerivationTypeStatus>Measured</dataDerivationTypeStatus>
			<generalComment xml:lang="en">Belongs to the adult shrimp breeding stage</generalComment>
			<generalComment xml:lang="zh">属于成虾养殖阶段</generalComment>
		</exchange>
		<exchange dataSetInternalID="7">
			<referenceToFlowDataSet type="flow data set" refObjectId="964635dd-359e-4d1c-afe1-0a74d1de3533" uri="../flows/964635dd-359e-4d1c-afe1-0a74d1de3533.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">fish meal</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToFlowDataSet>
			<exchangeDirection>Input</exchangeDirection>
			<meanAmount>411.765</meanAmount>
			<resultingAmount>411.765</resultingAmount>
			<dataDerivationTypeStatus>Measured</dataDerivationTypeStatus>
		</exchange>
		<exchange dataSetInternalID="8">
			<referenceToFlowDataSet type="flow data set" refObjectId="801e05b6-845d-4d04-80e4-9899dd329748" uri="../flows/801e05b6-845d-4d04-80e4-9899dd329748.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">Soybean</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToFlowDataSet>
			<exchangeDirection>Input</exchangeDirection>
			<meanAmount>288.2355</meanAmount>
			<resultingAmount>288.2355</resultingAmount>
			<dataDerivationTypeStatus>Measured</dataDerivationTypeStatus>
		</exchange>
		<exchange dataSetInternalID="9">
			<referenceToFlowDataSet type="flow data set" refObjectId="68a36c87-ffa2-42ad-9a5f-83fb16569829" uri="../flows/68a36c87-ffa2-42ad-9a5f-83fb16569829.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">Peanut</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToFlowDataSet>
			<exchangeDirection>Input</exchangeDirection>
			<meanAmount>222.3531</meanAmount>
			<resultingAmount>222.3531</resultingAmount>
			<dataDerivationTypeStatus>Measured</dataDerivationTypeStatus>
		</exchange>
		<exchange dataSetInternalID="10">
			<referenceToFlowDataSet type="flow data set" refObjectId="dacba994-e061-44ed-940e-61f7820422c6" uri="../flows/dacba994-e061-44ed-940e-61f7820422c6.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">Fish Oil</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToFlowDataSet>
			<exchangeDirection>Input</exchangeDirection>
			<meanAmount>24.7059</meanAmount>
			<resultingAmount>24.7059</resultingAmount>
			<dataDerivationTypeStatus>Measured</dataDerivationTypeStatus>
		</exchange>
		<exchange dataSetInternalID="11">
			<referenceToFlowDataSet type="flow data set" refObjectId="67b80ae5-687f-418a-84ba-f06b01a6139b" uri="../flows/67b80ae5-687f-418a-84ba-f06b01a6139b.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">Flour</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToFlowDataSet>
			<exchangeDirection>Input</exchangeDirection>
			<meanAmount>378.8238</meanAmount>
			<resultingAmount>378.8238</resultingAmount>
			<dataDerivationTypeStatus>Measured</dataDerivationTypeStatus>
		</exchange>
		<exchange dataSetInternalID="12">
			<referenceToFlowDataSet type="flow data set" refObjectId="dab6715a-38e0-47fd-b04d-5c3b17bd2922" uri="../flows/dab6715a-38e0-47fd-b04d-5c3b17bd2922.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">Mineral</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToFlowDataSet>
			<exchangeDirection>Input</exchangeDirection>
			<meanAmount>49.4118</meanAmount>
			<resultingAmount>49.4118</resultingAmount>
			<dataDerivationTypeStatus>Measured</dataDerivationTypeStatus>
		</exchange>
		<exchange dataSetInternalID="13">
			<referenceToFlowDataSet type="flow data set" refObjectId="279b6b7f-519f-4f32-aab0-99bb61cb90dc" uri="../flows/279b6b7f-519f-4f32-aab0-99bb61cb90dc.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">Adhesives</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToFlowDataSet>
			<exchangeDirection>Input</exchangeDirection>
			<meanAmount>5.7647</meanAmount>
			<resultingAmount>5.7647</resultingAmount>
			<dataDerivationTypeStatus>Measured</dataDerivationTypeStatus>
		</exchange>
		<exchange dataSetInternalID="14">
			<referenceToFlowDataSet type="flow data set" refObjectId="c566e036-2e0c-4f44-b4c2-08dc00af93c2" uri="../flows/c566e036-2e0c-4f44-b4c2-08dc00af93c2.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">Hydrogen peroxide</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToFlowDataSet>
			<exchangeDirection>Input</exchangeDirection>
			<meanAmount>141.18</meanAmount>
			<resultingAmount>141.18</resultingAmount>
			<dataDerivationTypeStatus>Measured</dataDerivationTypeStatus>
		</exchange>
		<exchange dataSetInternalID="15">
			<referenceToFlowDataSet type="flow data set" refObjectId="9302a882-11b1-48e0-aaa1-ea25c7d89101" uri="../flows/9302a882-11b1-48e0-aaa1-ea25c7d89101.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">Fertilizer paste for aquaculture</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToFlowDataSet>
			<exchangeDirection>Input</exchangeDirection>
			<meanAmount>117.65</meanAmount>
			<resultingAmount>117.65</resultingAmount>
			<dataDerivationTypeStatus>Measured</dataDerivationTypeStatus>
		</exchange>
		<exchange dataSetInternalID="16">
			<referenceToFlowDataSet type="flow data set" refObjectId="3a9517b4-22a2-4ed7-aaed-2316e98e8fcb" uri="../flows/3a9517b4-22a2-4ed7-aaed-2316e98e8fcb.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">Multivitamins</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToFlowDataSet>
			<exchangeDirection>Input</exchangeDirection>
			<meanAmount>0.94</meanAmount>
			<resultingAmount>0.94</resultingAmount>
			<dataDerivationTypeStatus>Measured</dataDerivationTypeStatus>
		</exchange>
		<exchange dataSetInternalID="17">
			<referenceToFlowDataSet type="flow data set" refObjectId="f919d36c-31a2-40a0-861e-b65d42a13141" uri="../flows/f919d36c-31a2-40a0-861e-b65d42a13141.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">Immunopolysaccharide</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToFlowDataSet>
			<exchangeDirection>Input</exchangeDirection>
			<meanAmount>2.35</meanAmount>
			<resultingAmount>2.35</resultingAmount>
			<dataDerivationTypeStatus>Measured</dataDerivationTypeStatus>
		</exchange>
		<exchange dataSetInternalID="18">
			<referenceToFlowDataSet type="flow data set" refObjectId="4f1a3f41-7b3b-11dd-ad8b-0800200c9a66" uri="../flows/4f1a3f41-7b3b-11dd-ad8b-0800200c9a66.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">waste water - untreated</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToFlowDataSet>
			<exchangeDirection>Output</exchangeDirection>
			<meanAmount>8470590.0</meanAmount>
			<resultingAmount>8470590.0</resultingAmount>
			<dataDerivationTypeStatus>Measured</dataDerivationTypeStatus>
		</exchange>
		<exchange dataSetInternalID="19">
			<referenceToFlowDataSet type="flow data set" refObjectId="08a91e70-3ddc-11dd-9783-0050c2490048" uri="../flows/08a91e70-3ddc-11dd-9783-0050c2490048.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">phosphate</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToFlowDataSet>
			<exchangeDirection>Output</exchangeDirection>
			<meanAmount>0.091788</meanAmount>
			<resultingAmount>0.091788</resultingAmount>
			<dataDerivationTypeStatus>Measured</dataDerivationTypeStatus>
		</exchange>
		<exchange dataSetInternalID="20">
			<referenceToFlowDataSet type="flow data set" refObjectId="08a91e70-3ddc-11dd-96b0-0050c2490048" uri="../flows/08a91e70-3ddc-11dd-96b0-0050c2490048.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">ammonia</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToFlowDataSet>
			<exchangeDirection>Output</exchangeDirection>
			<meanAmount>0.17099</meanAmount>
			<resultingAmount>0.17099</resultingAmount>
			<dataDerivationTypeStatus>Measured</dataDerivationTypeStatus>
		</exchange>
		<exchange dataSetInternalID="21">
			<referenceToFlowDataSet type="flow data set" refObjectId="08a91e70-3ddc-11dd-96e2-0050c2490048" uri="../flows/08a91e70-3ddc-11dd-96e2-0050c2490048.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">nitrite</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToFlowDataSet>
			<exchangeDirection>Output</exchangeDirection>
			<meanAmount>0.05497</meanAmount>
			<resultingAmount>0.05497</resultingAmount>
			<dataDerivationTypeStatus>Measured</dataDerivationTypeStatus>
		</exchange>
		<exchange dataSetInternalID="22">
			<referenceToFlowDataSet type="flow data set" refObjectId="e57fc631-2c77-457a-aa30-be79e357792b" uri="../flows/e57fc631-2c77-457a-aa30-be79e357792b.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">Chemical Oxygen Demand (COD)</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToFlowDataSet>
			<exchangeDirection>Output</exchangeDirection>
			<meanAmount>13.21783</meanAmount>
			<resultingAmount>13.21783</resultingAmount>
			<dataDerivationTypeStatus>Measured</dataDerivationTypeStatus>
		</exchange>
		<exchange dataSetInternalID="23">
			<referenceToFlowDataSet type="flow data set" refObjectId="585733ef-4208-4edb-ab68-51a22dd88c6c" uri="../flows/585733ef-4208-4edb-ab68-51a22dd88c6c.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">Litopenaeus vannamei</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToFlowDataSet>
			<exchangeDirection>Output</exchangeDirection>
			<meanAmount>1000.0</meanAmount>
			<resultingAmount>1000.0</resultingAmount>
			<dataDerivationTypeStatus>Measured</dataDerivationTypeStatus>
		</exchange>
	</exchanges>
</processDataSet>
