<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet version="1.0" href="../../stylesheets/process2html.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<processDataSet xmlns:common="http://lca.jrc.it/ILCD/Common" xmlns="http://lca.jrc.it/ILCD/Process" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" version="1.1" locations="../ILCDLocations.xml" xsi:schemaLocation="http://lca.jrc.it/ILCD/Process ../../schemas/ILCD_ProcessDataSet.xsd">
	<processInformation>
		<dataSetInformation>
			<common:UUID>aa6656f9-d94c-4d25-889d-cd675272b069</common:UUID>
			<name>
				<baseName xml:lang="en">cement production;cement, ordinary portland cement, 42.5MPa;new dry process, low-temperature waste heat power generation technology, 2000 t/d;fly ash</baseName>
				<baseName xml:lang="zh">水泥生产;水泥, 普通硅酸盐水泥, 42.5MPa;新型干法, 低温余热发电技术, 2000 t/d;粉煤灰</baseName>
			</name>
			<classificationInformation>
				<common:classification>
					<common:class level="0">Materials production</common:class>
					<common:class level="1">Other mineralic materials</common:class>
				</common:classification>
			</classificationInformation>
			<common:generalComment xml:lang="en">Laboratory data. New dry process low temperature waste heat power generation.The cement is produced by burning carbide slag generated by the acetylene industry in Heilongjiang. The new dry production line for low-temperature waste heat power generation uses the exhaust gas waste heat from the cooler at the kiln head and the preheater at the kiln tail, which is about 350°C, as the heating energy source. The low-pressure backpressure steam turbine is used for low-temperature waste heat power generation. An AQC waste heat boiler (vertical structure) is installed between the kiln head cooler and the waste gas fan, with a settling chamber before the AQC boiler. An SP waste heat boiler is installed between the kiln tail rotary kiln outlet and the high-temperature fan.The AQC boiler adopts the middle section air extraction with recycled waste gas method, and the original waste gas extraction port is changed into two extraction ports, with one high-temperature extraction port located in the front and one low-temperature extraction port located in the rear. The high-temperature hot air from the front extraction port is recovered after some fly ash is collected in the settling chamber and sent to the AQC boiler, while the low-temperature extraction port is mixed with the AQC boiler outlet air and processed by the original cement production line dust removal system. The waste gas at the kiln tail is cooled and heated by the SP boiler to around 230°C, and a part of it is sent to the raw material mill of the original system by the high-temperature fan, while the other part is humidified in the humidification tower before being sent to the tail gas dust collector. If the power generation system stops operating, the waste gas enters the high-temperature fan through the waste gas pipeline of the original system to ensure the stable operation of the cement production line.Through heat exchange, the boiler produces superheated steam, which is sent to the mixed steam cylinder for mixing and then enters the steam turbine for power generation through the superheated steam pipeline. The low-pressure steam from the steam turbine enters the condenser, where the steam condenses into water, which flows into the hot water well and is then pumped into the vacuum deaerator by a water pump. The water is then pumped into the AQC boiler for circulation by the feedwater pump.</common:generalComment>
			<common:generalComment xml:lang="zh">实验室数据。新型干法低温余热发电。应用黑龙江乙炔化工行业所产生的电石渣烧制水泥。新型干法生产线低温余热发电的工艺以窑头熟料冷却机和窑尾预热器排出350左右烟气余热作为供热能源，通过低压补汽式汽轮机进行低温余热发电。在窑头冷机和余风风机之间布置一台篦式冷却机（Air Quenching Cooler，AQC）余热锅炉（立式结构），在篦式冷却机（AQC）锅炉之前布置有沉降室；在窑尾一级旋简出口与高温风机之间装一台悬浮预热器（SP）余热锅炉。篦式冷却机（AQC）锅炉采用中部抽气带余风再循环方式，将原余风抽风口改为两个抽风口，新开抽风口一个靠前一个挪后，靠前的高温抽风口热风经沉降室回收部分飞灰后送至篦式冷却机（AQC）锅炉，挪后的低温抽风与篦式冷却机（AQC）锅炉出风混合后经原水泥生产线的除尘系统处理。窑尾废气经悬浮预热器（SP）锅炉吸热降温至230C左右，由高温风机将一部分送至原系统的生料磨，另外一部分经增湿塔增湿后至察尾收尘器若发电系统停用，则废气经原系统的废气管道进入高温风机，可确保水泥生产线稳定运行。通过热能交换，锅炉产生过热蒸汽，送到分汽缸进行混合，然后通过过热蒸汽管进入汽轮机发电。经汽轮机的乏汽进入凝汽器，蒸汽在凝汽器中凝结成水，汇入热水井，然后由水泵送往真空除氧器，再经给水泵泵入篦式冷却机（AQC）锅炉循环使用。</common:generalComment>
		</dataSetInformation>
		<quantitativeReference type="Reference flow(s)">
			<referenceToReferenceFlow>9</referenceToReferenceFlow>
		</quantitativeReference>
		<time>
			<common:referenceYear>2008</common:referenceYear>
		</time>
		<geography>
			<locationOfOperationSupplyOrProduction location="HLJ-CN">
				<descriptionOfRestrictions xml:lang="en">Mudanjiang New Material Technology Co., Ltd.</descriptionOfRestrictions>
				<descriptionOfRestrictions xml:lang="zh">牡丹江新材料科技有限公司</descriptionOfRestrictions>
			</locationOfOperationSupplyOrProduction>
		</geography>
		<technology>
			<technologyDescriptionAndIncludedProcesses xml:lang="en">This section selects the above process and uses calcium carbide slag produced by the Heilongjiang Yikuai chemical industry to burn cement to improve the environmental coordination of the Heilongjiang cement industry and promote the sustainable development of the cement industry. The process flow of pre-drying, dry grinding and dry burning is shown in Figure 5-1. Figure 5-4 shows the process flow of low-temperature waste heat power generation in the new dry process production line. This process uses about 350% flue gas waste heat discharged from the kiln head clinker cooler and kiln tail preheater as heating energy, and generates low-temperature waste heat power generation through a low-pressure steam turbine. An AQC waste heat boiler (vertical structure) is arranged between the kiln head cooler and the residual air fan, and a descending chamber is arranged in front of the AOC boiler; an SP waste heat boiler is installed between the outlet of the tail first-stage rotor and the high-temperature fan.The AQC boiler adopts the middle exhaust with residual air recirculation method. The original residual air exhaust outlet is changed to two exhaust outlets. One of the new exhaust outlets is moved to the front and the other is moved to the rear. The hot air from the front high-temperature exhaust outlet recovers part of the fly ash through the settling chamber. It is sent to the AOC boiler. The moved low-temperature exhaust air is mixed with the AOC boiler outlet air and then processed by the dust removal system of the original cement production line. The dense tail exhaust gas absorbs heat and is cooled to about 230C by the SP boiler. A part of the high temperature fan is sent to the raw meal mill of the original system, and the other part is humidified by the humidification tower and then sent to the tail dust collector. If the power generation system is disabled, the exhaust gas The exhaust gas pipe of the original system enters the high-temperature fan to ensure stable operation of the cement production line.Through heat energy exchange, the boiler generates superheated steam, which is sent to the separate cylinders for mixing, and then enters the steam turbine through the superheated steam pipe to generate electricity. The spent steam from the steam turbine enters the condenser. The spent steam condenses into water in the condenser and flows into the hot water well. It is then sent to the vacuum deaerator by the water pump, and then pumped into the AQC boiler through the feed water pump for recycling.</technologyDescriptionAndIncludedProcesses>
			<technologyDescriptionAndIncludedProcesses xml:lang="zh">本节选取上述工艺，应用黑龙江乙快化工行业所产生的电石渣烧制水泥，以改善黑龙江水泥工业环境协调性，促进水泥工业可持续发展。预烘干干磨干烧工艺流程如图 5-1 所示。图 5-4 所示为新型干法生产线低温余热发电的工艺流程。该工艺以窑头熟料冷却机和窑尾预热器排出 350 左右烟气余热作为供热能源，通过低压补汽式汽轮机进行低温余热发电。在窑头冷机和余风风机之间布置一台 AQC 余热锅炉(立式结构)，在 AOC 锅炉之前布置有降室;在尾一级旋简出口与高温风机之间装一台 SP 余热锅炉。AQC 锅炉采用中部抽气带余风再循环方式，将原余风抽风口改为两个抽风口，新开抽风口一个靠前一个挪后，靠前的高温抽风口热风经沉降室回收部分飞灰后送至 AOC 锅炉，挪后的低温抽风与 AOC 锅炉出风混合后经原水泥生产线的除尘系统处理。密尾废气经 SP 锅炉吸热降温至 230C左右，由高温风机将一部分送至原系统的生料磨，另外一部分经增湿塔增湿后至察尾收尘器若发电系统停用，则废气经原系统的废气管道进入高温风机，可确保水泥生产线稳定运行。通过热能交换，锅炉产生过热墓汽，送到分汽缸进行混合，然后通过过热蒸汽管进入汽轮机发电。经汽轮机的乏汽进入凝汽器，乏汽在凝汽器中凝结成水，汇入热水井，然后由水泵送往真空除氧器，再经给水泵泵入 AQC 锅炉循环使用。</technologyDescriptionAndIncludedProcesses>
			<technologicalApplicability xml:lang="en">The cement production process described is used in the manufacturing of ordinary Portland cement, with a specified compressive strength of 42.5MPa. This particular process applies new dry process technology integrated with a low-temperature waste heat power generation system capable of handling 2000 tons per day, which includes the use of fly ash and carbide slag, a by-product from the acetylene chemical industry in Heilongjiang. This approach serves to lower carbon emissions and improve environmental sustainability within the cement industry.</technologicalApplicability>
			<technologicalApplicability xml:lang="zh">该水泥生产工艺用于生产指定抗压强度为42.5MPa的普通硅酸盐水泥。这一特定工艺应用了新型干法技术，并集成了低温余热发电系统，日处理能力达2000吨，包括使用粉煤灰和黑龙江乙炔化工行业副产的电石渣。这种方法有助于降低碳排放并提升水泥工业的环境可持续性。</technologicalApplicability>
			<referenceToTechnologyFlowDiagrammOrPicture type="source data set" refObjectId="8f75402f-7d5a-520f-afe8-e0a5a640287c" uri="../sources/8f75402f-7d5a-520f-afe8-e0a5a640287c.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">OROjbidQYo3peXxxYEmc7c1Unif.png</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToTechnologyFlowDiagrammOrPicture>
		</technology>
		<mathematicalRelations>
			<modelDescription xml:lang="en">The functional unit is the performance of 1kg cement with a 28-day compressive strength of 42.5MPa, that is, 1Fu=42.5kgMPa. The scope of evaluation is raw meal preparation, clinker calcination and cement preparation. The environmental load caused by the consumption of clay resources is not considered for the time being. Iron powder is an iron correction material, and its environmental impact will not be considered. The wastes considered to be emitted at the output end of the product system mainly include nitrogen oxides, sulfur dioxide, carbon dioxide and dust.</modelDescription>
			<modelDescription xml:lang="zh">以1kg28天抗压强度为42.5MPa的水泥所具有的使用性能作为功能单位，即1Fu=42.5kgMPa。评价范围为生料准备、熟料煅烧和水泥制备。粘土类资源消耗造成的环境负荷暂不考虑。铁粉属于铁质校正材料，其引发的环境影响不予考虑。产品系统输出端考虑排放的废弃物主要包括氮氧化物、二氧化硫、二氧化碳及粉尘。</modelDescription>
		</mathematicalRelations>
	</processInformation>
	<modellingAndValidation>
		<LCIMethodAndAllocation>
			<typeOfDataSet>Unit process, black box</typeOfDataSet>
			<LCIMethodPrinciple>Not applicable</LCIMethodPrinciple>
			<deviationsFromLCIMethodPrinciple xml:lang="en">None</deviationsFromLCIMethodPrinciple>
			<deviationsFromLCIMethodPrinciple xml:lang="zh">无</deviationsFromLCIMethodPrinciple>
			<deviationsFromModellingConstants xml:lang="en">None</deviationsFromModellingConstants>
			<deviationsFromModellingConstants xml:lang="zh">无</deviationsFromModellingConstants>
		</LCIMethodAndAllocation>
		<dataSourcesTreatmentAndRepresentativeness>
			<deviationsFromCutOffAndCompletenessPrinciples xml:lang="en">None</deviationsFromCutOffAndCompletenessPrinciples>
			<deviationsFromCutOffAndCompletenessPrinciples xml:lang="zh">无</deviationsFromCutOffAndCompletenessPrinciples>
			<dataSelectionAndCombinationPrinciples xml:lang="en">Combined with the renovation design of Mudanjiang New Material Technology Co., Ltd.'s new dry process waste heat utilization energy-saving technology, the input and output data of the determined product system were collected, and the data were calculated and quantified.(1) Waste heat conditions can be utilized. 2 2000t/d new dry process production lines. In order to ensure the quality of waste heat, the inlet air of the waste heat furnace at the kiln head is extracted from the middle of the pavilion cooling machine. The air volume is 2x170329Nm^3/h, the exhaust gas temperature is 360°C, the waste heat utilization temperature range is 360~86°C, and the heat is 12302E+4kJ/h; the tail preheater The air intake volume of the heater is 2x203147Nm^3/h, and the exhaust gas temperature is 350°C. Considering the dry heat consumption of the coal mill, the waste heat utilization range is 350-205°C, with a heat capacity of 7927E+4kJ/h.(2) Installed capacity. Use the waste heat of the kiln tail waste gas to set up a kiln tail waste heat boiler. 2 kiln tail waste heat boilers can produce 2x13.5t/h-1.35Mpa-320 superheated steam; use the kiln head clinker cooler waste gas waste heat to set up a kiln head waste heat boiler. 2 The kiln head waste heat boiler can produce 2x9.0t/h-1.35Mpa-345 superheated steam and 62t/h-170 hot water at the same time, of which 44t/h is supplied to the kiln head and tail waste heat boilers to produce main steam, and 18t/h is supplied to the steam turbine. Room flash evaporation produces low-pressure saturated steam. According to the main steam quality that the waste heat boiler can produce, a steam-admission steam turbine is selected. The main steam parameter is 1.25MPa-320; the main steam volume produced by the head and tail is 45t/h, and the low-pressure steam volume produced by the head boiler is 5t/h. ; Calculated based on the overall efficiency of the steam turbine and generator being 805%, the average waste heat power generation power is 8600kW.(3) Save electricity. According to the actual operating conditions and power generation efficiency of the low-temperature waste heat power station, the average power generation power of the power station is 8600kW. Calculated based on the annual operation of 7200 hours, the annual power generation is 6192E+4kWh; deducting 7.8% of the power station’s self-consumption rate, which is 483E+4kWh, the actual power of the waste heat power station is 8600kW. The production line supplies 5709E+4kWh.(4) Reduce emissions. An interference separator is installed at the exhaust gas inlet of the waste heat boiler, which is conducive to the sedimentation of dust in the exhaust gas and reduces the dust content in the cement kiln exhaust gas by nearly 50%. Since thermal power generation is used in the north, electric energy is saved to reduce CO2 and SO2 caused by coal combustion during the power generation process. and NOx emissions.Through the above analysis, the inventory and analysis data of the environmental impact assessment of the cement industry under the new dry process low-temperature waste heat power generation scheme are calculated and obtained.</dataSelectionAndCombinationPrinciples>
			<dataSelectionAndCombinationPrinciples xml:lang="zh">结合牡丹江新材料科技有限公司新型干法余热利用节能技术改造设计，对所确定产品系统的输入、输出数据进行收集，并对数据进行了计算、量化。（1）可利用余热条件。2000t/d新型干法生产线2条。为保证余热品质，窑头余热炉进风从馆冷机中部抽取，取风量为2x170329Nm^3/h，废气温度360，余热利用温度范围360~86，具有12302E+4kJ/h的热量；尾预热器取风量2x203147Nm^3/h，废气温度350，考虑煤磨供干耗热，余热利用范围350-205，具有7927E+4kJ/h的热量。（2）装机容量。利用窑尾废气余热，设置窑尾余热锅炉，2台窑尾余热锅炉可生产2x13.5t/h-1.35Mpa-320过热蒸汽；利用窑头熟料冷却机废气余热，设置窑头余热锅炉，2台窑头余热锅炉可生产2x9.0t/h-1.35Mpa-345过热蒸汽，同时生产62t/h-170热水，其中44t/h供给窑头和尾余热锅炉生产主蒸汽，18t/h供给汽轮机房闪蒸生产低压饱和蒸汽。根据余热锅炉所能产生的主汽品味，选用补汽进汽式汽轮机，主蒸汽参数为1.25MPa-320；头、尾共生产主蒸汽量45t/h，头锅炉生产的低压蒸汽量5t/h；按汽轮机和发电机整体效率805%计算，平均余热发电功率为8600kW.（3）节约电能。根据低温余热电站实际运行状况和发电效率，电站平均发电功率为8600kW，以年运行7200h计算，年发电6192E+4kWh；扣除7.8%电站自用电率，即483E+4kWh，余热电站实际向生产线供电5709E+4kWh。（4）减少排放。余热锅炉废气入口处设置干扰式分离器，有利于废气中粉尘沉降，使水泥窑废气中粉尘含量下降近50%；由于北方采用火力发电，故节约电能减少发电过程中煤燃烧引发的CO2、SO2及NOx排放。通过上述分析，计算获取新型干法低温余热发电方案下，水泥工业环境影响评价编目分析数据。</dataSelectionAndCombinationPrinciples>
			<deviationsFromSelectionAndCombinationPrinciples xml:lang="en">None</deviationsFromSelectionAndCombinationPrinciples>
			<deviationsFromSelectionAndCombinationPrinciples xml:lang="zh">无</deviationsFromSelectionAndCombinationPrinciples>
			<deviationsFromTreatmentAndExtrapolationPrinciples xml:lang="en">None</deviationsFromTreatmentAndExtrapolationPrinciples>
			<deviationsFromTreatmentAndExtrapolationPrinciples xml:lang="zh">无</deviationsFromTreatmentAndExtrapolationPrinciples>
			<referenceToDataSource type="source data set" refObjectId="69b8c8e6-2264-4083-8d14-e06eda21e01f" uri="../sources/69b8c8e6-2264-4083-8d14-e06eda21e01f.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">于淼. (2008). 黑龙江水泥工业可持续发展研究 [硕士, 哈尔滨工业大学]. </common:shortDescription>
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="zh">于淼. (2008). 黑龙江水泥工业可持续发展研究 [硕士, 哈尔滨工业大学]. </common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToDataSource>
			<useAdviceForDataSet xml:lang="en">When utilizing this dataset for environmental impact assessments and life cycle analyses, LCA practitioners should closely consider the specific operating conditions detailed, such as temperatures and energy outputs. Attention should be paid to the implications of energy- and resource-efficiency improvements, integration of waste materials (fly ash and carbide slag), and emission reductions due to the waste heat recovery system. It's important to note that clay resource consumption and the environmental impact of iron powder correction materials are excluded from this data. Emission data for NOx, SO2, CO2, and dust at the output end should be taken into account.</useAdviceForDataSet>
			<useAdviceForDataSet xml:lang="zh">在使用此数据集进行环境影响评估和生命周期分析时，LCA实践者应密切关注详细的特定操作条件，如温度和能量输出。应注意能源和资源效率改进的影响，废弃物料（粉煤灰和电石渣）的综合利用，以及由于余热回收系统导致的排放减少。重要的是要注意，粘土资源消耗和铁粉校正材料的环境影响在此数据中被排除。产品系统输出端的NOx、SO2、CO2和粉尘排放数据应被考虑在内。</useAdviceForDataSet>
		</dataSourcesTreatmentAndRepresentativeness>
		<completeness/>
		<validation>
			<review type="Dependent internal review">
				<common:reviewDetails xml:lang="en">Inventory: The internal review was done by several iteration steps concerning raw data validation, raw data documentation, representativity, completeness and consistency of modelling with regard to ISO 14040 and 14044.</common:reviewDetails>
				<common:reviewDetails xml:lang="zh">清单： 内部审查通过几个迭代步骤完成，涉及原始数据验证、原始数据记录、代表性、完整性、与 ISO 14040 和 14044 有关的建模的一致性。</common:reviewDetails>
				<common:referenceToNameOfReviewerAndInstitution refObjectId="f4b4c314-8c4c-4c83-968f-5b3c7724f6a8" type="contact data set" uri="../contacts/f4b4c314-8c4c-4c83-968f-5b3c7724f6a8.xml">
					<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">Tiangong LCI Data Working Group</common:shortDescription>
					<common:shortDescription xml:lang="zh">天工LCI数据工作小组</common:shortDescription>
				</common:referenceToNameOfReviewerAndInstitution>
			</review>
		</validation>
	</modellingAndValidation>
	<administrativeInformation>
		<dataGenerator>
			<common:referenceToPersonOrEntityGeneratingTheDataSet type="contact data set" refObjectId="8ef5498f-0005-47f9-91da-1ded9b451ba1" uri="../contacts/8ef5498f-0005-47f9-91da-1ded9b451ba1.xml" version="01.00.000">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">Siqi Yang, ysqsophia@gmail.com</common:shortDescription>
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="zh">杨思琪, ysqsophia@gmail.com</common:shortDescription>
			</common:referenceToPersonOrEntityGeneratingTheDataSet>
			<common:other xml:lang="en">ysqsophia@gmail.com</common:other>
			<common:other xml:lang="zh">ysqsophia@gmail.com</common:other>
		</dataGenerator>
		<dataEntryBy>
			<common:timeStamp>2023-12-21T10:49:48+08:00</common:timeStamp>
		</dataEntryBy>
		<publicationAndOwnership>
			<common:dateOfLastRevision>2023-12-21T10:49:48+08:00</common:dateOfLastRevision>
			<common:dataSetVersion>01.00.000</common:dataSetVersion>
			<common:permanentDataSetURI>https://lcadata.tiangong.world/showProcess.xhtml?uuid=aa6656f9-d94c-4d25-889d-cd675272b069&amp;amp;version=01.00.000&amp;amp;stock=TianGong</common:permanentDataSetURI>
			<common:referenceToOwnershipOfDataSet refObjectId="f4b4c314-8c4c-4c83-968f-5b3c7724f6a8" type="contact data set" uri="../contacts/f4b4c314-8c4c-4c83-968f-5b3c7724f6a8.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">Tiangong LCI Data Working Group</common:shortDescription>
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="zh">天工LCI数据工作小组</common:shortDescription>
			</common:referenceToOwnershipOfDataSet>
			<common:copyright>false</common:copyright>
			<common:licenseType>Free of charge for all users and uses</common:licenseType>
		</publicationAndOwnership>
	</administrativeInformation>
	<exchanges>
		<exchange dataSetInternalID="0">
			<referenceToFlowDataSet type="flow data set" refObjectId="c431c0c3-3f5e-4b7b-af99-2ebbdcaf5f98" uri="../flows/c431c0c3-3f5e-4b7b-af99-2ebbdcaf5f98.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">limestone, crushed, for mill</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToFlowDataSet>
			<exchangeDirection>Input</exchangeDirection>
			<meanAmount>1104.4</meanAmount>
			<resultingAmount>1104.4</resultingAmount>
			<dataDerivationTypeStatus></dataDerivationTypeStatus>
			<generalComment xml:lang="en">Limestone</generalComment>
			<generalComment xml:lang="zh">石灰石</generalComment>
		</exchange>
		<exchange dataSetInternalID="1">
			<referenceToFlowDataSet type="flow data set" refObjectId="4f19a2fe-7b3b-11dd-ad8b-0800200c9a66" uri="../flows/4f19a2fe-7b3b-11dd-ad8b-0800200c9a66.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">gypsum stone (CaSO4-dihydrate)</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToFlowDataSet>
			<exchangeDirection>Input</exchangeDirection>
			<meanAmount>58.7</meanAmount>
			<resultingAmount>58.7</resultingAmount>
			<dataDerivationTypeStatus></dataDerivationTypeStatus>
			<generalComment xml:lang="en">Gypsum</generalComment>
			<generalComment xml:lang="zh">石膏</generalComment>
		</exchange>
		<exchange dataSetInternalID="2">
			<referenceToFlowDataSet type="flow data set" refObjectId="000194b6-3952-98e9-d1ad-0000493d769a" uri="../flows/000194b6-3952-98e9-d1ad-0000493d769a.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">ash</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToFlowDataSet>
			<exchangeDirection>Input</exchangeDirection>
			<meanAmount>319.4</meanAmount>
			<resultingAmount>319.4</resultingAmount>
			<dataDerivationTypeStatus></dataDerivationTypeStatus>
			<generalComment xml:lang="en">Fly ash</generalComment>
			<generalComment xml:lang="zh">粉煤灰</generalComment>
		</exchange>
		<exchange dataSetInternalID="3">
			<referenceToFlowDataSet type="flow data set" refObjectId="4f19a2ff-7b3b-11dd-ad8b-0800200c9a66" uri="../flows/4f19a2ff-7b3b-11dd-ad8b-0800200c9a66.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">hard coal</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToFlowDataSet>
			<exchangeDirection>Input</exchangeDirection>
			<meanAmount>100.526</meanAmount>
			<resultingAmount>100.526</resultingAmount>
			<dataDerivationTypeStatus></dataDerivationTypeStatus>
			<generalComment xml:lang="en">Standard coal. The original data is 0.0934kg standard coal, here converted to hard coal, the conversion formula is 1kg hard coal = 0.929kg standard coal.</generalComment>
			<generalComment xml:lang="zh">标准煤。原始数据为0.0934kg标准煤，这里换算为硬煤，换算公式为1kg硬煤=0.929kg标准煤。</generalComment>
		</exchange>
		<exchange dataSetInternalID="4">
			<referenceToFlowDataSet type="flow data set" refObjectId="890a70b7-b677-4e2a-8a1b-7d017e0a10ae" uri="../flows/890a70b7-b677-4e2a-8a1b-7d017e0a10ae.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">Electricity</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToFlowDataSet>
			<exchangeDirection>Input</exchangeDirection>
			<meanAmount>211.32000000000002</meanAmount>
			<resultingAmount>211.32000000000002</resultingAmount>
			<dataDerivationTypeStatus></dataDerivationTypeStatus>
			<generalComment xml:lang="en">Electricity</generalComment>
			<generalComment xml:lang="zh">电力</generalComment>
		</exchange>
		<exchange dataSetInternalID="5">
			<referenceToFlowDataSet type="flow data set" refObjectId="fe0acd60-3ddc-11dd-a70a-0050c2490048" uri="../flows/fe0acd60-3ddc-11dd-a70a-0050c2490048.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">particles (&gt; PM10)</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToFlowDataSet>
			<exchangeDirection>Output</exchangeDirection>
			<meanAmount>0.249</meanAmount>
			<resultingAmount>0.249</resultingAmount>
			<dataDerivationTypeStatus></dataDerivationTypeStatus>
			<generalComment xml:lang="en">Dust</generalComment>
			<generalComment xml:lang="zh">粉尘</generalComment>
		</exchange>
		<exchange dataSetInternalID="6">
			<referenceToFlowDataSet type="flow data set" refObjectId="fe0acd60-3ddc-11dd-ac48-0050c2490048" uri="../flows/fe0acd60-3ddc-11dd-ac48-0050c2490048.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">sulfur dioxide</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToFlowDataSet>
			<exchangeDirection>Output</exchangeDirection>
			<meanAmount>0.3893</meanAmount>
			<resultingAmount>0.3893</resultingAmount>
			<dataDerivationTypeStatus></dataDerivationTypeStatus>
			<generalComment xml:lang="en">Sulfur dioxide</generalComment>
			<generalComment xml:lang="zh">二氧化硫</generalComment>
		</exchange>
		<exchange dataSetInternalID="7">
			<referenceToFlowDataSet type="flow data set" refObjectId="f79d0f8f-2b0e-49cb-bed0-b1ea0fbd8625" uri="../flows/f79d0f8f-2b0e-49cb-bed0-b1ea0fbd8625.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">Nitrogen oxides</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToFlowDataSet>
			<exchangeDirection>Output</exchangeDirection>
			<meanAmount>1.557</meanAmount>
			<resultingAmount>1.557</resultingAmount>
			<dataDerivationTypeStatus></dataDerivationTypeStatus>
			<generalComment xml:lang="en">Nitrogen oxides</generalComment>
			<generalComment xml:lang="zh">氮氧化物</generalComment>
		</exchange>
		<exchange dataSetInternalID="8">
			<referenceToFlowDataSet type="flow data set" refObjectId="fe0acd60-3ddc-11dd-af54-0050c2490048" uri="../flows/fe0acd60-3ddc-11dd-af54-0050c2490048.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">carbon dioxide</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToFlowDataSet>
			<exchangeDirection>Output</exchangeDirection>
			<meanAmount>813.1</meanAmount>
			<resultingAmount>813.1</resultingAmount>
			<dataDerivationTypeStatus></dataDerivationTypeStatus>
			<generalComment xml:lang="en">Carbon dioxide</generalComment>
			<generalComment xml:lang="zh">二氧化碳</generalComment>
		</exchange>
		<exchange dataSetInternalID="9">
			<referenceToFlowDataSet type="flow data set" refObjectId="89fb85db-c8dc-426c-a4cd-52de2184a31b" uri="../flows/89fb85db-c8dc-426c-a4cd-52de2184a31b.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">cement, ordinary portland cement, 42.5MPa</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToFlowDataSet>
			<exchangeDirection>Output</exchangeDirection>
			<meanAmount>1000.0</meanAmount>
			<resultingAmount>1000.0</resultingAmount>
			<dataDerivationTypeStatus></dataDerivationTypeStatus>
			<generalComment xml:lang="en">42.5 Ordinary silicate cement</generalComment>
			<generalComment xml:lang="zh">42.5普通硅酸盐水泥</generalComment>
		</exchange>
	</exchanges>
</processDataSet>
