<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet version="1.0" href="../../stylesheets/process2html.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<processDataSet xmlns:common="http://lca.jrc.it/ILCD/Common" xmlns="http://lca.jrc.it/ILCD/Process" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" version="1.1" locations="../ILCDLocations.xml" xsi:schemaLocation="http://lca.jrc.it/ILCD/Process ../../schemas/ILCD_ProcessDataSet.xsd">
	<processInformation>
		<dataSetInformation>
			<common:UUID>b128ca26-fcb5-47f8-b9fe-3910834afb2c</common:UUID>
			<name>
				<baseName xml:lang="en">Pig production ; farmers in Penzhoushan area free-range</baseName>
				<baseName xml:lang="zh">养猪生产 ; 盆周山地区农户散养</baseName>
			</name>
			<classificationInformation>
				<common:classification>
					<common:class level="0">Materials production</common:class>
					<common:class level="1">Agricultural production means</common:class>
				</common:classification>
			</classificationInformation>
			<common:generalComment xml:lang="en">In Sichuan, farmers provide about 79.5% of the commercial pigs, which has an important position in Sichuan pig industry. The main scenario states and parameters were set as follows: (1) the feed was mainly composed of self-planted corn, vegetables and other agricultural by-products, supplemented with a small amount of concentrated feed (soybean meal 70%, rapeseed meal 10%), and the insufficient part was collected as feed supplement. The cultivated land area is assumed to be 0.2067 square hectares per household. (2) The average number of pigs is 3 / household, most of the varieties are soil mixed pigs (local sows and foreign breeding pigs cross, a few are Chinese local breeds) the average slaughter rate is 70%; (3) Extensive feeding and management methods, long feeding period, the average pig feeding day is about 240d, the average weight of the yard is 100kg; (4) Manure treatment and utilization: The anaerobic manure tank is used for storage,80% of which is returned to the field, 48% of which is directly returned to the field in the busy season, and the long-term storage accounts for 32% (irregular return to the field). 20% of the fecal water is leaking in the manure tank or when returning to the field, and the COD of the seepage water is 50mg/L.</common:generalComment>
			<common:generalComment xml:lang="zh">在四川，农户散养提供了大约79.5%的商品猪，在四川养猪业中具有重要的地位。主要情景状态和参数设定为 ①饲料以自种玉米、蔬菜和其他农副产物为主，辅以少量浓缩饲料（豆粕70%、 菜籽粕10%），不足部分采集野草作为饲料补充。耕地面积假设为0.2067平方公顷/户。② 出栏猪数量平均3头/户，品种多数为土杂猪（地方母猪与外种猪杂交，少数为中国地方品种）屠宰率平均为70% ③饲养管理方式粗放，饲养期长，猪平均饲养240d左右,出栏重平均为100kg ④粪便处理和利用: 采用厌氧粪池存贮,80%还田,其 中48%在农忙季节直接还田,长期存贮量占32% (不定时还田)。20%粪水在粪池中或还田时渗漏,渗出水COD为50mg/L.</common:generalComment>
		</dataSetInformation>
		<quantitativeReference type="Reference flow(s)">
			<functionalUnitOrOther xml:lang="en">In this study, the functional unit (FU) was defined as &quot;1kg pig carcass&quot;, which included skin, bone and fat. Foreign studies generally only considered lean meat, but in China's consumption mode, skin and viscera were also fully utilized as edible foods. The concept of carcass was adopted in this study. Although the bone included in this study is an inedible part, it can play a certain compensative role because it does not contain internal organs. In addition, the current data can be easily converted into carcass weight, so it is more in line with the actual situation.</functionalUnitOrOther>
			<referenceToReferenceFlow>3</referenceToReferenceFlow>
		</quantitativeReference>
		<time>
			<common:referenceYear>2006</common:referenceYear>
		</time>
		<geography>
			<locationOfOperationSupplyOrProduction location="SC-CN">
				<descriptionOfRestrictions xml:lang="en">The data of fecal water quantity were obtained from a survey of typical free-range farmers in the surrounding areas of the east Sichuan, north Sichuan and southwest Sichuan basins</descriptionOfRestrictions>
				<descriptionOfRestrictions xml:lang="zh">粪水量数据来自对川东、川北和四川西南盆地周边区个典型性散养农户的调查</descriptionOfRestrictions>
			</locationOfOperationSupplyOrProduction>
		</geography>
		<technology>
			<technologyDescriptionAndIncludedProcesses xml:lang="en">Including raw material production, transportation and pig production process, but does not include pig slaughtering, processing and packaging, transportation process. Pig equipment, machinery and construction are not included, and materials less than 5% of the total or of low environmental relevance are excluded. The production, use and emission of drugs are not considered. Fishmeal and amino acid production are not considered</technologyDescriptionAndIncludedProcesses>
			<technologyDescriptionAndIncludedProcesses xml:lang="zh">包括原料生产、运输和养猪生产过程，但没有包括猪的屠宰、加工及包装、运输过程。没有包括养猪设备、机械和建筑方面，对小于总量5%或环境关联性小的材料进行了剔除。药品的生产、使用和污染排放没有考虑。鱼粉和氨基酸生产没考虑</technologyDescriptionAndIncludedProcesses>
			<technologicalApplicability xml:lang="en">The pig production data is relevant for assessing the environmental impacts of free-range pig farming in the Penzhoushan area, Sichuan. It applies to traditional free-range practices where pigs are mainly nourished by on-site grown crops and agricultural by-products, and less with concentrated feeds. This data suits investigations into extensive pig breeding systems that are a major part of Sichuan's pig industry, providing transparency in nutrient production, greenhouse gas emissions, and manure management practices.</technologicalApplicability>
			<technologicalApplicability xml:lang="zh">本数据适用于评估四川盆周山地区农户散养养猪的环境影响。散养系统主要以自产的玉米、蔬菜和其他农副产品为饲料，辅以少量浓缩饲料，适合于研究四川省养猪业的传统粗放养殖模式，提供营养物质生产、温室气体排放和粪便管理等环境透明度信息。</technologicalApplicability>
			<referenceToTechnologyFlowDiagrammOrPicture type="source data set" refObjectId="1e45a6d4-512e-aa46-b69e-6089bb1aedb8" uri="../sources/1e45a6d4-512e-aa46-b69e-6089bb1aedb8.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">ZPnhbjhFNokw6WxhhvSclKMbnpI.png</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToTechnologyFlowDiagrammOrPicture>
		</technology>
	</processInformation>
	<modellingAndValidation>
		<LCIMethodAndAllocation>
			<typeOfDataSet>Unit process, single operation</typeOfDataSet>
			<LCIMethodPrinciple>Not applicable</LCIMethodPrinciple>
			<deviationsFromLCIMethodPrinciple xml:lang="en">None</deviationsFromLCIMethodPrinciple>
			<deviationsFromLCIMethodPrinciple xml:lang="zh">无</deviationsFromLCIMethodPrinciple>
			<deviationsFromLCIMethodApproaches xml:lang="en">This study combined LCA methodology and scenario analysis method to conduct systematic environmental impact assessment for three typical pig production scenarios in Sichuan, explore the specific algorithms applied to the current environmental impact assessment of pig production, and reveal the environmentally friendly and unfavorable aspects of various pig production systems and their non-renewable energy utilization efficiency. The results are helpful to the understanding of environmental impact of pig industry and provide reference for the establishment of sustainable development model of pig industry.</deviationsFromLCIMethodApproaches>
			<deviationsFromLCIMethodApproaches xml:lang="zh">本研究采用LCA方法学和情景分析法相结合的方式对四川三种典型的养猪生产 情景进行系统的环境影响评估，探索这种分析方法应用于当前养猪生产环境影响评估 时的具体算法，并揭示各种养猪生产系统中的环境友好和不利方面以及其不可更新能 源利用效率。研究结果有助于对养猪业环境影响态势的认识，并为养猪可持续发展模 式的建立提供参考。</deviationsFromLCIMethodApproaches>
			<deviationsFromModellingConstants xml:lang="en">None</deviationsFromModellingConstants>
			<deviationsFromModellingConstants xml:lang="zh">无</deviationsFromModellingConstants>
		</LCIMethodAndAllocation>
		<dataSourcesTreatmentAndRepresentativeness>
			<deviationsFromCutOffAndCompletenessPrinciples xml:lang="en">None</deviationsFromCutOffAndCompletenessPrinciples>
			<deviationsFromCutOffAndCompletenessPrinciples xml:lang="zh">无</deviationsFromCutOffAndCompletenessPrinciples>
			<dataSelectionAndCombinationPrinciples xml:lang="en">In the pollution emission inventory of pig production under various scenarios, the production of fecal and urine nutrients and the production of major greenhouse gases are mainly analyzed. The environmental pollution of malodorous gases, noise and pathogens is not analyzed due to the lack of quantitative data on its potential impact on health. The waste discharge of animal production process was corrected by referring to recent research literature and combining with the data collected in the investigation, so as to reflect the actual situation in Sichuan. Among them, the emission estimate of NH3 is based on the research results of multiple literatures</dataSelectionAndCombinationPrinciples>
			<dataSelectionAndCombinationPrinciples xml:lang="zh">各种情景下的养猪生产过程的污染排放清单中，主要分析粪便和尿液养分的产生量及主要的温室气体产生量，对恶臭气体、噪声和病原体的环境污染，因目前缺少其 对健康的影响潜势方面的量化数据，没有进行分析。动物生产过程的废物排放参考近年的研究文献，结合调查中收集的数据进行校正，以基本反映四川实际。其中，NH3的排放量估计是综合了多个文献的研究成果</dataSelectionAndCombinationPrinciples>
			<deviationsFromSelectionAndCombinationPrinciples xml:lang="en">None</deviationsFromSelectionAndCombinationPrinciples>
			<deviationsFromSelectionAndCombinationPrinciples xml:lang="zh">无</deviationsFromSelectionAndCombinationPrinciples>
			<dataTreatmentAndExtrapolationsPrinciples xml:lang="en">1) Due to the complexity of pig breeding patterns in different regions, it is impossible to obtain completely consistent data in similar models. Therefore, according to the main differences related to environmental pollution among relevant literatures, yearbooks and set scenarios, the average data in similar scenarios are calculated on the basis of eliminating suspicious data. 2) There are two types of waste discharge data sources in animal production process, one is directly obtained from investigation and literature, and the other is derived from literature. In order to ensure the quality of data, some actual production data which deviated from the mean value were verified by experiments and consulted by experts, and corrected by cross-reference and comparison of various literatures.</dataTreatmentAndExtrapolationsPrinciples>
			<dataTreatmentAndExtrapolationsPrinciples xml:lang="zh">1）由于各地养猪模式十分复杂，无法在同类模式中取得完全一致的数据，因此根据相关文献、年鉴和设定情景间与环境污染有关的主要差异，在剔除可疑数据的基础上计算出同类情景中的平均数据。2）动物生产过程的废物排放数据来源有两类，一类是直接由调查和文献中得到，另一类是根据文献资料反推得到。为保证数据质量，对部分偏离均值较大的生产中实际产生量数据进行了试验验证和专家咨询，并通过多种途径的文献互相参照比较进行校正。</dataTreatmentAndExtrapolationsPrinciples>
			<deviationsFromTreatmentAndExtrapolationPrinciples xml:lang="en">None</deviationsFromTreatmentAndExtrapolationPrinciples>
			<deviationsFromTreatmentAndExtrapolationPrinciples xml:lang="zh">无</deviationsFromTreatmentAndExtrapolationPrinciples>
			<referenceToDataSource type="source data set" refObjectId="78ae11f1-32df-436b-a9b2-08f104575682" uri="../sources/78ae11f1-32df-436b-a9b2-08f104575682.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">白林. 四川养猪业清洁生产系统LCA及猪粪资源化利用关键技术研究. (四川农业大学, 2007).</common:shortDescription>
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="zh">白林. 四川养猪业清洁生产系统LCA及猪粪资源化利用关键技术研究. (四川农业大学, 2007).</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToDataSource>
			<useAdviceForDataSet xml:lang="en">When using the LCA data, tailor your analysis tools to track and aggregate inputs such as self-planted crops and by-products, concentrated feed composition, cultivated land area, and livestock output measures like slaughter rate and average carcass weight. Pay special attention to the parameters of manure treatment, storage and field application practices. Ensure any modeling reflects the free-range, extensive farming style and geographical specificity of the Penzhoushan area. Emissions such as NH3 should be estimated based on multiple literature sources. Exclude considerations of pig slaughtering, processing, and transportation from this dataset, as well as minor materials with less environmental significance.</useAdviceForDataSet>
			<useAdviceForDataSet xml:lang="zh">使用生命周期评估数据时，需调整分析工具来跟踪和汇总投入，如自种作物及副产品、浓缩饲料成分、耕地面积以及屠宰率、平均胴体重量等畜产出度量指标。粪便处理、储存和田间施用的做法需要重点关注。确保任何建模都反映了盆周山地区特有的自由放养、粗放农业风格。NH3等排放量应根据多份文献来源估算。此数据集不包括猪的屠宰、加工和运输过程，同时还应排除对环境影响较小的材料考虑。</useAdviceForDataSet>
		</dataSourcesTreatmentAndRepresentativeness>
		<completeness/>
		<validation>
			<review type="Dependent internal review">
				<common:reviewDetails xml:lang="en">Inventory: The internal review was done by several iteration steps concerning raw data validation, raw data documentation, representativity, completeness and consistency of modelling with regard to ISO 14040 and 14044.</common:reviewDetails>
				<common:reviewDetails xml:lang="zh">清单： 内部审查通过几个迭代步骤完成，涉及原始数据验证、原始数据记录、代表性、完整性、与 ISO 14040 和 14044 有关的建模的一致性。</common:reviewDetails>
				<common:referenceToNameOfReviewerAndInstitution refObjectId="f4b4c314-8c4c-4c83-968f-5b3c7724f6a8" type="contact data set" uri="../contacts/f4b4c314-8c4c-4c83-968f-5b3c7724f6a8.xml">
					<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">Tiangong LCI Data Working Group</common:shortDescription>
					<common:shortDescription xml:lang="zh">天工LCI数据工作小组</common:shortDescription>
				</common:referenceToNameOfReviewerAndInstitution>
			</review>
		</validation>
	</modellingAndValidation>
	<administrativeInformation>
		<dataGenerator>
			<common:referenceToPersonOrEntityGeneratingTheDataSet type="contact data set" refObjectId="f3bc507b-0b5e-46f7-a7a3-44799e722d1c" uri="../contacts/f3bc507b-0b5e-46f7-a7a3-44799e722d1c.xml" version="01.00.000">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">Rui Yang, 1632707028@qq.com</common:shortDescription>
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="zh">杨瑞, 1632707028@qq.com</common:shortDescription>
			</common:referenceToPersonOrEntityGeneratingTheDataSet>
			<common:other xml:lang="en">1632707028@qq.com</common:other>
			<common:other xml:lang="zh">1632707028@qq.com</common:other>
		</dataGenerator>
		<dataEntryBy>
			<common:timeStamp>2023-12-18T10:39:37+08:00</common:timeStamp>
		</dataEntryBy>
		<publicationAndOwnership>
			<common:dateOfLastRevision>2024-01-27T10:20:40.760907+08:00</common:dateOfLastRevision>
			<common:dataSetVersion>00.01.004</common:dataSetVersion>
			<common:permanentDataSetURI>https://lcadata.tiangong.world/showProcess.xhtml?uuid=b128ca26-fcb5-47f8-b9fe-3910834afb2c&amp;amp;version=01.00.000&amp;amp;stock=TianGong</common:permanentDataSetURI>
			<common:referenceToOwnershipOfDataSet refObjectId="f4b4c314-8c4c-4c83-968f-5b3c7724f6a8" type="contact data set" uri="../contacts/f4b4c314-8c4c-4c83-968f-5b3c7724f6a8.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">Tiangong LCI Data Working Group</common:shortDescription>
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="zh">天工LCI数据工作小组</common:shortDescription>
			</common:referenceToOwnershipOfDataSet>
			<common:copyright>false</common:copyright>
			<common:licenseType>Free of charge for all users and uses</common:licenseType>
		</publicationAndOwnership>
	</administrativeInformation>
	<exchanges>
		<exchange dataSetInternalID="0">
			<referenceToFlowDataSet type="flow data set" refObjectId="08a91e70-3ddc-11dd-96ae-0050c2490048" uri="../flows/08a91e70-3ddc-11dd-96ae-0050c2490048.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">ammonia</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToFlowDataSet>
			<exchangeDirection>Output</exchangeDirection>
			<meanAmount>0.010029999999999999</meanAmount>
			<resultingAmount>0.010029999999999999</resultingAmount>
			<dataDerivationTypeStatus>Measured</dataDerivationTypeStatus>
			<generalComment xml:lang="en">Scenario A</generalComment>
			<generalComment xml:lang="zh">情景A(农户散养）</generalComment>
		</exchange>
		<exchange dataSetInternalID="1">
			<referenceToFlowDataSet type="flow data set" refObjectId="29061478-6556-11dd-ad8b-0800200c9a66" uri="../flows/29061478-6556-11dd-ad8b-0800200c9a66.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">nitrous oxide</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToFlowDataSet>
			<exchangeDirection>Output</exchangeDirection>
			<meanAmount>0.00027360000000000004</meanAmount>
			<resultingAmount>0.00027360000000000004</resultingAmount>
			<dataDerivationTypeStatus>Unknown derivation</dataDerivationTypeStatus>
			<generalComment xml:lang="en">Scenario A</generalComment>
			<generalComment xml:lang="zh">情景A(农户散养）</generalComment>
		</exchange>
		<exchange dataSetInternalID="2">
			<referenceToFlowDataSet type="flow data set" refObjectId="08a91e70-3ddc-11dd-960e-0050c2490048" uri="../flows/08a91e70-3ddc-11dd-960e-0050c2490048.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">methane</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToFlowDataSet>
			<exchangeDirection>Output</exchangeDirection>
			<meanAmount>0.031169000000000002</meanAmount>
			<resultingAmount>0.031169000000000002</resultingAmount>
			<dataDerivationTypeStatus>Calculated</dataDerivationTypeStatus>
			<generalComment xml:lang="en">Scenario A</generalComment>
			<generalComment xml:lang="zh">情景A(农户散养）</generalComment>
		</exchange>
		<exchange dataSetInternalID="3">
			<referenceToFlowDataSet type="flow data set" refObjectId="819b3d73-321f-4c77-8039-0fffab79e82f" uri="../flows/819b3d73-321f-4c77-8039-0fffab79e82f.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">pig</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToFlowDataSet>
			<exchangeDirection>Output</exchangeDirection>
			<meanAmount>1.0</meanAmount>
			<resultingAmount>1.0</resultingAmount>
			<dataDerivationTypeStatus>Measured</dataDerivationTypeStatus>
			<generalComment xml:lang="en">pork</generalComment>
			<generalComment xml:lang="zh">猪肉</generalComment>
		</exchange>
		<exchange dataSetInternalID="4">
			<referenceToFlowDataSet type="flow data set" refObjectId="890a70b7-b677-4e2a-8a1b-7d017e0a10ae" uri="../flows/890a70b7-b677-4e2a-8a1b-7d017e0a10ae.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">Electricity</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToFlowDataSet>
			<exchangeDirection>Input</exchangeDirection>
			<meanAmount>0.329142852</meanAmount>
			<resultingAmount>0.329142852</resultingAmount>
			<dataDerivationTypeStatus>Calculated</dataDerivationTypeStatus>
			<generalComment xml:lang="zh">情景A(农户散养）</generalComment>
		</exchange>
	</exchanges>
</processDataSet>
