<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet version="1.0" href="../../stylesheets/process2html.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<processDataSet xmlns:common="http://lca.jrc.it/ILCD/Common" xmlns="http://lca.jrc.it/ILCD/Process" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" version="1.1" locations="../ILCDLocations.xml" xsi:schemaLocation="http://lca.jrc.it/ILCD/Process ../../schemas/ILCD_ProcessDataSet.xsd">
	<processInformation>
		<dataSetInformation>
			<common:UUID>c046b5c6-cc75-4c19-bd14-c78577f6c07b</common:UUID>
			<name>
				<baseName xml:lang="en">The production of M.OSB ; Miscanthus lutarioriparius-based oriented strand particleboards ; A particular modified starch-based adhesive (paraffin-free) was added in </baseName>
				<baseName xml:lang="zh">M. OSB的生产 ; 基于芦苇芒属的刨花板 ; 添加了一种特殊的改性淀粉基粘合剂（不含石蜡）</baseName>
			</name>
			<classificationInformation>
				<common:classification>
					<common:class level="0">Materials production</common:class>
					<common:class level="1">Other materials</common:class>
				</common:classification>
			</classificationInformation>
			<common:generalComment xml:lang="en">The content of cellulose, hemicellulose, and lignin reached 39.07%, 8.90%, and 12.48% at the late growth stage of M. lutarioriparius, which was higher than the other three kinds of agricultural residues (rice-straw, cornstalk, and wheat-straw). It, therefore, has better physical properties as a base material for particleboards. The findings of this paper are a supplement to previous studies on non-wood particleboard. In conventional processes, two types of chemicals are usually utilized: thermosetting resin, such as urea-formaldehyde resin, acting as a binder; and paraffin emulsion, which improves the hygroscopic properties of the panel. A particular modified starch-based adhesive was added in M.OSB, which was free of paraffin. The main components of the modified starch-based adhesive are corn starch, polyvinyl alcohol, and water. As the formulation is a non-patented technology, this is not an exhaustive list, and components of less than 1% mass are not listed. </common:generalComment>
			<common:generalComment xml:lang="zh">芦苇芒属植物生长后期的纤维素、半纤维素和木质素含量分别达到 39.07%、8.90% 和 12.48%，高于其他三种农作物秸秆（稻草、玉米秆和麦秆）。因此，它作为刨花板的基材具有更好的物理特性。本文的研究结果是对以往有关非木材刨花板研究的补充。在传统工艺中，通常使用两种化学品：热固性树脂（如脲醛树脂）作为粘合剂；石蜡乳液可改善板材的吸湿性能。在 M.OSB 中添加了一种不含石蜡的改性淀粉基粘合剂。改性淀粉基粘合剂的主要成分是玉米淀粉、聚乙烯醇和水。由于该配方属于非专利技术，因此这并不是一份详尽的清单，质量小于 1%的成分也未列出。</common:generalComment>
		</dataSetInformation>
		<quantitativeReference type="Reference flow(s)">
			<referenceToReferenceFlow>8</referenceToReferenceFlow>
		</quantitativeReference>
		<time>
			<common:referenceYear>2021</common:referenceYear>
		</time>
		<geography>
			<locationOfOperationSupplyOrProduction location="HUN-CN">
				<descriptionOfRestrictions xml:lang="en">This is an LCA Case Study of Lake Dongting District in China.</descriptionOfRestrictions>
				<descriptionOfRestrictions xml:lang="zh">这是一项关于中国洞庭湖区（湖南省）的生命周期评估案例研究。</descriptionOfRestrictions>
			</locationOfOperationSupplyOrProduction>
		</geography>
		<technology>
			<technologyDescriptionAndIncludedProcesses xml:lang="zh">该工业系统的主要步骤包括制备主要材料、干燥、生产粘合剂、上浆、成型和完成板材。在原料准备阶段，需要对原料进行堆放和筛选，以去除杂质，如树叶、节疤和灰尘。在烘干阶段，将栗木切碎，然后烘干以达到所需的含水量，之后生产颗粒并重复筛选。粘合剂的生产过程涉及非专利技术，因此在此不再赘述。在施胶阶段，生物粘合剂是提前准备好的，颗粒和胶水是自动处理的，直到粘合剂在胶水混合器中通过相互摩擦均匀地保持在表面上。成型阶段包括将已确定尺寸的颗粒成型为板坯，并对板坯进行预压，以减小厚度并提高抗拉强度。合格的板坯继续成型和修补，不合格的板坯通过重复这一过程进行回收。最后一道工序是板材加工，成型的板材在卸载、干燥和切割后堆放两天。这些步骤又分为四个阶段：材料准备（I）、粘合剂生产（II）、刨花板生产（III）和发热（IV）。此外，还有一些辅助工序（V），包括现场清洁和内部运输。</technologyDescriptionAndIncludedProcesses>
			<technologyDescriptionAndIncludedProcesses xml:lang="en">The main steps of the industrial system include preparation of the primary material, drying, adhesive production, sizing, forming, and finishing the board. The material preparation phase involves stockpiling the raw materials and screening them to remove impurities such as leaves, joints, and dust. In the drying phase, M. lutarioriparius are chipped and then dried to meet the required water content, after which particles are produced and screening is repeated. The production process of the adhesive involves a non-patented technology, and as such will not be elaborated on here. During the sizing phase, bio-adhesives are prepared in advance, with particles and glue being processed automatically until the binder is kept evenly on the surface by mutual friction in the glue mixer. The forming phase involves forming the sized particles into slabs, which are preloaded to reduce the thickness and increase the tensile strength. The qualified slabs go on to be shaped and repaired, with unqualified slabs being recycled by repeating this process. The final step is board finishing, in which the formed boards are stacked for two days after unloading, drying, and cutting. These steps are further divided into four stages: material preparation (I), adhesive production (II), particleboard production (III), and heat generation (IV). In addition, there are a few more auxiliary processes (V), including field cleaning and internal transportation. </technologyDescriptionAndIncludedProcesses>
			<referenceToTechnologyFlowDiagrammOrPicture type="source data set" refObjectId="9279423b-c7ee-8284-7ef8-23a70c2ff68e" uri="../sources/9279423b-c7ee-8284-7ef8-23a70c2ff68e.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">W5Web4id7oRJidxMVB8cvcebnih.png</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToTechnologyFlowDiagrammOrPicture>
		</technology>
	</processInformation>
	<modellingAndValidation>
		<LCIMethodAndAllocation>
			<typeOfDataSet>Unit process, single operation</typeOfDataSet>
			<LCIMethodPrinciple>Attributional</LCIMethodPrinciple>
			<deviationsFromLCIMethodPrinciple xml:lang="en">None</deviationsFromLCIMethodPrinciple>
			<deviationsFromLCIMethodPrinciple xml:lang="zh">无</deviationsFromLCIMethodPrinciple>
			<LCIMethodApproach>Allocation</LCIMethodApproach>
			<deviationsFromModellingConstants xml:lang="en">None</deviationsFromModellingConstants>
			<deviationsFromModellingConstants xml:lang="zh">无</deviationsFromModellingConstants>
		</LCIMethodAndAllocation>
		<dataSourcesTreatmentAndRepresentativeness>
			<deviationsFromCutOffAndCompletenessPrinciples xml:lang="en">None</deviationsFromCutOffAndCompletenessPrinciples>
			<deviationsFromCutOffAndCompletenessPrinciples xml:lang="zh">无</deviationsFromCutOffAndCompletenessPrinciples>
			<dataSelectionAndCombinationPrinciples xml:lang="en">The inventory data of M.OSB (agricultural and industrial production) were obtained from the Hanchuang Particleboard Manufacturing Co. Ltd. in Anxiang County, Changde, China. The average value of M.OSB production was retrieved from the field measurement data and internal documents of a third-party institution (Jinke Testing Institution, Changsha, China). Data regarding the production of polyvinyl alcohol (PVA) was collected from a chemical plant (Ningdong Energy Chemical Investment Co. Ltd.) in Ningxia Hui Autonomous Region of China. The inventory of biomass fuel follows the production profile of a biomass solid fuel plant, which is only 2 km away from the M.OSB production field. The CO2 emission during biomass fuel combustion was calculated according to IPCC 2006. The inventory data of transportation were derived from the literature. The remaining background data were obtained from various databases in SimaPro 9.0, such as ELCD and Ecoinvent. </dataSelectionAndCombinationPrinciples>
			<dataSelectionAndCombinationPrinciples xml:lang="zh">M.OSB（农业和工业生产）的库存数据来自中国常德市安乡县汉创刨花板制造有限公司。中国常德市安乡县汉创刨花板制造有限公司的库存数据。M.OSB产量的平均值来自实地测量数据和第三方机构（中国长沙金科检测机构）的内部文件。聚乙烯醇 (PVA) 的生产数据来自中国宁夏回族自治区的一家化工厂（宁东能源化工投资有限公司）。生物质燃料清单是根据一家生物质固体燃料厂的生产概况编制的，该厂距离 M.OSB 生产基地仅 2 公里。生物质燃料燃烧过程中的二氧化碳排放量根据 IPCC 2006 进行计算。运输的清单数据来自文献。其余背景数据来自 SimaPro 9.0 中的各种数据库，如 ELCD 和 Ecoinvent。</dataSelectionAndCombinationPrinciples>
			<deviationsFromSelectionAndCombinationPrinciples xml:lang="en">None</deviationsFromSelectionAndCombinationPrinciples>
			<deviationsFromSelectionAndCombinationPrinciples xml:lang="zh">无</deviationsFromSelectionAndCombinationPrinciples>
			<dataTreatmentAndExtrapolationsPrinciples xml:lang="en">Several data sources have been averaged. Average values are the ones used in the inventory. </dataTreatmentAndExtrapolationsPrinciples>
			<dataTreatmentAndExtrapolationsPrinciples xml:lang="zh">对多个数据源进行了平均处理。清单中使用的是平均值。</dataTreatmentAndExtrapolationsPrinciples>
			<deviationsFromTreatmentAndExtrapolationPrinciples xml:lang="en">None</deviationsFromTreatmentAndExtrapolationPrinciples>
			<deviationsFromTreatmentAndExtrapolationPrinciples xml:lang="zh">无</deviationsFromTreatmentAndExtrapolationPrinciples>
			<referenceToDataSource type="source data set" refObjectId="1237fd3b-17ba-4c88-9594-74744a201f86" uri="../sources/1237fd3b-17ba-4c88-9594-74744a201f86.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">Liao, Q., Zhang, J., Yi, Z. &amp; Li, Y. Do Miscanthus lutarioriparius-Based Oriented Strand Boards Provide Environmentally Benign Alternatives? An LCA Case Study of Lake Dongting District in China. Sustainability 13, 12976 (2021).</common:shortDescription>
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="zh">Liao, Q., Zhang, J., Yi, Z. &amp; Li, Y. Do Miscanthus lutarioriparius-Based Oriented Strand Boards Provide Environmentally Benign Alternatives? An LCA Case Study of Lake Dongting District in China. Sustainability 13, 12976 (2021).</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToDataSource>
		</dataSourcesTreatmentAndRepresentativeness>
		<completeness>
			<common:other xml:lang="en">It covers the life cycle of M.OSB production, comparing it with MDP, OSB, and MDF in China, utilizing attributive LCA methods. The boundary of this system, which begins at the fields (cradle) and ends with fiberboard production (product gate), consists of two subsystems: agricultural and industrial. The agricultural boundary usually includes ditching, sowing, fertilization, insect control, and seeding. However, for this study, we only consider the diesel fuel consumption of harvesting and feedstock transportation. The reasons for this are: (1) ditching is required every five years, and sowing at intervals of 15 years; (2) only a small quantity of fertilizer is used, because the fields, located in the wetland and tidal flats around Lake Dongting, are fertilized annually by seasonal flooding; and (3) the doses of herbicides and pesticides needed are small or even none, and as of 2017 should be in accordance with the environmental policy for Lake Dongting. For comparability between the plates, all the system boundaries were unified and carbon sequestration during the plants’ growth stage was not considered. For the biomass fuels used in the combustion phase, the generated CO2 is approximately equal to the fixed. Consequently, the net CO2 emission in this stage can be ignored. If fossil fuels were used instead of bio-fuels, the produced CO2 is a net emission with no offset. For these reasons, the actual CO2 emission of production utilizing biomass fuel should be less than our result.The process flow has been designed with the aim of cleaner production. The fuel used in the heat generation is partly recycled from the waste generated during the screening and cutting steps. The solid waste, including combustion remains, dust on the ground, and dust collected by cyclone dust collectors, is collected by the local fertilizer company. In addition, all wastewater is recycled during the manufacturing process of the adhesive. In previous studies on wood boards, it has been proven that the environmental impact of producing the capital assets is much less important compared to their operational stage. Capital assets such as industrial machinery and infrastructure, as well as human activities such as daily consumption of workers and domestic sewage discharge, are not included within the system boundaries.</common:other>
			<common:other xml:lang="zh">它涵盖了 M.OSB 生产的生命周期，利用归因式生命周期评估方法将其与中国的 MDP、OSB 和中密度纤维板进行了比较。该系统的边界始于田间（摇篮），止于纤维板生产（产品门），由农业和工业两个子系统组成。农业边界通常包括开沟、灌溉、施肥、防虫和播种。不过，在本研究中，我们只考虑收割和原料运输的柴油消耗。原因如下 (1）开沟每五年一次，播种每 15 年一次；（2）只使用少量肥料，因为田地位于洞庭湖周围的湿地和滩涂，每年通过季节性洪水施肥；（3）所需除草剂和杀虫剂的剂量很小，甚至没有，截至 2017 年应符合洞庭湖的环保政策。为保证各板块之间的可比性，所有系统边界统一，不考虑植物生长阶段的碳封存。对于燃烧阶段使用的生物质燃料，产生的二氧化碳约等于固定的二氧化碳。因此，这一阶段的二氧化碳净排放量可以忽略不计。如果使用化石燃料而不是生物燃料，则产生的二氧化碳为净排放，无法抵消。因此，使用生物质燃料进行生产的实际二氧化碳排放量应小于我们的计算结果。工艺流程的设计旨在实现清洁生产。用于发热的燃料部分是从筛选和切割步骤中产生的废料中回收的。固体废物，包括燃烧残留物、地面灰尘和旋风除尘器收集的灰尘，由当地化肥公司收集。此外，在胶粘剂的生产过程中，所有废水都被回收利用。在以往关于木板的研究中，已经证明生产资本资产对环境的影响远远小于其运营阶段对环境的影响。工业机械和基础设施等资本资产，以及工人的日常消费和生活污水排放等人类活动，都不包括在系统范围内。</common:other>
		</completeness>
		<validation>
			<review type="Dependent internal review">
				<common:reviewDetails xml:lang="en">Inventory: The internal review was done by several iteration steps concerning raw data validation, raw data documentation, representativity, completeness and consistency of modelling with regard to ISO 14040 and 14044.</common:reviewDetails>
				<common:reviewDetails xml:lang="zh">清单： 内部审查通过几个迭代步骤完成，涉及原始数据验证、原始数据记录、代表性、完整性、与 ISO 14040 和 14044 有关的建模的一致性。</common:reviewDetails>
				<common:referenceToNameOfReviewerAndInstitution refObjectId="f4b4c314-8c4c-4c83-968f-5b3c7724f6a8" type="contact data set" uri="../contacts/f4b4c314-8c4c-4c83-968f-5b3c7724f6a8.xml">
					<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">Tiangong LCI Data Working Group</common:shortDescription>
					<common:shortDescription xml:lang="zh">天工LCI数据工作小组</common:shortDescription>
				</common:referenceToNameOfReviewerAndInstitution>
			</review>
		</validation>
	</modellingAndValidation>
	<administrativeInformation>
		<dataGenerator>
			<common:referenceToPersonOrEntityGeneratingTheDataSet type="contact data set" refObjectId="df059f52-a1c7-4bff-9ef1-9335a3530e71" uri="../contacts/df059f52-a1c7-4bff-9ef1-9335a3530e71.xml" version="01.00.000">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">Wanyue Tan, wytan9@student.ubc.ca</common:shortDescription>
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="zh">谭惋月, wytan9@student.ubc.ca</common:shortDescription>
			</common:referenceToPersonOrEntityGeneratingTheDataSet>
			<common:other xml:lang="en">wytan9@student.ubc.ca</common:other>
			<common:other xml:lang="zh">wytan9@student.ubc.ca</common:other>
		</dataGenerator>
		<dataEntryBy>
			<common:timeStamp>2023-12-04T19:49:25+08:00</common:timeStamp>
		</dataEntryBy>
		<publicationAndOwnership>
			<common:dateOfLastRevision>2023-12-04T19:49:25+08:00</common:dateOfLastRevision>
			<common:dataSetVersion>01.00.000</common:dataSetVersion>
			<common:permanentDataSetURI>https://lcadata.tiangong.world/showProcess.xhtml?uuid=c046b5c6-cc75-4c19-bd14-c78577f6c07b&amp;amp;version=01.00.000&amp;amp;stock=TianGong</common:permanentDataSetURI>
			<common:referenceToOwnershipOfDataSet refObjectId="f4b4c314-8c4c-4c83-968f-5b3c7724f6a8" type="contact data set" uri="../contacts/f4b4c314-8c4c-4c83-968f-5b3c7724f6a8.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">Tiangong LCI Data Working Group</common:shortDescription>
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="zh">天工LCI数据工作小组</common:shortDescription>
			</common:referenceToOwnershipOfDataSet>
			<common:copyright>false</common:copyright>
			<common:licenseType>Free of charge for all users and uses</common:licenseType>
		</publicationAndOwnership>
	</administrativeInformation>
	<exchanges>
		<exchange dataSetInternalID="0">
			<referenceToFlowDataSet type="flow data set" refObjectId="e82e9a84-4e44-4914-b1da-6186401eb560" uri="../flows/e82e9a84-4e44-4914-b1da-6186401eb560.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">Miscanthus lutarioriparius </common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToFlowDataSet>
			<exchangeDirection>Input</exchangeDirection>
			<meanAmount>1010.0</meanAmount>
			<resultingAmount>1010.0</resultingAmount>
			<dataDerivationTypeStatus>Measured</dataDerivationTypeStatus>
			<generalComment xml:lang="en">This is the input flow called M.lutarioriparius in the paper. </generalComment>
			<generalComment xml:lang="zh">This is the input flow called M.lutarioriparius in the paper. </generalComment>
		</exchange>
		<exchange dataSetInternalID="1">
			<referenceToFlowDataSet type="flow data set" refObjectId="2a847cb1-f8c0-4fd4-8c7c-2f26f1dcec70" uri="../flows/2a847cb1-f8c0-4fd4-8c7c-2f26f1dcec70.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">starch-based adhesive</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToFlowDataSet>
			<exchangeDirection>Input</exchangeDirection>
			<meanAmount>52.0</meanAmount>
			<resultingAmount>52.0</resultingAmount>
			<dataDerivationTypeStatus>Measured</dataDerivationTypeStatus>
			<generalComment xml:lang="en">This is the input flow called starch-based adhesive in the paper. </generalComment>
			<generalComment xml:lang="zh">This is the input flow called starch-based adhesive in the paper. </generalComment>
		</exchange>
		<exchange dataSetInternalID="2">
			<referenceToFlowDataSet type="flow data set" refObjectId="959f4657-43de-4558-988f-804bbb8c62a9" uri="../flows/959f4657-43de-4558-988f-804bbb8c62a9.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">Lubricant</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToFlowDataSet>
			<exchangeDirection>Input</exchangeDirection>
			<meanAmount>0.0003</meanAmount>
			<resultingAmount>0.0003</resultingAmount>
			<dataDerivationTypeStatus>Measured</dataDerivationTypeStatus>
			<generalComment xml:lang="en">This is the input flow called lubricants in the paper. </generalComment>
			<generalComment xml:lang="zh">This is the input flow called lubricants in the paper. </generalComment>
		</exchange>
		<exchange dataSetInternalID="3">
			<referenceToFlowDataSet type="flow data set" refObjectId="81960a30-5488-4358-a28a-a0ee1f43f0f2" uri="../flows/81960a30-5488-4358-a28a-a0ee1f43f0f2.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">Water for industrial use</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToFlowDataSet>
			<exchangeDirection>Input</exchangeDirection>
			<meanAmount>17.85</meanAmount>
			<resultingAmount>17.85</resultingAmount>
			<dataDerivationTypeStatus>Software or database</dataDerivationTypeStatus>
			<generalComment xml:lang="en">The &quot;Water for industrial use&quot; is selected here, which substitutes for the &quot;Water&quot; in the paper. </generalComment>
			<generalComment xml:lang="zh">The &quot;Water for industrial use&quot; is selected here, which substitutes for the &quot;Water&quot; in the paper. </generalComment>
		</exchange>
		<exchange dataSetInternalID="4">
			<referenceToFlowDataSet type="flow data set" refObjectId="3d76a1c4-d3d5-4f4a-8f19-2105511a4488" uri="../flows/3d76a1c4-d3d5-4f4a-8f19-2105511a4488.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">secondary fuel renewable</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToFlowDataSet>
			<exchangeDirection>Input</exchangeDirection>
			<meanAmount>41.9</meanAmount>
			<resultingAmount>41.9</resultingAmount>
			<dataDerivationTypeStatus>Measured</dataDerivationTypeStatus>
			<dataDerivationTypeStatus>Software or database</dataDerivationTypeStatus>
			<generalComment xml:lang="en">The secondary fuel renewable is selected here, which substitutes for the renewable fuel in the paper. </generalComment>
			<generalComment xml:lang="zh">The secondary fuel renewable is selected here, which substitutes for the renewable fuel in the paper. </generalComment>
		</exchange>
		<exchange dataSetInternalID="5">
			<referenceToFlowDataSet type="flow data set" refObjectId="890a70b7-b677-4e2a-8a1b-7d017e0a10ae" uri="../flows/890a70b7-b677-4e2a-8a1b-7d017e0a10ae.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">Electricity</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToFlowDataSet>
			<exchangeDirection>Input</exchangeDirection>
			<meanAmount>236.70453600000002</meanAmount>
			<resultingAmount>236.70453600000002</resultingAmount>
			<dataDerivationTypeStatus>Software or database</dataDerivationTypeStatus>
		</exchange>
		<exchange dataSetInternalID="6">
			<referenceToFlowDataSet type="flow data set" refObjectId="55a4c166-2eb6-43a3-9a13-2e4f2c4fee60" uri="../flows/55a4c166-2eb6-43a3-9a13-2e4f2c4fee60.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">Diesel</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToFlowDataSet>
			<exchangeDirection>Input</exchangeDirection>
			<meanAmount>1.34</meanAmount>
			<resultingAmount>1.34</resultingAmount>
			<dataDerivationTypeStatus>Unknown derivation</dataDerivationTypeStatus>
		</exchange>
		<exchange dataSetInternalID="7">
			<referenceToFlowDataSet type="flow data set" refObjectId="4f1a3f30-7b3b-11dd-ad8b-0800200c9a66" uri="../flows/4f1a3f30-7b3b-11dd-ad8b-0800200c9a66.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">transport in t*km</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToFlowDataSet>
			<exchangeDirection>Input</exchangeDirection>
			<meanAmount>170.5</meanAmount>
			<resultingAmount>170.5</resultingAmount>
			<dataDerivationTypeStatus>article inperiodical</dataDerivationTypeStatus>
		</exchange>
		<exchange dataSetInternalID="8">
			<referenceToFlowDataSet type="flow data set" refObjectId="4f19ca17-7b3b-11dd-ad8b-0800200c9a66" uri="../flows/4f19ca17-7b3b-11dd-ad8b-0800200c9a66.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">particle board</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToFlowDataSet>
			<exchangeDirection>Output</exchangeDirection>
			<meanAmount>1.0</meanAmount>
			<resultingAmount>1.0</resultingAmount>
			<dataDerivationTypeStatus>Measured</dataDerivationTypeStatus>
			<generalComment xml:lang="en">The particle board is selected here, which substitutes for the &quot;M.MDP (M.OSB)&quot; in the paper. </generalComment>
			<generalComment xml:lang="zh">The particle board is selected here, which substitutes for the &quot;M.MDP (M.OSB)&quot; in the paper. </generalComment>
		</exchange>
		<exchange dataSetInternalID="9">
			<referenceToFlowDataSet type="flow data set" refObjectId="f79d0f8f-2b0e-49cb-bed0-b1ea0fbd8625" uri="../flows/f79d0f8f-2b0e-49cb-bed0-b1ea0fbd8625.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">Nitrogen oxides</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToFlowDataSet>
			<exchangeDirection>Output</exchangeDirection>
			<meanAmount>0.0426</meanAmount>
			<resultingAmount>0.0426</resultingAmount>
			<dataDerivationTypeStatus>Software or database</dataDerivationTypeStatus>
		</exchange>
		<exchange dataSetInternalID="10">
			<referenceToFlowDataSet type="flow data set" refObjectId="fe0acd60-3ddc-11dd-ac48-0050c2490048" uri="../flows/fe0acd60-3ddc-11dd-ac48-0050c2490048.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">sulfur dioxide</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToFlowDataSet>
			<exchangeDirection>Output</exchangeDirection>
			<meanAmount>0.00712</meanAmount>
			<resultingAmount>0.00712</resultingAmount>
			<dataDerivationTypeStatus>Software or database</dataDerivationTypeStatus>
		</exchange>
		<exchange dataSetInternalID="11">
			<referenceToFlowDataSet type="flow data set" refObjectId="fe0acd60-3ddc-11dd-af54-0050c2490048" uri="../flows/fe0acd60-3ddc-11dd-af54-0050c2490048.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">carbon dioxide</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToFlowDataSet>
			<exchangeDirection>Output</exchangeDirection>
			<meanAmount>68.47</meanAmount>
			<resultingAmount>68.47</resultingAmount>
			<dataDerivationTypeStatus>Calculated</dataDerivationTypeStatus>
		</exchange>
		<exchange dataSetInternalID="12">
			<referenceToFlowDataSet type="flow data set" refObjectId="172b2803-6556-11dd-ad8b-0800200c9a66" uri="../flows/172b2803-6556-11dd-ad8b-0800200c9a66.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">soft wood (dry matter)</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToFlowDataSet>
			<exchangeDirection>Output</exchangeDirection>
			<meanAmount>0.017</meanAmount>
			<resultingAmount>0.017</resultingAmount>
			<dataDerivationTypeStatus>Measured</dataDerivationTypeStatus>
			<dataDerivationTypeStatus>Software or database</dataDerivationTypeStatus>
			<generalComment xml:lang="en">The inorganic dissolved matter is selected here, which substitutes for the particulate matter in the paper. </generalComment>
			<generalComment xml:lang="zh">The inorganic dissolved matter is selected here, which substitutes for the particulate matter in the paper. </generalComment>
		</exchange>
		<exchange dataSetInternalID="13">
			<referenceToFlowDataSet type="flow data set" refObjectId="08a91e70-3ddc-11dd-97ef-0050c2490048" uri="../flows/08a91e70-3ddc-11dd-97ef-0050c2490048.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">chemical oxygen demand</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToFlowDataSet>
			<exchangeDirection>Output</exchangeDirection>
			<meanAmount>0.0038</meanAmount>
			<resultingAmount>0.0038</resultingAmount>
			<dataDerivationTypeStatus>Software or database</dataDerivationTypeStatus>
			<generalComment xml:lang="en">The chemical oxygen demand is selected here, which substitutes for the CODcr in the paper.</generalComment>
			<generalComment xml:lang="zh">The chemical oxygen demand is selected here, which substitutes for the CODcr in the paper.</generalComment>
		</exchange>
		<exchange dataSetInternalID="14">
			<referenceToFlowDataSet type="flow data set" refObjectId="08a91e70-3ddc-11dd-97e0-0050c2490048" uri="../flows/08a91e70-3ddc-11dd-97e0-0050c2490048.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">biological oxygen demand</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToFlowDataSet>
			<exchangeDirection>Output</exchangeDirection>
			<meanAmount>0.00094</meanAmount>
			<resultingAmount>0.00094</resultingAmount>
			<dataDerivationTypeStatus>Software or database</dataDerivationTypeStatus>
			<generalComment xml:lang="en">The biological oxygen demand is selected here, which substitutes for the BOD_5 in the paper. </generalComment>
			<generalComment xml:lang="zh">The biological oxygen demand is selected here, which substitutes for the BOD_5 in the paper. </generalComment>
		</exchange>
		<exchange dataSetInternalID="15">
			<referenceToFlowDataSet type="flow data set" refObjectId="618d3d9a-9f85-417d-b0c4-e87942a9e345" uri="../flows/618d3d9a-9f85-417d-b0c4-e87942a9e345.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">Suspended solids, unspecified</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToFlowDataSet>
			<exchangeDirection>Output</exchangeDirection>
			<meanAmount>0.0028</meanAmount>
			<resultingAmount>0.0028</resultingAmount>
			<dataDerivationTypeStatus>Software or database</dataDerivationTypeStatus>
		</exchange>
		<exchange dataSetInternalID="16">
			<referenceToFlowDataSet type="flow data set" refObjectId="ad7051d4-bc9e-4de9-b5d4-4da0370f2551" uri="../flows/ad7051d4-bc9e-4de9-b5d4-4da0370f2551.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">Ammonia (NH4+, NH3, as N)</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToFlowDataSet>
			<exchangeDirection>Output</exchangeDirection>
			<meanAmount>0.00032</meanAmount>
			<resultingAmount>0.00032</resultingAmount>
			<dataDerivationTypeStatus>Software or database</dataDerivationTypeStatus>
			<generalComment xml:lang="en">The Ammonia (NH4+, NH3, as N) is selected here, which substitutes for the &quot;NH3-N&quot; in the paper. </generalComment>
			<generalComment xml:lang="zh">The Ammonia (NH4+, NH3, as N) is selected here, which substitutes for the &quot;NH3-N&quot; in the paper. </generalComment>
		</exchange>
		<exchange dataSetInternalID="17">
			<referenceToFlowDataSet type="flow data set" refObjectId="d69e658d-4380-4652-ba6d-4de8bde32fdb" uri="../flows/d69e658d-4380-4652-ba6d-4de8bde32fdb.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">Oils, unspecified</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToFlowDataSet>
			<exchangeDirection>Output</exchangeDirection>
			<meanAmount>0.01364</meanAmount>
			<resultingAmount>0.01364</resultingAmount>
			<dataDerivationTypeStatus>Software or database</dataDerivationTypeStatus>
			<generalComment xml:lang="en">The &quot;Oils&quot; is selected here, which substitutes for the &quot;Waste oil&quot; in the paper. </generalComment>
			<generalComment xml:lang="zh">The &quot;Oils&quot; is selected here, which substitutes for the &quot;Waste oil&quot; in the paper. </generalComment>
		</exchange>
		<exchange dataSetInternalID="18">
			<referenceToFlowDataSet type="flow data set" refObjectId="f24aafe3-8c41-466a-97c8-001dd37c60de" uri="../flows/f24aafe3-8c41-466a-97c8-001dd37c60de.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">Waste (solid)</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToFlowDataSet>
			<exchangeDirection>Output</exchangeDirection>
			<meanAmount>303.36</meanAmount>
			<resultingAmount>303.36</resultingAmount>
			<dataDerivationTypeStatus>Software or database</dataDerivationTypeStatus>
			<generalComment xml:lang="en">The Waste (solid) is selected here, which substitutes for the recyclable solid in the paper. </generalComment>
			<generalComment xml:lang="zh">The Waste (solid) is selected here, which substitutes for the recyclable solid in the paper. </generalComment>
		</exchange>
	</exchanges>
</processDataSet>
