<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet version="1.0" href="../../stylesheets/process2html.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<processDataSet xmlns:common="http://lca.jrc.it/ILCD/Common" xmlns="http://lca.jrc.it/ILCD/Process" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" version="1.1" locations="../ILCDLocations.xml" xsi:schemaLocation="http://lca.jrc.it/ILCD/Process ../../schemas/ILCD_ProcessDataSet.xsd">
	<processInformation>
		<dataSetInformation>
			<common:UUID>cc7f6831-3035-4ae0-aa3f-764636355e4e</common:UUID>
			<name>
				<baseName xml:lang="en">Pig production ; intensive feeding</baseName>
				<baseName xml:lang="zh">养猪生产 ; 集约化饲养</baseName>
			</name>
			<classificationInformation>
				<common:classification>
					<common:class level="0">Materials production</common:class>
					<common:class level="1">Agricultural production means</common:class>
				</common:classification>
			</classificationInformation>
			<common:generalComment xml:lang="en">Large-scale intensive feeding in hilly and plain areas. It provides about 1.5% of Sichuan's commercial pigs, and plays a major role in modern pig farming in Sichuan. The main scenarios and parameters of this pig raising scenario are as follows: (1) Energy feed is mainly corn and other grains, all feed raw materials are purchased from outside the system, the feeding period is about 170d, and the average output is 95kg; ② The average number of listed is 5000 per year, most of the varieties are foreign three yuan hybrid pigs (such as DLY, a few are PIC commercial pigs), the slaughter rate is 76%, and the whole feed meat ratio is 3.0:1; ③ The feeding management is more advanced, the use of a large number of modern pig technology, generally self-breeding, the use of limit column and high bed feeding. ④ Fecal treatment and utilization: fecal and sewage anaerobic fermentation treatment. 70% is shipped out to return to the field (at present, this level has not been reached, assuming that this goal can be achieved in the next 5 years due to the strict implementation of environmental protection laws and regulations) long-term storage accounted for 45%, 30% after anaerobic fermentation treatment and put into the surrounding environment  discharge water COD is 200mg/L.</common:generalComment>
			<common:generalComment xml:lang="zh">丘陵区和平原区规模化集约化饲养。提供了四川大约1.5%的商品猪， 在四川养猪业中起着主要的现代养猪示范作用。这种养猪情景的主要情景状态和设定参数为： ①能量饲料以玉米等谷物为主，全部饲料原料从系统外购买，饲养期170d左右，出栏平均为95kg；②出栏数量平均为每年5000头，品种多数为洋三元杂交猪（如DLY，少数为PIC商品猪），屠宰率76%，全程料肉比3.0：1；③饲养管理上比较先进，采用了大量现代养猪技术，一般自繁自养，采用限位栏和高床饲养。④粪便处理及利用：粪便和污水进行厌氧发酵处理。70%运出还田（目前未达到这一水平，假设未来5年内由于环保法规的严厉执行可实现这一目标）长期存贮量占45%，30%经厌氧发酵处理后排放到周边环境排出水COD为 200mg/L。</common:generalComment>
		</dataSetInformation>
		<quantitativeReference type="Reference flow(s)">
			<functionalUnitOrOther xml:lang="en">In this study, the functional unit (FU) was defined as &quot;1kg pig carcass&quot;, which included skin, bone and fat. Foreign studies generally only considered lean meat, but in China's consumption mode, skin and viscera were also fully utilized as edible foods. The concept of carcass was adopted in this study. Although the bone included in this study is an inedible part, it can play a certain compensative role because it does not contain internal organs. In addition, the current data can be easily converted into carcass weight, so it is more in line with the actual situation.</functionalUnitOrOther>
			<referenceToReferenceFlow>3</referenceToReferenceFlow>
		</quantitativeReference>
		<time>
			<common:referenceYear>2006</common:referenceYear>
		</time>
		<geography>
			<locationOfOperationSupplyOrProduction location="SC-CN">
				<descriptionOfRestrictions xml:lang="en">The data of fecal water quantity were obtained from a survey of typical free-range farmers in the surrounding areas of the east Sichuan, north Sichuan and southwest Sichuan basins</descriptionOfRestrictions>
				<descriptionOfRestrictions xml:lang="zh">粪水量数据来自对川东、川北和四川西南盆地周边区个典型性散养农户的调查</descriptionOfRestrictions>
			</locationOfOperationSupplyOrProduction>
		</geography>
		<technology>
			<technologyDescriptionAndIncludedProcesses xml:lang="en">Including raw material production, transportation and pig production process, but does not include pig slaughtering, processing and packaging, transportation process. Pig equipment, machinery and construction are not included, and materials less than 5% of the total or of low environmental relevance are excluded. The production, use and emission of drugs are not considered. Fishmeal and amino acid production are not considered</technologyDescriptionAndIncludedProcesses>
			<technologyDescriptionAndIncludedProcesses xml:lang="zh">包括原料生产、运输和养猪生产过程，但没有包括猪的屠宰、加工及包装、运输过程。没有包括养猪设备、机械和建筑方面，对小于总量5%或环境关联性小的材料进行了剔除。药品的生产、使用和污染排放没有考虑。鱼粉和氨基酸生产没考虑</technologyDescriptionAndIncludedProcesses>
			<technologicalApplicability xml:lang="en">This data set describes an intensive pig production process in hilly and plain areas of Sichuan, providing about 1.5% of Sichuan's commercial pigs. It serves as a modern pig farming model within the region. The process includes large-scale feeding using primarily grain-based energy feed, with a focus on advanced management techniques such as self-breeding, restricted pen usage, and high-bed feed operations. The data set is relevant for actors in the agricultural sector seeking to model modern, intensive animal husbandry practices and for policymakers aiming to understand and manage the environmental impacts of commercial pig production.</technologicalApplicability>
			<technologicalApplicability xml:lang="zh">该数据集描述了四川丘陵和平原区的集约化养猪生产过程，贡献了约四川省1.5%的商品猪供给。它在该地区充当现代养猪模型的角色。该过程包括使用以谷物为主的能源饲料的大规模饲养，注重采用先进的管理技术，如自繁自养、限位栏使用和高床饲养操作。该数据集适用于农业部门的参与者用于模拟现代、集约化畜牧业实践，以及政策制定者旨在理解和管理商业养猪生产的环境影响。</technologicalApplicability>
			<referenceToTechnologyFlowDiagrammOrPicture type="source data set" refObjectId="1e45a6d4-512e-aa46-b69e-6089bb1aedb8" uri="../sources/1e45a6d4-512e-aa46-b69e-6089bb1aedb8.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">ZPnhbjhFNokw6WxhhvSclKMbnpI.png</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToTechnologyFlowDiagrammOrPicture>
		</technology>
	</processInformation>
	<modellingAndValidation>
		<LCIMethodAndAllocation>
			<typeOfDataSet>Unit process, single operation</typeOfDataSet>
			<LCIMethodPrinciple>Not applicable</LCIMethodPrinciple>
			<deviationsFromLCIMethodPrinciple xml:lang="en">None</deviationsFromLCIMethodPrinciple>
			<deviationsFromLCIMethodPrinciple xml:lang="zh">无</deviationsFromLCIMethodPrinciple>
			<deviationsFromLCIMethodApproaches xml:lang="en">This study combined LCA methodology and scenario analysis method to conduct systematic environmental impact assessment for three typical pig production scenarios in Sichuan, explore the specific algorithms applied to the current environmental impact assessment of pig production, and reveal the environmentally friendly and unfavorable aspects of various pig production systems and their non-renewable energy utilization efficiency. The results are helpful to the understanding of environmental impact of pig industry and provide reference for the establishment of sustainable development model of pig industry.</deviationsFromLCIMethodApproaches>
			<deviationsFromLCIMethodApproaches xml:lang="zh">本研究采用LCA方法学和情景分析法相结合的方式对四川三种典型的养猪生产 情景进行系统的环境影响评估，探索这种分析方法应用于当前养猪生产环境影响评估 时的具体算法，并揭示各种养猪生产系统中的环境友好和不利方面以及其不可更新能 源利用效率。研究结果有助于对养猪业环境影响态势的认识，并为养猪可持续发展模 式的建立提供参考。</deviationsFromLCIMethodApproaches>
			<deviationsFromModellingConstants xml:lang="en">None</deviationsFromModellingConstants>
			<deviationsFromModellingConstants xml:lang="zh">无</deviationsFromModellingConstants>
		</LCIMethodAndAllocation>
		<dataSourcesTreatmentAndRepresentativeness>
			<deviationsFromCutOffAndCompletenessPrinciples xml:lang="en">None</deviationsFromCutOffAndCompletenessPrinciples>
			<deviationsFromCutOffAndCompletenessPrinciples xml:lang="zh">无</deviationsFromCutOffAndCompletenessPrinciples>
			<dataSelectionAndCombinationPrinciples xml:lang="en">In the pollution emission inventory of pig production under various scenarios, the production of fecal and urine nutrients and the production of major greenhouse gases are mainly analyzed. The environmental pollution of malodorous gases, noise and pathogens is not analyzed due to the lack of quantitative data on its potential impact on health. The waste discharge of animal production process was corrected by referring to recent research literature and combining with the data collected in the investigation, so as to reflect the actual situation in Sichuan. Among them, the emission estimate of NH3 is based on the research results of multiple literatures</dataSelectionAndCombinationPrinciples>
			<dataSelectionAndCombinationPrinciples xml:lang="zh">各种情景下的养猪生产过程的污染排放清单中，主要分析粪便和尿液养分的产生量及主要的温室气体产生量，对恶臭气体、噪声和病原体的环境污染，因目前缺少其 对健康的影响潜势方面的量化数据，没有进行分析。动物生产过程的废物排放参考近年的研究文献，结合调查中收集的数据进行校正，以基本反映四川实际。其中，NH3的排放量估计是综合了多个文献的研究成果</dataSelectionAndCombinationPrinciples>
			<deviationsFromSelectionAndCombinationPrinciples xml:lang="en">None</deviationsFromSelectionAndCombinationPrinciples>
			<deviationsFromSelectionAndCombinationPrinciples xml:lang="zh">无</deviationsFromSelectionAndCombinationPrinciples>
			<dataTreatmentAndExtrapolationsPrinciples xml:lang="en">1) Due to the complexity of pig breeding patterns in different regions, it is impossible to obtain completely consistent data in similar models. Therefore, according to the main differences related to environmental pollution among relevant literatures, yearbooks and set scenarios, the average data in similar scenarios are calculated on the basis of eliminating suspicious data. 2) There are two types of waste discharge data sources in animal production process, one is directly obtained from investigation and literature, and the other is derived from literature. In order to ensure the quality of data, some actual production data which deviated from the mean value were verified by experiments and consulted by experts, and corrected by cross-reference and comparison of various literatures.</dataTreatmentAndExtrapolationsPrinciples>
			<dataTreatmentAndExtrapolationsPrinciples xml:lang="zh">1）由于各地养猪模式十分复杂，无法在同类模式中取得完全一致的数据，因此根据相关文献、年鉴和设定情景间与环境污染有关的主要差异，在剔除可疑数据的基础上计算出同类情景中的平均数据。2）动物生产过程的废物排放数据来源有两类，一类是直接由调查和文献中得到，另一类是根据文献资料反推得到。为保证数据质量，对部分偏离均值较大的生产中实际产生量数据进行了试验验证和专家咨询，并通过多种途径的文献互相参照比较进行校正。</dataTreatmentAndExtrapolationsPrinciples>
			<deviationsFromTreatmentAndExtrapolationPrinciples xml:lang="en">None</deviationsFromTreatmentAndExtrapolationPrinciples>
			<deviationsFromTreatmentAndExtrapolationPrinciples xml:lang="zh">无</deviationsFromTreatmentAndExtrapolationPrinciples>
			<referenceToDataSource type="source data set" refObjectId="78ae11f1-32df-436b-a9b2-08f104575682" uri="../sources/78ae11f1-32df-436b-a9b2-08f104575682.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">白林. 四川养猪业清洁生产系统LCA及猪粪资源化利用关键技术研究. (四川农业大学, 2007).</common:shortDescription>
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="zh">白林. 四川养猪业清洁生产系统LCA及猪粪资源化利用关键技术研究. (四川农业大学, 2007).</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToDataSource>
			<useAdviceForDataSet xml:lang="en">As the data set reflects an intensive pig production scenario, users should note the specificity of the regional context when applying the data to other regions. It is important to consider local differences such as climate, feed composition, and technological applicability when utilizing this LCA data. Additionally, users should be aware that certain elements such as the treatment of manure, animal medication, and production of by-products like fishmeal and amino acids are not considered in this data set. When using the data for environmental impact assessment, it is advisable to supplement it with local data to adjust for regional disparities and to capture a comprehensive picture of the actual environmental footprint.</useAdviceForDataSet>
			<useAdviceForDataSet xml:lang="zh">由于数据集反映了一个集约养猪生产情景，用户在将数据应用到其他地区时应注意区域背景的特定性。在使用这份LCA数据时，考虑当地差异如气候、饲料成分和技术适用性是重要的。此外，用户应意识到该数据集中未考虑诸如粪便处理、动物用药和产生副产品（如鱼粉和氨基酸）的某些要素。在使用数据进行环境影响评估时，建议与当地数据结合，以调整地区差异并捕捉实际环境足迹的全面图景。</useAdviceForDataSet>
		</dataSourcesTreatmentAndRepresentativeness>
		<completeness/>
		<validation>
			<review type="Dependent internal review">
				<common:reviewDetails xml:lang="en">Inventory: The internal review was done by several iteration steps concerning raw data validation, raw data documentation, representativity, completeness and consistency of modelling with regard to ISO 14040 and 14044.</common:reviewDetails>
				<common:reviewDetails xml:lang="zh">清单： 内部审查通过几个迭代步骤完成，涉及原始数据验证、原始数据记录、代表性、完整性、与 ISO 14040 和 14044 有关的建模的一致性。</common:reviewDetails>
				<common:referenceToNameOfReviewerAndInstitution refObjectId="f4b4c314-8c4c-4c83-968f-5b3c7724f6a8" type="contact data set" uri="../contacts/f4b4c314-8c4c-4c83-968f-5b3c7724f6a8.xml">
					<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">Tiangong LCI Data Working Group</common:shortDescription>
					<common:shortDescription xml:lang="zh">天工LCI数据工作小组</common:shortDescription>
				</common:referenceToNameOfReviewerAndInstitution>
			</review>
		</validation>
	</modellingAndValidation>
	<administrativeInformation>
		<dataGenerator>
			<common:referenceToPersonOrEntityGeneratingTheDataSet type="contact data set" refObjectId="f3bc507b-0b5e-46f7-a7a3-44799e722d1c" uri="../contacts/f3bc507b-0b5e-46f7-a7a3-44799e722d1c.xml" version="01.00.000">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">Rui Yang, 1632707028@qq.com</common:shortDescription>
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="zh">杨瑞, 1632707028@qq.com</common:shortDescription>
			</common:referenceToPersonOrEntityGeneratingTheDataSet>
			<common:other xml:lang="en">1632707028@qq.com</common:other>
			<common:other xml:lang="zh">1632707028@qq.com</common:other>
		</dataGenerator>
		<dataEntryBy>
			<common:timeStamp>2023-12-18T11:16:18+08:00</common:timeStamp>
		</dataEntryBy>
		<publicationAndOwnership>
			<common:dateOfLastRevision>2023-12-18T11:16:18+08:00</common:dateOfLastRevision>
			<common:dataSetVersion>01.00.000</common:dataSetVersion>
			<common:permanentDataSetURI>https://lcadata.tiangong.world/showProcess.xhtml?uuid=cc7f6831-3035-4ae0-aa3f-764636355e4e&amp;amp;version=01.00.000&amp;amp;stock=TianGong</common:permanentDataSetURI>
			<common:referenceToOwnershipOfDataSet refObjectId="f4b4c314-8c4c-4c83-968f-5b3c7724f6a8" type="contact data set" uri="../contacts/f4b4c314-8c4c-4c83-968f-5b3c7724f6a8.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">Tiangong LCI Data Working Group</common:shortDescription>
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="zh">天工LCI数据工作小组</common:shortDescription>
			</common:referenceToOwnershipOfDataSet>
			<common:copyright>false</common:copyright>
			<common:licenseType>Free of charge for all users and uses</common:licenseType>
		</publicationAndOwnership>
	</administrativeInformation>
	<exchanges>
		<exchange dataSetInternalID="0">
			<referenceToFlowDataSet type="flow data set" refObjectId="08a91e70-3ddc-11dd-96ae-0050c2490048" uri="../flows/08a91e70-3ddc-11dd-96ae-0050c2490048.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">ammonia</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToFlowDataSet>
			<exchangeDirection>Output</exchangeDirection>
			<meanAmount>0.0107934</meanAmount>
			<resultingAmount>0.0107934</resultingAmount>
			<dataDerivationTypeStatus>Measured</dataDerivationTypeStatus>
			<generalComment xml:lang="en">Scenario C</generalComment>
			<generalComment xml:lang="zh">情景C</generalComment>
		</exchange>
		<exchange dataSetInternalID="1">
			<referenceToFlowDataSet type="flow data set" refObjectId="29061478-6556-11dd-ad8b-0800200c9a66" uri="../flows/29061478-6556-11dd-ad8b-0800200c9a66.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">nitrous oxide</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToFlowDataSet>
			<exchangeDirection>Output</exchangeDirection>
			<meanAmount>0.0002784</meanAmount>
			<resultingAmount>0.0002784</resultingAmount>
			<dataDerivationTypeStatus>Unknown derivation</dataDerivationTypeStatus>
			<generalComment xml:lang="en">Scenario C</generalComment>
			<generalComment xml:lang="zh">情景C</generalComment>
		</exchange>
		<exchange dataSetInternalID="2">
			<referenceToFlowDataSet type="flow data set" refObjectId="08a91e70-3ddc-11dd-960e-0050c2490048" uri="../flows/08a91e70-3ddc-11dd-960e-0050c2490048.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">methane</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToFlowDataSet>
			<exchangeDirection>Output</exchangeDirection>
			<meanAmount>0.030219000000000003</meanAmount>
			<resultingAmount>0.030219000000000003</resultingAmount>
			<dataDerivationTypeStatus>Calculated</dataDerivationTypeStatus>
			<generalComment xml:lang="en">Scenario C</generalComment>
			<generalComment xml:lang="zh">情景C</generalComment>
		</exchange>
		<exchange dataSetInternalID="3">
			<referenceToFlowDataSet type="flow data set" refObjectId="819b3d73-321f-4c77-8039-0fffab79e82f" uri="../flows/819b3d73-321f-4c77-8039-0fffab79e82f.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">pig</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToFlowDataSet>
			<exchangeDirection>Output</exchangeDirection>
			<meanAmount>1.0</meanAmount>
			<resultingAmount>1.0</resultingAmount>
			<dataDerivationTypeStatus>Measured</dataDerivationTypeStatus>
			<generalComment xml:lang="en">pork</generalComment>
			<generalComment xml:lang="zh">猪肉</generalComment>
		</exchange>
		<exchange dataSetInternalID="4">
			<referenceToFlowDataSet type="flow data set" refObjectId="890a70b7-b677-4e2a-8a1b-7d017e0a10ae" uri="../flows/890a70b7-b677-4e2a-8a1b-7d017e0a10ae.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">Electricity</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToFlowDataSet>
			<exchangeDirection>Input</exchangeDirection>
			<meanAmount>0.6980609520000001</meanAmount>
			<resultingAmount>0.6980609520000001</resultingAmount>
			<dataDerivationTypeStatus>Calculated</dataDerivationTypeStatus>
			<generalComment xml:lang="zh">情景C</generalComment>
		</exchange>
	</exchanges>
</processDataSet>
