<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet version="1.0" href="../../stylesheets/process2html.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<processDataSet xmlns:common="http://lca.jrc.it/ILCD/Common" xmlns="http://lca.jrc.it/ILCD/Process" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" version="1.1" locations="../ILCDLocations.xml" xsi:schemaLocation="http://lca.jrc.it/ILCD/Process ../../schemas/ILCD_ProcessDataSet.xsd">
	<processInformation>
		<dataSetInformation>
			<common:UUID>e51b108e-411f-4650-83d0-b6f00cd98e91</common:UUID>
			<name>
				<baseName xml:lang="en">Pig production ; farmers in Penzhoushan area free-range ; feed raw materials production</baseName>
				<baseName xml:lang="zh">养猪生产 ; 盆周山地区农户散养 ; 饲料原料生产</baseName>
			</name>
			<classificationInformation>
				<common:classification>
					<common:class level="0">Unit processes</common:class>
					<common:class level="1">Materials production</common:class>
					<common:class level="2">Agricultural production means</common:class>
				</common:classification>
			</classificationInformation>
			<common:generalComment xml:lang="en">In Sichuan, farmers provide about 79.5% of the commercial pigs, which has an important position in Sichuan pig industry. The main scenario states and parameters were set as follows: (1) the feed was mainly composed of self-planted corn, vegetables and other agricultural by-products, supplemented with a small amount of concentrated feed (soybean meal 70%, rapeseed meal 10%), and the insufficient part was collected as feed supplement. The cultivated land area is assumed to be 0.2067 square hectares per household. (2) The average number of pigs is 3 / household, most of the varieties are soil mixed pigs (local sows and foreign breeding pigs cross, a few are Chinese local breeds) the average slaughter rate is 70%; (3) Extensive feeding and management methods, long feeding period, the average pig feeding day is about 240d, the average weight of the yard is 100kg; (4) Manure treatment and utilization: The anaerobic manure tank is used for storage,80% of which is returned to the field, 48% of which is directly returned to the field in the busy season, and the long-term storage accounts for 32% (irregular return to the field). 20% of the fecal water is leaking in the manure tank or when returning to the field, and the COD of the seepage water is 50mg/L.</common:generalComment>
			<common:generalComment xml:lang="zh">在四川，农户散养提供了大约79.5%的商品猪，在四川养猪业中具有重要的地位。主要情景状态和参数设定为 ①饲料以自种玉米、蔬菜和其他农副产物为主，辅以少量浓缩饲料（豆粕70%、 菜籽粕10%），不足部分采集野草作为饲料补充。耕地面积假设为0.2067平方公顷/户。② 出栏猪数量平均3头/户，品种多数为土杂猪（地方母猪与外种猪杂交，少数为中国地方品种）屠宰率平均为70% ③饲养管理方式粗放，饲养期长，猪平均饲养240d左右,出栏重平均为100kg ④粪便处理和利用: 采用厌氧粪池存贮,80%还田,其 中48%在农忙季节直接还田,长期存贮量占32% (不定时还田)。20%粪水在粪池中或还田时渗漏,渗出水COD为50mg/L.</common:generalComment>
		</dataSetInformation>
		<quantitativeReference type="Reference flow(s)">
			<functionalUnitOrOther xml:lang="en">In this study, the functional unit (FU) was defined as &quot;1kg pig carcass&quot;, which included skin, bone and fat. Foreign studies generally only considered lean meat, but in China's consumption mode, skin and viscera were also fully utilized as edible foods. The concept of carcass was adopted in this study. Although the bone included in this study is an inedible part, it can play a certain compensative role because it does not contain internal organs. In addition, the current data can be easily converted into carcass weight, so it is more in line with the actual situation.</functionalUnitOrOther>
			<referenceToReferenceFlow>7</referenceToReferenceFlow>
		</quantitativeReference>
		<time>
			<common:referenceYear>2006</common:referenceYear>
			<common:timeRepresentativenessDescription xml:lang="en">The average level of energy consumption and the amount of fertilizer, pesticide and mulch used in feed raw materials production in Sichuan Province was calculated according to China Statistical Yearbook 2006.</common:timeRepresentativenessDescription>
			<common:timeRepresentativenessDescription xml:lang="zh">饲料原料生产的能量消耗和化肥、农药、地膜等使用量按《中国统计年鉴2006》计算四川平均水平。</common:timeRepresentativenessDescription>
		</time>
		<geography>
			<locationOfOperationSupplyOrProduction location="SC-CN">
				<descriptionOfRestrictions xml:lang="en">Since the agricultural resource consumption is allocated according to the occupied land, the specific crop yield is no longer considered in scenario A, and the concentrated feed and the full-priced feed under various scenarios are converted into equivalent land area according to the corresponding average yield of main grains in the whole country or Sichuan province according to the set two situations.</descriptionOfRestrictions>
				<descriptionOfRestrictions xml:lang="zh">由于本文按占用土地进行农资消耗分配，情景A中不再考虑具体的作物产量，各种情景下的浓缩饲料和全价饲料均按设定的两种情况按相应的全国或四川省内主要谷物平均产量折算成相当的土地面积。</descriptionOfRestrictions>
			</locationOfOperationSupplyOrProduction>
		</geography>
		<technology>
			<technologyDescriptionAndIncludedProcesses xml:lang="en">Soybean meal (70%) and rapeseed meal (10%) were analyzed in concentrate, and other components were not considered. The components of the full price feed are mainly corn based grains (70%) and soybean meal (25%), and the other components are not considered. Minerals, disinfectants and various small equipment facilities are not included.</technologyDescriptionAndIncludedProcesses>
			<technologyDescriptionAndIncludedProcesses xml:lang="zh">浓缩料中分析豆粕（70%）、菜籽粕（10%），其余成分没有考虑。全价饲料的成分主要是玉米为主的谷物（70%）和豆粕（25%），其余成分没有考虑。没有包括矿物质、消毒剂和各种小型设备设施。</technologyDescriptionAndIncludedProcesses>
			<technologicalApplicability xml:lang="en">The described process refers to a small-scale, free-range pig farming operation within the Penzhoushan region in Sichuan, China. The pigs are raised primarily on a diet of self-grown corn, vegetables, and agricultural by-products, with a supplement of concentrated feed composed of soybean and rapeseed meal. This method of pig production is significant within the Sichuan pig industry and is crucial in contributing to the local food supply. The pigs are a mixture of local and foreign breeds, with an average slaughter rate of 70%. The pig manure is managed using an anaerobic manure storage system, with a large portion returned to the fields as fertilizer. This type of farming could be relevant for regions looking to implement sustainable and localized agricultural practices, contributing to environmental conservation and rural economic development.</technologicalApplicability>
			<technologicalApplicability xml:lang="zh">本工艺描述的是中国四川盆周山地区的小规模散养养猪操作。养猪主要依赖自种玉米、蔬菜及其他农副产品，辅以豆粕和菜籽粕为主的浓缩饲料。这种养猪方式在四川养猪产业中占有重要地位，对当地食品供应链贡献显著。所养猪种是地方品种和外来品种的混合体，平均屠宰率为70%。猪粪通过厌氧存储管理，大部分返回到田地作为肥料。此种农业实践对于寻求实施可持续和地方化农业实践的地区具有相关性，有助于环境保护和农村经济发展。</technologicalApplicability>
			<referenceToTechnologyFlowDiagrammOrPicture type="source data set" refObjectId="1e45a6d4-512e-aa46-b69e-6089bb1aedb8" uri="../sources/1e45a6d4-512e-aa46-b69e-6089bb1aedb8.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">XWCLb2JXKo4EM4xySawc8SFPnPc.png</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToTechnologyFlowDiagrammOrPicture>
		</technology>
	</processInformation>
	<modellingAndValidation>
		<LCIMethodAndAllocation>
			<typeOfDataSet>Unit process, single operation</typeOfDataSet>
			<deviationsFromLCIMethodPrinciple xml:lang="en">None</deviationsFromLCIMethodPrinciple>
			<deviationsFromLCIMethodPrinciple xml:lang="zh">无</deviationsFromLCIMethodPrinciple>
			<deviationsFromLCIMethodApproaches xml:lang="en">This study combined LCA methodology and scenario analysis method to conduct systematic environmental impact assessment for three typical pig production scenarios in Sichuan, explore the specific algorithms applied to the current environmental impact assessment of pig production, and reveal the environmentally friendly and unfavorable aspects of various pig production systems and their non-renewable energy utilization efficiency. The results are helpful to the understanding of environmental impact of pig industry and provide reference for the establishment of sustainable development model of pig industry.</deviationsFromLCIMethodApproaches>
			<deviationsFromLCIMethodApproaches xml:lang="zh">本研究采用LCA方法学和情景分析法相结合的方式对四川三种典型的养猪生产 情景进行系统的环境影响评估，探索这种分析方法应用于当前养猪生产环境影响评估 时的具体算法，并揭示各种养猪生产系统中的环境友好和不利方面以及其不可更新能 源利用效率。研究结果有助于对养猪业环境影响态势的认识，并为养猪可持续发展模 式的建立提供参考。</deviationsFromLCIMethodApproaches>
			<deviationsFromModellingConstants xml:lang="en">None</deviationsFromModellingConstants>
			<deviationsFromModellingConstants xml:lang="zh">无</deviationsFromModellingConstants>
		</LCIMethodAndAllocation>
		<dataSourcesTreatmentAndRepresentativeness>
			<deviationsFromCutOffAndCompletenessPrinciples xml:lang="en">None</deviationsFromCutOffAndCompletenessPrinciples>
			<deviationsFromCutOffAndCompletenessPrinciples xml:lang="zh">无</deviationsFromCutOffAndCompletenessPrinciples>
			<dataSelectionAndCombinationPrinciples xml:lang="en">1) The basic situation of Sichuan pig industry and the setting of various scenarios in this study, on the one hand, the opinions of a number of pig experts in Sichuan Province were solicited, and on the other hand, field investigations were carried out. 2) The relevant data in crop production are mainly from the 2005 statistics given in the annual yearbook. The production data of feed raw materials in Sichuan and the national average data are used to distinguish the two cases of raw materials coming from within the province and outside the province.</dataSelectionAndCombinationPrinciples>
			<dataSelectionAndCombinationPrinciples xml:lang="zh">1）本研究中四川养猪业的基本情况和各种情景的设定，一方面征求了四川省多位养猪专家的意见，另一方面进行了实地调查。2）作物生产中的相关数据主要来自年年鉴中给出的2005年统计数据。四川的饲料原料生产数据和全国的平均数据用于区分原料来自省内和省外两种情况。</dataSelectionAndCombinationPrinciples>
			<deviationsFromSelectionAndCombinationPrinciples xml:lang="en">None</deviationsFromSelectionAndCombinationPrinciples>
			<deviationsFromSelectionAndCombinationPrinciples xml:lang="zh">无</deviationsFromSelectionAndCombinationPrinciples>
			<dataTreatmentAndExtrapolationsPrinciples xml:lang="en">The production data of feed raw materials in Sichuan and the national average data are used to distinguish the two cases of raw materials coming from within the province and outside the province. The consumption of agricultural materials is calculated according to the corresponding raw material consumption and the average yield of main grains in the whole country or Sichuan Province, and then calculated according to the area. Due to the large differences in the feed formulations used in the three scenarios, the assumption of the proportion of main raw material consumption was made, and then adjusted according to the sample survey data.</dataTreatmentAndExtrapolationsPrinciples>
			<dataTreatmentAndExtrapolationsPrinciples xml:lang="zh">四川的饲料原料生产数据和全国的平均数据用于区分原料来自省内和省外两种情况。农资消耗量按相应的原料消耗量和全国或四川省内主要谷物平均产量折算成相当的土地面积，再按面积求得。由于三种情景中所用的饲料配方差异大，故进行了主要原料消耗比例的假设，然后根据抽样调查资料进行了调整。</dataTreatmentAndExtrapolationsPrinciples>
			<deviationsFromTreatmentAndExtrapolationPrinciples xml:lang="en">None</deviationsFromTreatmentAndExtrapolationPrinciples>
			<deviationsFromTreatmentAndExtrapolationPrinciples xml:lang="zh">无</deviationsFromTreatmentAndExtrapolationPrinciples>
			<referenceToDataSource type="source data set" refObjectId="78ae11f1-32df-436b-a9b2-08f104575682" uri="../sources/78ae11f1-32df-436b-a9b2-08f104575682.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">白林. 四川养猪业清洁生产系统LCA及猪粪资源化利用关键技术研究. (四川农业大学, 2007).</common:shortDescription>
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="zh">白林. 四川养猪业清洁生产系统LCA及猪粪资源化利用关键技术研究. (四川农业大学, 2007).</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToDataSource>
			<useAdviceForDataSet xml:lang="en">When utilizing the data from this pig production process for a Life Cycle Assessment (LCA), users should account for the localized nature of the raw material production and manure management system. Special attention should be given to the agricultural resource consumption allocated according to the occupied land rather than specific crop yield in scenario A. For feed production, the assumed proportions of self-cultivated crops and agricultural by-products plus concentrated feeds need to be reflected in the LCA. The environmental impact from feed should be derived from the 2005 statistics for crop production and use levels of fertilizer, pesticide, and mulch, as well as the average energy consumption for raw material production. It is important to use the definition of the functional unit as 1 kg of pig carcass, including skin, bones, and fat, as is customary in China, rather than lean meat only. Any LCA employing this data should adapt the functional unit accordingly and note the environmental advantages or disadvantages specific to this farming system and the non-renewable energy efficiencies involved.</useAdviceForDataSet>
			<useAdviceForDataSet xml:lang="zh">使用本养猪生产过程数据进行生命周期评估（LCA）时，用户应考虑原材料生产和粪便管理系统的地方性特点。特别注意，情景A中应依据占用土地而非具体作物产量分配农业资源消耗。在饲料生产中，应在LCA中反映自种农作物和农副产品与浓缩饲料相结合的假定比例。饲料的环境影响应来源于2005年作物生产统计数据、肥料、农药和地膜的使用量，以及四川省原材料生产的平均能耗。重要的是，功能单元的定义应为包括皮、骨和脂肪的1公斤猪胴体，符合中国的惯例，而不仅是瘦肉。任何使用这些数据的LCA都应相应地调整功能单元，并注意与该养殖系统特定以及其中所涉及的不可再生能源效率的环境优势或不利之处。</useAdviceForDataSet>
		</dataSourcesTreatmentAndRepresentativeness>
		<completeness/>
		<validation>
			<review type="Dependent internal review">
				<common:reviewDetails xml:lang="en">Inventory: The internal review was done by several iteration steps concerning raw data validation, raw data documentation, representativity, completeness and consistency of modelling with regard to ISO 14040 and 14044.</common:reviewDetails>
				<common:reviewDetails xml:lang="zh">清单： 内部审查通过几个迭代步骤完成，涉及原始数据验证、原始数据记录、代表性、完整性、与 ISO 14040 和 14044 有关的建模的一致性。</common:reviewDetails>
				<common:referenceToNameOfReviewerAndInstitution refObjectId="f4b4c314-8c4c-4c83-968f-5b3c7724f6a8" type="contact data set" uri="../contacts/f4b4c314-8c4c-4c83-968f-5b3c7724f6a8.xml">
					<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">Tiangong LCI Data Working Group</common:shortDescription>
					<common:shortDescription xml:lang="zh">天工LCI数据工作小组</common:shortDescription>
				</common:referenceToNameOfReviewerAndInstitution>
			</review>
		</validation>
	</modellingAndValidation>
	<administrativeInformation>
		<dataGenerator>
			<common:referenceToPersonOrEntityGeneratingTheDataSet type="contact data set" refObjectId="f3bc507b-0b5e-46f7-a7a3-44799e722d1c" uri="../contacts/f3bc507b-0b5e-46f7-a7a3-44799e722d1c.xml" version="01.00.000">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">Rui Yang, 1632707028@qq.com</common:shortDescription>
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="zh">杨瑞, 1632707028@qq.com</common:shortDescription>
			</common:referenceToPersonOrEntityGeneratingTheDataSet>
			<common:other xml:lang="en">1632707028@qq.com</common:other>
			<common:other xml:lang="zh">1632707028@qq.com</common:other>
		</dataGenerator>
		<dataEntryBy>
			<common:timeStamp>2024-03-19T15:52:00+08:00</common:timeStamp>
		</dataEntryBy>
		<publicationAndOwnership>
			<common:dateOfLastRevision>2024-04-15T22:44:25.701116+08:00</common:dateOfLastRevision>
			<common:dataSetVersion>00.01.005</common:dataSetVersion>
			<common:permanentDataSetURI>https://lcadata.tiangong.world/showProcess.xhtml?uuid=e51b108e-411f-4650-83d0-b6f00cd98e91&amp;amp;version=01.00.000&amp;amp;stock=TianGong</common:permanentDataSetURI>
			<common:referenceToOwnershipOfDataSet refObjectId="f4b4c314-8c4c-4c83-968f-5b3c7724f6a8" type="contact data set" uri="../contacts/f4b4c314-8c4c-4c83-968f-5b3c7724f6a8.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">Tiangong LCI Data Working Group</common:shortDescription>
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="zh">天工LCI数据工作小组</common:shortDescription>
			</common:referenceToOwnershipOfDataSet>
			<common:copyright>false</common:copyright>
			<common:licenseType>Free of charge for all users and uses</common:licenseType>
		</publicationAndOwnership>
	</administrativeInformation>
	<exchanges>
		<exchange dataSetInternalID="0">
			<referenceToFlowDataSet type="flow data set" refObjectId="4f19ca0f-7b3b-11dd-ad8b-0800200c9a66" uri="../flows/4f19ca0f-7b3b-11dd-ad8b-0800200c9a66.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">nitrogen</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToFlowDataSet>
			<exchangeDirection>Input</exchangeDirection>
			<meanAmount>0.1074</meanAmount>
			<resultingAmount>0.1074</resultingAmount>
			<dataDerivationTypeStatus>Measured</dataDerivationTypeStatus>
			<generalComment xml:lang="en">Scenario A</generalComment>
			<generalComment xml:lang="zh">情景A（农户散养）</generalComment>
		</exchange>
		<exchange dataSetInternalID="1">
			<referenceToFlowDataSet type="flow data set" refObjectId="041f5cea-6556-11dd-ad8b-0800200c9a66" uri="../flows/041f5cea-6556-11dd-ad8b-0800200c9a66.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">phosphorus</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToFlowDataSet>
			<exchangeDirection>Input</exchangeDirection>
			<meanAmount>0.0334</meanAmount>
			<resultingAmount>0.0334</resultingAmount>
			<dataDerivationTypeStatus>Measured</dataDerivationTypeStatus>
			<generalComment xml:lang="en">Scenario A</generalComment>
			<generalComment xml:lang="zh">情景A（农户散养）</generalComment>
		</exchange>
		<exchange dataSetInternalID="2">
			<referenceToFlowDataSet type="flow data set" refObjectId="4f19f121-7b3b-11dd-ad8b-0800200c9a66" uri="../flows/4f19f121-7b3b-11dd-ad8b-0800200c9a66.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">polyvinylchloride resin (E-PVC)</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToFlowDataSet>
			<exchangeDirection>Input</exchangeDirection>
			<meanAmount>0.0073</meanAmount>
			<resultingAmount>0.0073</resultingAmount>
			<dataDerivationTypeStatus>Measured</dataDerivationTypeStatus>
			<generalComment xml:lang="en">Scenario A</generalComment>
			<generalComment xml:lang="zh">情景A（农户散养）</generalComment>
		</exchange>
		<exchange dataSetInternalID="3">
			<referenceToFlowDataSet type="flow data set" refObjectId="4f19a2ff-7b3b-11dd-ad8b-0800200c9a66" uri="../flows/4f19a2ff-7b3b-11dd-ad8b-0800200c9a66.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">hard coal</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToFlowDataSet>
			<exchangeDirection>Input</exchangeDirection>
			<meanAmount>1.5738181199999999</meanAmount>
			<resultingAmount>1.5738181199999999</resultingAmount>
			<dataDerivationTypeStatus>Calculated</dataDerivationTypeStatus>
			<generalComment xml:lang="en">Scenario A</generalComment>
			<generalComment xml:lang="zh">情景A（农户散养）</generalComment>
		</exchange>
		<exchange dataSetInternalID="4">
			<referenceToFlowDataSet type="flow data set" refObjectId="9b5fb8b6-a8f4-48d5-b912-56c65c0cc263" uri="../flows/9b5fb8b6-a8f4-48d5-b912-56c65c0cc263.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">Gasoline (regular)</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToFlowDataSet>
			<exchangeDirection>Input</exchangeDirection>
			<meanAmount>0.15503720399999998</meanAmount>
			<resultingAmount>0.15503720399999998</resultingAmount>
			<dataDerivationTypeStatus>Calculated</dataDerivationTypeStatus>
			<generalComment xml:lang="en">Scenario A</generalComment>
			<generalComment xml:lang="zh">情景A（农户散养）</generalComment>
		</exchange>
		<exchange dataSetInternalID="5">
			<referenceToFlowDataSet type="flow data set" refObjectId="55a4c166-2eb6-43a3-9a13-2e4f2c4fee60" uri="../flows/55a4c166-2eb6-43a3-9a13-2e4f2c4fee60.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">Diesel</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToFlowDataSet>
			<exchangeDirection>Input</exchangeDirection>
			<meanAmount>1.249089912</meanAmount>
			<resultingAmount>1.249089912</resultingAmount>
			<dataDerivationTypeStatus>Calculated</dataDerivationTypeStatus>
			<generalComment xml:lang="en">Scenario A</generalComment>
			<generalComment xml:lang="zh">情景A（农户散养）</generalComment>
		</exchange>
		<exchange dataSetInternalID="6">
			<referenceToFlowDataSet type="flow data set" refObjectId="890a70b7-b677-4e2a-8a1b-7d017e0a10ae" uri="../flows/890a70b7-b677-4e2a-8a1b-7d017e0a10ae.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">Electricity</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToFlowDataSet>
			<exchangeDirection>Input</exchangeDirection>
			<meanAmount>0.073269</meanAmount>
			<resultingAmount>0.073269</resultingAmount>
			<dataDerivationTypeStatus>Calculated</dataDerivationTypeStatus>
			<generalComment xml:lang="en">Scenario A</generalComment>
			<generalComment xml:lang="zh">情景A（农户散养）</generalComment>
		</exchange>
		<exchange dataSetInternalID="7">
			<referenceToFlowDataSet type="flow data set" refObjectId="819b3d73-321f-4c77-8039-0fffab79e82f" uri="../flows/819b3d73-321f-4c77-8039-0fffab79e82f.xml">
				<common:shortDescription xml:lang="en">pig</common:shortDescription>
			</referenceToFlowDataSet>
			<exchangeDirection>Output</exchangeDirection>
			<meanAmount>1.0</meanAmount>
			<resultingAmount>1.0</resultingAmount>
			<dataDerivationTypeStatus>Measured</dataDerivationTypeStatus>
			<dataDerivationTypeStatus>Estimated</dataDerivationTypeStatus>
			<generalComment xml:lang="zh">作为参考定量，非实际输出</generalComment>
		</exchange>
	</exchanges>
</processDataSet>
